<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recipes on Lam Family Cookbook</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/</link><description>Recent content in Recipes on Lam Family Cookbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rempah</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/rempah/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/rempah/</guid><description>Ingredients 20 g dried chilli, deseeded, soaked to soften 5 fresh chilli, deseeded 250 g shallot onions 10 garlic cloves 6 lemongrass stalks (white part only) 30 g fresh galangal, chopped 20 g fresh ginger, chopped 20 g fresh turmeric, chopped 1 torch lily bud, chopped (optional) 25 g belacan paste/powder, toasted 150 g cooking oil 20 g sugar 15 g salt Method Pound or blend together all the ingredients (Thermomix: 5 sec/speed 6, 30 sec/speed 10) Fry in wok for 20-30 minutes until brown and very fragrant (Thermomix: 5 min/120°C/speed 2, 15 min/90°C/speed 2)</description></item><item><title>Lo mai gai</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/lo-mai-gai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/lo-mai-gai/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 metric cups glutinous rice 2 pieces lup chong, sliced ⅓ cup dried shrimp, re-hydrated in water then finely chopped ~10 dried shiitake mushrooms, re-hydrated then thickly sliced 3 chicken thigh fillets, cut into large cubes 1 onion, diced 1 clove garlic, crushed Fried onion Sauce (for chicken and rice): Light soy sauce Dark soy sauce Oyster sauce Cooking caramel Sesame oil Pepper Method Rinse then soak glutinous rice in water for at least 2 hours.</description></item><item><title>Dad's pork crackling</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/dads-pork-crackling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/dads-pork-crackling/</guid><description>Ingredients Pork belly Salt Oil (olive oil or similar) Five-spice powder (optional) Method A few days beforehand, place the pork belly on a plate and rub a generous amount of salt onto the skin.</description></item><item><title>Egg rolls</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/egg-rolls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/egg-rolls/</guid><description>Ingredients Omelette 3 eggs Salt Pepper Sesame oil Filling Pork mince Spring onion Crushed garlic Soy sauce Cooking wine Oyster sauce Sesame oil Pepper Corn flour or egg (for binding) Sugar Method Mix the filling ingredients in a mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>Son-in-law eggs</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/son-in-law-eggs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/son-in-law-eggs/</guid><description>Called &amp;ldquo;kai look koei&amp;rdquo; in Thai. Mum learned this in a Thai cooking class decades ago. This recipe is from her old recipe notes.
Ingredients 6 eggs, hard boiled 3 tbsp oil 2 tbsp chopped onion 3 tbsp brown sugar 2 tsp fish sauce 2 tbsp vinegar Fresh chilli and coriander to garnish Method Cover bottom of pan with oil and fry the halved eggs yolk side down.</description></item><item><title>Stuffed eggplant</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stuffed-eggplant/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stuffed-eggplant/</guid><description>Ingredients Eggplant Filling Pork mince Spring onion Crushed garlic Soy sauce Cooking wine Oyster sauce Sesame oil Pepper Corn flour or egg (for binding) Sugar Sauce 2 tbsp corn flour Oyster sauce Sesame oil Water Sugar, garlic, five spice (optional) Method Mix the filling ingredients in a mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>Stuffed mushroom</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stuffed-mushroom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stuffed-mushroom/</guid><description>Ingredients Dried shiitake mushrooms Filling Pork mince Spring onion Crushed garlic Soy sauce Cooking wine Oyster sauce Sesame oil Pepper Corn flour or egg (for binding) Sugar Marinade Five spice powder Salt Pepper Sesame oil Cooking wine Soy sauce (not too much, the mushrooms are already salty) Sauce 2 tbsp corn flour Oyster sauce Sesame oil Water Sugar, garlic, five spice (optional) Method Mix the filling ingredients in a mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>Burbur cha cha</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/burbur-cha-cha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/burbur-cha-cha/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 taro 1 sweet potato Sago pearls 1 can coconut cream (we like Ayam brand) Ginger Sugar Method Cut taro and sweet potato into ~1cm diamond shape.</description></item><item><title>Sweet corn soup</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/sweet-corn-soup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/sweet-corn-soup/</guid><description>Mum&amp;rsquo;s classic sweet corn soup recipe.
Ingredients 1 can corn kernels 1 can creamed corn Finely diced chicken Soup seasoning (dashi, salt, pepper, sesame oil, etc.), adjust according to available ingredients 1 tsp corn flour (approx) 1 egg Method Boil about 1 cup water in pot.</description></item><item><title>Mum's mapo tofu</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-mapo-tofu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-mapo-tofu/</guid><description>This recipe was adapted by Mum from cousins' grandpa who used to run a Taiwanese restaurant.
Ingredients 1 pack soft tofu Minced pork Diced onion Crushed garlic and ginger Sliced chilli Method Cut soft tofu into diamonds and soak in water.</description></item><item><title>Mum's Malaysian curry</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-malaysian-curry/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-malaysian-curry/</guid><description>Ingredients Aromatics Chopped onion Garlic and ginger Curry/kaffir lime leaves Lemongrass, bruised Curry powder+water paste Whole chicken, chopped Potato, chopped Coconut cream Method Fry aromatics in a deep pot.</description></item><item><title>Stir fried kang kung</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stir-fried-kang-kung/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stir-fried-kang-kung/</guid><description>Method Fry aromatics: Diced onion Garlic and ginger Shrimps Cut chilli Add kang kung Fry until wilted, add salt and pepper and sesame oil to taste</description></item><item><title>Breakfast oats</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/breakfast-oats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/breakfast-oats/</guid><description>Method In a jar, add: 1 cup oats Assorted dry ingredients: Chia seeds Cacao nibs Goji berries Sultanas Dried apricot Then add: ~1 cup (cover dry ingredients) milk ~1 cup (3 large scoops) yoghurt Mix thoroughly, add fresh soft fruit on top: Grapes Berries Mango Peach Nectarine</description></item><item><title>Hokkien noodles</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/hokkien-noodles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/hokkien-noodles/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 packet (~1 kg) Hokkien noodles Chicken thigh fillets, roughly chopped Soy sauce Oyster sauce Sesame oil Cooking caramel (karamel masakan) Bok choy, leaves and stems separated, stems cut in half.</description></item><item><title>Popcorn</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/popcorn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/popcorn/</guid><description>Ingredients Unpopped popcorn kernels Flavacol flavouring Butter Method Heat up an empty saucepan on a stove for a few minutes. Melt the butter in the pan. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry if it turns brown, just make sure it doesn&amp;rsquo;t turn black because that means it is burnt.</description></item><item><title>Mum's special sauce</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-special-sauce/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-special-sauce/</guid><description>Good for serving with chicken and pork. Cooked version is good for steamed fish.
Ingredients 1 tbsp light soy sauce 1 tbsp dark soy sauce 1 tbsp oyster sauce 1 tsp sugar 1 tsp sesame oil Fried red onions (optional) Chopped spring onions Method (raw version) Mix everything together and serve.</description></item><item><title>Tau yu bak</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/tau-yu-bak/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/tau-yu-bak/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 kg pork collar butt, cut into large pieces 1 head garlic, separated into cloves with skin on 1 tbsp sugar 1 tbsp cooking caramel 2 tbsp light soy sauce 2 tbsp dark soy sauce Pepper 1 tsp five-spice powder (optional) Hard-boiled eggs Method Add garlic, sugar, cooking caramel, light soy sauce, dark soy sauce, five-spice powder and pepper to a large pot.</description></item><item><title>Curry puffs</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/curry-puffs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/curry-puffs/</guid><description>This recipe makes 72 curry puffs. Can halve or quarter the quantity to make less.
Ingredients 1.4 kg pork mince 1 kg potato, cut into 1cm cube 1 medium onion, finely chopped 2 tbsp coriander powder 2 tbsp curry powder, substitute with coriander powder for non-spicy version 2 tsp tumeric powder Salt and pepper Soy sauce (optional) 12 sheets puff pastry 2 eggs, for glazing Method Partially cook cubed potato in microwave oven for 10min on High with a little bit of water.</description></item><item><title>Chinese New Year cake</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/chinese-new-year-cake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 1994 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/chinese-new-year-cake/</guid><description>Makes 2 cakes of a reasonable size.
Ingredients 3 x 500 g packets of glutinous rice flour 900 g sugar 6 cups warm water Method Fry sugar until dissolved.</description></item><item><title>Laksa</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/laksa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 1993 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/laksa/</guid><description>Ingredients Pre-prepared rempah Chopped dried shrimp Coconut milk Coconut cream Bean sprouts White noodles Prawns, meat and shells separated Stuffed fried bean curd with fish meat Fish cake Fish balls Vegetables (cabbage, beans, tomato, cauliflower, etc.</description></item><item><title>Beef rendang</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/beef-rendang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 1993 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/beef-rendang/</guid><description>Ingredients Beef, cut into chunks 2-3 red onions Chilli Galangal Turmeric Belacan Cumin Coriander powder Coconut milk Salt Dessicated coconut Method Grind red onions, lemongrass, chilli, galangal, turmeric and belacan.</description></item><item><title>Assam chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/assam-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/assam-chicken/</guid><description>The rempah ingredients are from Ah Tai&amp;rsquo;s notes. Can also use this recipe.
Ingredients ~150 g rempah Belacan Chilli Onions Lemongrass Galangal Turmeric 1kg chicken thigh, cut in large pieces Tomatoes, cut in wedges 1 onion, coarsely chopped Tamarind paste, diluted with water Sugar Mint leaves/laksa leaves (optional) Method Use pre-made rempah, or grind rempah ingredients and fry in lots of oil until fragrant.</description></item><item><title>Assam fish</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/assam-fish/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/assam-fish/</guid><description>This dish is a bit soury.
Ingredients Rempah Belacan Chilli Onions Lemongrass Galangal Turmeric Tamarind paste Fish fillet Pineapple pieces Method Grind rempah ingredients and fry in lots of oil until fragrant.</description></item><item><title>Ah Tai's tau yu bak</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/ah-tais-tau-yu-bak/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/ah-tais-tau-yu-bak/</guid><description>Ingredients Pork (fatty cut like pork belly), cut in large chunks with fat and skin Onion, finely chopped Dark soy sauce Cinnamon stick Cloves 1 star anise 2-3 cloves garlic A bit of sugar Pinch of salt Method Fry onion.</description></item><item><title>Ayam kapitan</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/ayam-kapitan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/ayam-kapitan/</guid><description>Ingredients Chicken pieces Pre-prepared rempah Coconut milk Method Marinate chicken pieces with ground rempah. Fry marinated chicken in a pot on low heat until chicken is cooked. Add in some coconut milk then serve.</description></item><item><title>Curry prawns</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/curry-prawns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/curry-prawns/</guid><description>Ingredients Pre-prepared rempah Pineapple cubes Coconut milk Coconut cream Prawns Method Fry rempah in lots of oil. Add pinapple cubes and coconut milk. Simmer. Add prawns and coconut cream.</description></item><item><title>Lo bak kor</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/lo-bak-kor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/lo-bak-kor/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 radishes, grated Dried shrimp, soaked then finely chopped 1 packet rice flour Method Fry chopped dried shrimp in a pan until crispy. Scoop some out for topping.</description></item><item><title>Sambal ikan bilis</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/sambal-ikan-bilis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/sambal-ikan-bilis/</guid><description>Ingredients Rempah Red onions Lemongrass Galangal Turmeric Belacan Chilli powder Tamarind paste Sugar Ikan bilis, washed and rinsed to remove salt Method Fry ikan bilis in oil on low heat until crisp.</description></item><item><title>Tomato chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/tomato-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/tomato-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients Chicken fillets, cut into pieces Onion, finely chopped/ground Chilli, ground Tomato Vinegar Tomato sauce Sugar Method Marinate chicken pieces with salt. Fry the pieces until slightly browned.</description></item><item><title>Vegetable curry</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/vegetable-curry/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/vegetable-curry/</guid><description>Ingredients Rempah Onion Chilli Lemongrass Galangal Turmeric Belacan Dried shrimp Coconut milk Coconut cream Vegetables Small tofu Fish balls Bean curd sheet Cabbage Long bean Carrot Eggplant Method Grind rempah ingredients together.</description></item><item><title>Brownies</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/brownies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/brownies/</guid><description>Ingredients 200 g butter 1/2 cup cocoa 2 cups brown sugar (can be reduced to 1 3/4) 1 teaspoon imitation vanilla essence 1 cup plain flour 2 eggs Method Turn the oven to 180°C.</description></item><item><title>Coriander chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/coriander-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/coriander-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 kg chicken thigh fillets 2 cloves crushed garlic Salt and pepper to taste 1 tbsp soy sauce 2 tbsp coriander powder 1 tsp turmeric powder Method Marinate chicken in rest of the ingredients for at least 2 hours.</description></item><item><title>Nanna's steamed eggs</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/nannas-steamed-eggs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/nannas-steamed-eggs/</guid><description>Ingredients 5 eggs 1 cup mince 2½ cup warm water Chives Seasoning (light soy) Method Mix everything together in a dish. Microwave on high for 10 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Turmeric rice</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/turmeric-rice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/turmeric-rice/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 cups rice (rice measuring cup, not metric cup) 3 tablespoons coconut cream powder 1 teaspoon turmeric powder Pinch salt Method Wash rice. Add enough water for the quantity of rice.</description></item></channel></rss>