<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lam Family Cookbook</title>
    <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lam Family Cookbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jarodl.am/cookbook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dad&#39;s pork crackling</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/dads-pork-crackling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/dads-pork-crackling/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Pork belly Salt Oil (olive oil or similar) Five-spice powder (optional)  Method  A few days beforehand, place the pork belly on a plate and rub a generous amount of salt onto the skin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Egg rolls</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/egg-rolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/egg-rolls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Omelette  3 eggs Salt Pepper Sesame oil   Filling  Pork mince Spring onion Crushed garlic Soy sauce Cooking wine Oyster sauce Sesame oil Pepper Corn flour or egg (for binding) Sugar    Method  Mix the filling ingredients in a mixing bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Son-in-law eggs</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/son-in-law-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/son-in-law-eggs/</guid>
      <description>Called &amp;ldquo;kai look koei&amp;rdquo; in Thai. Mum learned this in a Thai cooking class decades ago. This recipe is from her old recipe notes.
Ingredients  6 eggs, hard boiled 3 tbsp oil 2 tbsp chopped onion 3 tbsp brown sugar 2 tsp fish sauce 2 tbsp vinegar Fresh chilli and coriander to garnish  Method  Cover bottom of pan with oil and fry the halved eggs yolk side down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuffed eggplant</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stuffed-eggplant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stuffed-eggplant/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Eggplant Filling  Pork mince Spring onion Crushed garlic Soy sauce Cooking wine Oyster sauce Sesame oil Pepper Corn flour or egg (for binding) Sugar   Sauce  2 tbsp corn flour Oyster sauce Sesame oil Water Sugar, garlic, five spice (optional)    Method  Mix the filling ingredients in a mixing bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuffed mushroom</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stuffed-mushroom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stuffed-mushroom/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Dried shiitake mushrooms Filling  Pork mince Spring onion Crushed garlic Soy sauce Cooking wine Oyster sauce Sesame oil Pepper Corn flour or egg (for binding) Sugar   Marinade  Five spice powder Salt Pepper Sesame oil Cooking wine Soy sauce (not too much, the mushrooms are already salty)   Sauce  2 tbsp corn flour Oyster sauce Sesame oil Water Sugar, garlic, five spice (optional)    Method  Mix the filling ingredients in a mixing bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burbur cha cha</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/burbur-cha-cha/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/burbur-cha-cha/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 taro 1 sweet potato Sago pearls 1 can coconut cream (we like Ayam brand) Ginger Sugar  Method  Cut taro and sweet potato into ~1cm diamond shape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet corn soup</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/sweet-corn-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/sweet-corn-soup/</guid>
      <description>Mum&amp;rsquo;s classic sweet corn soup recipe.
Ingredients  1 can corn kernels 1 can creamed corn Finely diced chicken Soup seasoning (dashi, salt, pepper, sesame oil, etc.), adjust according to available ingredients 1 tsp corn flour (approx) 1 egg  Method  Boil about 1 cup water in pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mum&#39;s mapo tofu</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-mapo-tofu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-mapo-tofu/</guid>
      <description>This recipe was adapted by Mum from cousins&#39; grandpa who used to run a Taiwanese restaurant.
Ingredients  1 pack soft tofu Minced pork Diced onion Crushed garlic and ginger Sliced chilli  Method  Cut soft tofu into diamonds and soak in water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mum&#39;s Malaysian curry</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-malaysian-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-malaysian-curry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Aromatics  Chopped onion Garlic and ginger Curry/kaffir lime leaves Lemongrass, bruised Curry powder+water paste   Whole chicken, chopped Potato, chopped Coconut cream  Method  Fry aromatics in a deep pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stir fried kang kung</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stir-fried-kang-kung/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stir-fried-kang-kung/</guid>
      <description>Method  Fry aromatics:  Diced onion Garlic and ginger Shrimps Cut chilli   Add kang kung Fry until wilted, add salt and pepper and sesame oil to taste  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast oats</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/breakfast-oats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/breakfast-oats/</guid>
      <description>Method  In a jar, add:  1 cup oats Assorted dry ingredients:  Chia seeds Cacao nibs Goji berries Sultanas Dried apricot     Then add:  ~1 cup (cover dry ingredients) milk ~1 cup (3 large scoops) yoghurt   Mix thoroughly, add fresh soft fruit on top:  Grapes Berries Mango Peach Nectarine    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hokkien noodles</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/hokkien-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/hokkien-noodles/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 packet (~1 kg) Hokkien noodles Chicken thigh fillets, roughly chopped Soy sauce Oyster sauce Sesame oil Cooking caramel (karamel masakan) Bok choy, leaves and stems separated, stems cut in half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All-in-One Chicken Dinner</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/all-in-one_chicken_dinner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/all-in-one_chicken_dinner/</guid>
      <description>Seasoning Ingredients  1 garlic clove, peeled 20g oil of choice 1 tbsp sweet/mild paprika 1 tsp onion powder ½ tsp salt pinch of pepper and cayenne  Mash Ingredients  600g sweet potato, peeled, cut into small cubes 30g butter (optional) 30g cream (optional) ¼ salt  Remaining Ingredients  800g liquid chicken stock (or 1 tbsp stock concentrate + 800 g water) 500-700g chicken breast, sliced in half length ways 400g vegetables of choice 2 tbsp corn flour or tapioca flour, dissolved in ¼ cup of water  Method  Add garlic clove to mixer bowl, chop for 2 sec/speed 9/MC on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grandma&#39;s Shortbread</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/grandma_s_shortbread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/grandma_s_shortbread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  50 grams cornflour 100 grams white sugar 225 grams Butter cubed, cold 260 grams plain flour  Method  Preheat oven to 160 degrees. Place sugar into mixing bowl and mill for 10 seconds on speed 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gummy Bears</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/gummy_bears/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/gummy_bears/</guid>
      <description>Notes  You can make gummy bears in almost any flavor, using different combinations of freshly squeezed juices or pureed fruits. NOTE: Do not use pineapple – it contains enzymes that break down gelatin so it will not set properly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato Chutney</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tomato_chutney/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tomato_chutney/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  200g red onion- peeled and quartered 1kg ripe tomatoes 250g tart apples-, peeled, cored &amp;amp; chopped into quarters 300g raw sugar 200g apple cider vinegar 1/2 teaspoon allspice 1/2 teaspoon ground ginger 1/2 teaspoon cayenne pepper 2 whole cloves 100g sultanas 2 teaspoons salt  Method  To &amp;ldquo;peel&amp;rdquo; the tomatoes - Score the base of each tomato with a cross.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Body Bath Bombs</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/body_bath_bombs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/body_bath_bombs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  6tbl baking soda 4tbl citric acid 3tbl cornflour 3tbl Epsom salt 2tbl coconut oil (solidified) 3tbl oil of choice (avocado, macadamia, olive or almond) a few drops of essential oil of choice (lavender or a relax blend all work great)  Method  Place all ingredients into your mixing jug and mix until well combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halloumi</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/halloumi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/halloumi/</guid>
      <description>Other Source  http://thecheesemakingworkshop.com.au/recipe/how-to-make-haloumi/  Ingredients  2 litres milk 0.5 teaspoon rennet 50g salt  Method - Setting Curds  Heat milk on temp 37 for 10 mins on speed 1 Mix rennet with 1 tbspn water (filtered or unchlorinated better), and add to milk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthy Caesar Salad</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/healthy_caesar_salad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/healthy_caesar_salad/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 anchovies pinch of salt 1 large garlic clove 1/2 cup extra virgin olive oil 1/2 tablespoon Dijon mustard 3 tablespoons of Worcestershire sauce 1 large free range egg, coddled (sitting in very warm water) 5 large heaping tablespoons of raw Parmesan cheese 1 large lemon 1 head romaine lettuce cleaned and dried thoroughly Your healthy homemade or organic croutons  Method  Crush garlic and anchovies together with a pinch of salt Add about 2 tablespoons of oil Add mustard and Worcestershire sauce and mix well Add oil and mix well Add egg and mix well Add Parmesan cheese and mix well Squeeze juice out of lemon into the dressing and mix well Tear lettuce leaves and toss into dressing Add croutons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pickled Watermelon Rind</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pickled_watermelon_rind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pickled_watermelon_rind/</guid>
      <description>Note  This is the recipe for pickled watermelon rind which I converted for TM5. If I&amp;rsquo;m making a big batch I actually prefer to do it the old fashioned way on the stove top because you can double the quantities in this recipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple &amp; Sultana Porridge</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/apple_sultana_porridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/apple_sultana_porridge/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 large sweet apple, (quartered &amp;amp; cored) 50 grams oats 350 grams milk 50 grams sultanas cinnamon, (to taste)  Method  Add apple to the bowl &amp;amp; grate 3 seconds, speed 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry &amp; Choc Chip Muffins</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/blueberry_choc_chip_muffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/blueberry_choc_chip_muffins/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  170 grams milk 75 grams vegetable oil 2 eggs 120 grams sugar 30 grams desicated coconut 300 grams Self Raising Flour 2 teaspoons baking powder, 125 125 grams white, milk or dark choc chips 125 grams blueberries  Method  Preheat oven to 180* fan forced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaky Bliss Bombs</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/breaky_bliss_bombs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/breaky_bliss_bombs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  100 grams sunflower seeds 50 grams desicated coconut 100 grams oats 50 grams almonds 25 grams Linseeds 1/2 tablespoon chia seeds 1/2 tablespoon cacao/ cocoa 150 grams pitted dates 1/2 tablespoon honey 1/2 m/c water  Method  Add sunflower seeds &amp;amp; coconut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cappucino</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cappucino/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cappucino/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  300 grams milk per serve instant coffee to taste sugar to taste  Method  Add all ingredients to the bowl and heat 4 minutes, 70/75*, speed 3. Now froth your milk by blending 20 seconds, speed 8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheese and Bacon Bread Rolls</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheese_and_bacon_bread_rolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheese_and_bacon_bread_rolls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  360 grams water, lukewarm 1.5 teaspoons sugar, optional 2 teaspoons dried instant yeast 600 grams white bakers flour 2 teaspoons salt 2 teaspoons bread improver 1 tablespoon oil 150 grams mixed cheese  Method  Add all ingredients (excluding cheese &amp;amp; bacon) to your thermo bowl in order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken &amp; Vegetable Pie Filling</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_vegetable_pie_filling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_vegetable_pie_filling/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 onion, quartered 2 cloves garlic 350-400 grams mixed roughly chopped vege 1 tablespoon oil 2 teaspoons wholegrain or dijon mustard 1 tablespoon thermomix vege stock concentrate 100 grams frozen veggies 100 grams cream 100 grams milk 400 grams raw diced chicken small handful diced bacon 2 tablespoons cornflour, (cornflour paste) 2 tablespoons water, (cornflour paste)  Method  Add onion, garlic &amp;amp; mixed chopped vege to bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easiyo Homemade Yoghurt</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/easiyo_homemade_yoghurt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/easiyo_homemade_yoghurt/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1/2 cup full milk powder 1/4 cup starter, full fat pot set yoghurt - yoghurt with live cultures in the ingredients list 800 grams full fat UHT/ longlife milk 2-3 tablespoons sugar, optional for a sweet vanilla version 1-2 teaspoons vanilla, optional for a sweet vanilla version  Method  Add all ingredients to a super clean bowl &amp;amp; heat 4 minutes, 37*, speed 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gravy</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/gravy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/gravy/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup water 2 tablespoons gravy powder  Method  Add water &amp;amp; gravy powder to bowl, cook 7 minutes, 100*, speed 4.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Icey Iced Coffee</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/icey_iced_coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/icey_iced_coffee/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  250 grams ice cubes 200 grams full cream milk 2 tablespoons sugar 2 heaped teaspoons instant coffee  Method  Add all ingredients to the bowl &amp;amp; blend 3 minutes, speed 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Nutella &amp; Tim Tam Ice Cream</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/quick_nutella_tim_tam_ice_cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/quick_nutella_tim_tam_ice_cream/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 pack of Tim Tams, (broken in half) 50 grams sugar 600 ml tub of cream 200 grams milk 100 grams Nutella  Method  Add tim tams to bowl &amp;amp; crush 4 seconds, speed 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steamed Breakfast Eggs</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/steamed_breakfast_eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/steamed_breakfast_eggs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 litre water silicone moulds eggs  Method  Place 1L of boiling water in your bowl. (You can boil the water in your electric kettle, or simply heat till temp in Thermie).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Bun Dough</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sweet_bun_dough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sweet_bun_dough/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  275 grams water, lukewarm 5 teaspoons instant dried yeast 550 grams white bakers flour 1 teaspoon salt 2 teaspoons milk powder, optional 2 teaspoons bread improver 65 grams sugar 45 grams soft butter  Method  Add all ingredients to your thermo bowl in order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thick Chocolate Custard</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thick_chocolate_custard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thick_chocolate_custard/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  ?? grams cream 250 grams milk 2 eggs 50 grams cornflour 60-100 grams sugar, to taste 25 grams cocoa powder, (or replace with a couple rows of chocolate &amp;amp; reduce sugar)  Method  Add all ingredients to bowl &amp;amp; cook 8 minutes, 90*, speed 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thick Vanilla Custard</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thick_vanilla_custard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thick_vanilla_custard/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  50 grams cream 250 grams milk 2 eggs 50 grams custard powder, (or cornflour if you prefer) 60-100 grams sugar, to taste 1-2 teaspoons Vanilla Bean Paste  Method  Add all ingredients to bowl &amp;amp; cook 8 minutes, 90*, speed 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thick Yoghurt - Electric Yoghurt Maker</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thick_yoghurt_-_electric_yoghurt_maker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thick_yoghurt_-_electric_yoghurt_maker/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1/2 cup full fat milk powder 1/4 cup starter, full fat pot set yoghurt - yoghurt with live cultures in the ingredients list or 1 portion of dried yoghurt cultures (match head worth) 1 litre full uht/ longlife milk 2-3 tablespoons sugar, (optional, for a sweet vanilla version) 1-2 teaspoons vanilla, (optional, for a sweet vanilla version)  Method  Add all ingredients to a super clean bowl &amp;amp; heat 4 minutes, 37*, speed 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanilla Bean Paste</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/vanilla_bean_paste/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/vanilla_bean_paste/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  150 grams water, boiling 150 grams sugar 50 grams Vanilla Bean Powder 60 grams vanilla extract  Method  Add boiling water &amp;amp; carefully add sugar to bowl making sure not to pour on the blades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whatever Ice Cream</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/whatever_ice_cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/whatever_ice_cream/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 litre full cream milk 200 grams sugar 600 ml Cream mix-ins- toppings/ flavourings of your choice  Method  Add milk &amp;amp; sugar to bowl. Cook 45 minutes, 100*, speed 3, MC OFF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/banana_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/banana_cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 1/2 cups self raising flour 1 tsp bicarb of soda 1 cup castor sugar (reduce to 3/4 cup) 4 eggs, lightly beaten 1 1/4 cups mashed banana (about 5 large ripe bananas) 1 cup oil  Ingredients - Icing  100g packaged cream cheese 60g butter 1 tsp vanilla essence 1 tbl apricot jam 2 cups icing sugar  Method  Grease a 23cm square slab pan, cover base with grease-proof paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheese and Bacon Crackers</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheese_and_bacon_crackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheese_and_bacon_crackers/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  5 slices shortcut bacon, the smokier in flavour the better 180g plain flour 1 teaspoon smoked paprika 1 teaspoon dried garlic powder 1 teaspoon dried onion powder 1 teaspoon salt 80g cold butter, cubed 120g grated cheddar or similar cheese 1 - 2 tablespoons of cold water  Method  Preheat oven to 180 degrees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheesy Herb Crackers</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheesy_herb_crackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheesy_herb_crackers/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  180g plain flour 1 tablespoon of dried mixed herbs 1 tsp garlic powder, optional 80g cold butter, cubed 35g parmesan cheese, cubed 100g grated cheddar or similar cheese 1 tsp salt 1 - 2 tablespoons of cold water  Method  Preheat oven to 180 degrees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweetened Condensed Milk</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sweetened_condensed_milk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sweetened_condensed_milk/</guid>
      <description>Note  This is equivalent to one 395g can of condensed milk  .
Ingredients  125 g water 225 g sugar 110 g powdered milk 1 pinch salt  Method  Measure ingredients into TM bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BBQ Style Beef Jerky</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/bbq_style_beef_jerky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/bbq_style_beef_jerky/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients    Method    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brioche</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/brioche/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/brioche/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  30 g caster sugar 330 g Full-cream milk 3 tsp dried yeast 80 g Butter 1 tsp sea salt 650 g BAKERS flour 1 egg 2 egg whites 1 tbsp water Brie Cheese wheel or Camembert (Personal preference)  Method  Place sugar, milk and yeast into mixing bowl and heat 2 min/37 degrees/speed 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brioche - the No Knead Version</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/brioche_-_the_no_knead_version/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/brioche_-_the_no_knead_version/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients    Method    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apricot &amp; Chia Balls</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/apricot_chia_balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/apricot_chia_balls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500g dried apricots 1/4 cup (60ml) hot water 1/4 cup (20g) shredded coconut 1/3 cup peanut butter 1/4 cup (60 ml) honey 1 tablespoon cocoa powder 1/4 cup (35g) sesame seeds 1 cup (160g) pepitas 1/4 cup (35g) chia seeds 1 cup (90g) rolled oats  Method  Line a large tray with non-stick baking paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Cereal Bars</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/strawberry_cereal_bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/strawberry_cereal_bars/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1.5 cups plain flour 1.5 cups rolled oats 1 cup brown sugar (Note: Too sweet. Half the sugar next time) 1 tsp baking powder 1/2 tsp salt 225 butter, cubed 280g strawberry jam  Method  Preheat oven to 180 deg C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basil Pesto</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/basil_pesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/basil_pesto/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  50 g Parmesan cheese, cubed 2 cloves fresh garlic peeled 1 bunch basil leaves, fresh (stalks removed) 100 g cashew nut or pine nuts, roasted, unsalted 1 tbl lemon juice 1 tsp sugar, optional salt &amp;amp; pepper, optional 120 g olive oil, extra virgin  Method 1  Place parmesan and garlic into TM bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Forest Cheesecake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/black_forest_cheesecake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/black_forest_cheesecake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  250g plain chocolate biscuits 125g butter, melted 3 teaspoons gelatine ½ cup (125ml) water 250g packet cream cheese, softened (room temperature - this is very important!) ¾ cup (165g) caster sugar 1 tablespoon lemon juice 300ml thickened cream 425g can pitted black cherries  topping</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Truffles</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_truffles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_truffles/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  100g dates 50g dried apricots 100g coconut butter 60g ground almonds 40g walnuts 30g cocoa powder  Method  Put dates and apricots in a bowl and cover them with warm water for 10 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon and Coconut Balls</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_and_coconut_balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_and_coconut_balls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  zest of one lemon juice of two lemons 3 tbs maple syrup 75g (1 cup) almond meal 75g cocount oil, melted 100g (1 cup) desiccated coconut 5 medjool dates, pitted extra coconut for rolling ball in  Method  Peel the lemon zest off using a potato peeler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Butter</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_butter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_butter/</guid>
      <description>Recipe 1 - Lemon Butter made with Rapadura ==Refer http://www.quirkycooking.com.au/2011/01/lemon-butter-made-with-rapadura/
Ingredients  60g Rapadura 1/4 tsp stevia liquid or powder juice of 1 lemon 80g ghee or butter or coconut oil 2 eggs  Method  Grind rapadura for 30 seconds on speed 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Bake Lime Cheesecake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/no_bake_lime_cheesecake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/no_bake_lime_cheesecake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  250g plain biscuits (I used Marie) 125g of softened butter 370g cream cheese (room temp – this is very important!) 400g condensed milk 250g thickened cream 75g of lime juice zest of lime  Method  Put peel of lime in TM to zest 5 sec / speed 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthy Granola</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/healthy_granola/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/healthy_granola/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups raw, whole rolled oats (aka old fashion oats) ½ cup raw nuts, chopped ¼ cup raw seeds (sunflower or pumpkin seeds are great) ½ cup unsweetened dried fruit, chopped (optional) 2-3 tablespoons grade-b maple syrup or raw honey (or a combo of both) 2 tbsp virgin coconut oil or other healthy cooking oil ½ tsp vanilla extract or almond extract 1 large pinch fine sea salt  Method  Preheat the oven to 300º F or 150 deg C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aloe Vera Gel</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/aloe_vera_gel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/aloe_vera_gel/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Aloe vera leaves 500mg powdered Vitamin C or 400 IU vitamin E (for every 1/4 cup of gel)- optional  Method  Wash your hands. It&amp;rsquo;s important to start with clean hands and use clean tools to make sure the gel doesn&amp;rsquo;t get contaminated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Popcorn</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/popcorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/popcorn/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Unpopped popcorn kernels Flavacol flavouring Butter  Method  Heat up an empty saucepan on a stove for a few minutes. Melt the butter in the pan. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry if it turns brown, just make sure it doesn&amp;rsquo;t turn black because that means it is burnt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Layered Fruity Dream Ice Cream Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/layered_fruity_dream_ice_cream_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/layered_fruity_dream_ice_cream_cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  350 grams Frozen strawberries 350 grams Frozen Oranges 350 grams Frozen Mixed Berries 3 egg whites 180 grams raw sugar  Method  Place all sugar into TM Closed lid and pulverise for 20 seconds on speed 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkish Bread</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/turkish_bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/turkish_bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  15g dried yeast 5g caster sugar 375g warm water (125g and 250g) 480g bakers flour (100g and 380g) 1 tsp salt 60g olive oil  Method  Add yeast, sugar and 125g water to the bowl and mix on Speed 3 for 10 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef jerky</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beef_jerky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beef_jerky/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 1/2 to 2 pounds flank steak 2/3 cup Worcestershire sauce 2/3 cup soy sauce 1 tablespoon honey 2 teaspoons freshly ground black pepper 2 teaspoons onion powder 1 teaspoon liquid smoke 1 teaspoon red pepper flakes  Method  Trim the flank steak of any excess fat, place in a zip-top bag, and place it in the freezer for 1 to 2 hours in order to firm up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Purpose Scrub</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/all_purpose_scrub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/all_purpose_scrub/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  ½ cup ground oatmeal ¼ cup almond meal ¼ cup sunflower seed meal 1 teaspoon ground peppermint, spearmint, or rosemary leaves Dash cinnamon powder (optional, but adds a hint of exotic fragrance).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamed Corn</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamed_corn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamed_corn/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  400 – 450 gram fresh cooked corn kernels., It is about five or six ears of sweet corn (you can use frozen kernels if you prefer, just cook it) 50 gram Butter, (1 Tablespoon) 50 gram flour, (1 Tablespoon) 500 gram milk, (2 Cups) 15-40 gram sugar, (to taste) salt and pepper to taste  Method  Cook or steam corn, and then cut kernels off the cobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crumpets 2</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crumpets_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crumpets_2/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  5 grams Yeast 1 cup Flour 1 tsp Salt 2 tbsp Butter 2 cups Water warm  Method  In a bowl or jug, mix the yeast with a few tablespoons of the warm water, stir until the yeast is dissolved and leave for about five minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Onion Soup Mix</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/french_onion_soup_mix/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/french_onion_soup_mix/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  4 tablespoons Onion powder 1 tablespoon Garlic powder 1 teaspoon celery salt 1/4 teaspoon white pepper 1 tablespoon beef stock powder 1/4 teaspoon sugar 1/2 teaspoon curry powder, optional  Method  Add all ingredients to TMX bowl and blitz for 30 seconds on speed 9 Store in a screw top jar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Condensed Milk</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_condensed_milk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_condensed_milk/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  80g water 90g butter 110g full cream milk powder 150g raw sugar  Method  Insert butterfly and add ingredients. Cook 6mins/90 deg/sp 4.  Note  You can double the recipe and cook for 10 mins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muesli Bar</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/muesli_bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/muesli_bar/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1½ cups rolled oats (use quinoa flakes for a gluten free option) ⅓ cup activated sunflower seeds ⅓ cup activated pumpkin seeds ¼ cup sesame seeds 2 tbp chia seeds ⅓ cup coconut flakes ¼ cup chopped raw cashews (or nut of your choice) ½ cup rice malt syrup ¼ cup coconut oil ¼ cup boiling water Generous pinch of sea salt  Method  Preheat oven to 170°C and line a 20cm square tin with baking paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raw Cashew and Coconut Protein Balls</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/raw_cashew_and_coconut_protein_balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/raw_cashew_and_coconut_protein_balls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup cashews 2 tbsp protein powder (I used vanilla soy protein which is dairy-free) ¼ cup shredded coconut 1 tbsp chia seeds 2 tbsp honey 10-12 pitted dates  Method  Place cashews in your food processor and blend into fine crumbs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Easy Homemade Room Spritzers</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/5_easy_homemade_room_spritzers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/5_easy_homemade_room_spritzers/</guid>
      <description>1. Minty Citrus Twist  Combine 4 drops Peppermint essential oil + 4 drops Wild Orange essential oil + 1 Tablespoon real vanilla extract in 8 oz of water.  2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate and Orange Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_and_orange_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_and_orange_cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Cake  2 oranges 1500 g water 6 eggs 250 g raw sugar 200 g whole raw almonds 1 tsp baking powder 1/2 tsp bi carb 50 g cocoa  Ingredients - Icing  150 g raw sugar 20 g cocoa 1/2 tsp orange essence 40 g milk  Method - Cake  Pour water into the bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Bath Salts</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_bath_salts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_bath_salts/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Coarse sea salt Epsom salts Baking soda Essential oils Food coloring  Method  In a large bowl, mix to combine: 6 parts coarse sea salt; 3 parts epsom salts, to soothe tired muscles and reduce inflammation; and 1 part baking soda, to soften waters and alleviate skin irritation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Body Wash</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_body_wash/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_body_wash/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  ¼ cup coconut oil ¼ cup raw honey ½ cup liquid Castile soap 1 teaspoon vitamin E 15 drops eucalyptus essential oil 10 drops sweet orange essential oil 10 drops lemon or grapefruit essential oil  Method  Scoop coconut oil into a microwave safe bowl and heat on medium setting for 30 seconds until melted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Citrus Lavender Perfume</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_citrus_lavender_perfume/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_citrus_lavender_perfume/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 tsp beeswax 2 tsp carrier oil – sweet almond oil or jojoba oil 48 drops essential oils - 12 drops each of lemon, sweet orange, bergamot &amp;amp; lavender essential oils Old lip balm tin (the size I used was 1/2 ounce)  Method  It’s definitely a good idea to blend the essential oils first before you start working with the beeswax because it hardens really, really fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Fabric Softener Crystals</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_fabric_softener_crystals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_fabric_softener_crystals/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  4 cups Epsom Salts 40 drops Essential Oils  Method  Mix them together and you are done.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Foaming Hand Soap</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_foaming_hand_soap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_foaming_hand_soap/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 T Castille Soap 2 t Coconut Oil, Fractionated 5 drops melaleuca essential oil 5-10 drops other essential oil for fragrance (optional)  water
 foaming hand soap dispenser  Method  Add castile soap, coconut oil and essential oils to a foaming hand soap dispenser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Hand Cream</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_hand_cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_hand_cream/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1/4 cup shea butter 1/8 cup sweet almond oil 1 tablespoon beeswax 10 drops myrrh essential oil 10 drops cedarwood essential oil  Method  Melt the shea butter, beeswax, and sweet almond oil together in a double boiler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Hand Sanitizer with Essential Oils</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_hand_sanitizer_with_essential_oils/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_hand_sanitizer_with_essential_oils/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  4 oz glass spray bottle (not plastic!)  Water
 2 teaspoons aloe vera gel 30 drops total of one of the following essential oil combinations:  Lemon, lime, melaleuca, and lavender OR my DIY anti-bacterial blend OR doTERRA&amp;rsquo;s On Guard blend</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Honey Lavender Relaxing Bath Melts</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_honey_lavender_relaxing_bath_melts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_honey_lavender_relaxing_bath_melts/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  50 grams Shea Butter 50 grams Cocoa Butter 1/4 teaspoon Yogi brand Honey Lavendar Stress Relief Herbal Organic Tea 1 teaspoon lavender flowers (you can also find this at your local craft store possibly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Hot Process Soap in a crock pot</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_hot_process_soap_in_a_crock_pot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_hot_process_soap_in_a_crock_pot/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  10 oz olive oil 20 oz coconut oil 9 oz distilled water 4.78 oz 100% pure lye Essential oils for scent (optional)  Other Equipment  Digital scale Safety gear (safety glasses, long sleeves, gloves) Stick blender Crock pot Non-metal dishes and utensils  Method  Measure out the olive and coconut oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Peppermint Extract</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_peppermint_extract/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_peppermint_extract/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup fresh mint leaves 1 1/2 to 2 cups of vodka  Method  Harvest the mint, and give it a quick rinse. Pat dry. Remove the leaves from the stems, and discard the stems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Vanilla Extract</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_vanilla_extract/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_vanilla_extract/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  6-7 beans for a quart of vanilla (or just 2 for a half pint) Vodka to fill jar  Method  Split the beans lengthwise Then chop into 3-4 inch pieces Place the beans into your glass jar and fill to the top with vodka Steep 2 to 8 months (2 months should be fine for a pint, but the longer is sits the better it gets so no worries if you forget about it for a few months)  Notes  Glass jars or containers are ideal to avoid any possible chemicals leaching into your vanilla from the plastic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Vanilla Extract (with or without alcohol)</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_vanilla_extract_with_or_without_alcohol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_vanilla_extract_with_or_without_alcohol/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 glass swing top or other tall bottle (more if you are making gifts) (where to find) 8 ounces vodka, rum or bourbon (vodka is traditional) OR 8 ounces food-grade glycerin (non-alcoholic version) 3-5 whole vanilla beans per 8 ounces of liquid  Method  Cut vanilla beans in half lengthwise with a sharp knife or kitchen scissors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peppermint &amp; Citrus Sugar Scrub</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/peppermint_citrus_sugar_scrub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/peppermint_citrus_sugar_scrub/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup granulated white sugar 1/4-1/3 cup oil: coconut oil, olive oil, sweet almond oil, apricot oil, avocado oil, or a combination Optional: 2-4 Tablespoons orange or grapefruit zest (for extra exfoliation) Optional: 2 Tablespoons vegetable glycerin (extra moisturizing) 10 drops peppermint essential oil 10-15 drops wild orange essential oil (lemon or grapefruit will also work- or any combination of these)  Method  Mix sugar, oil, zest, and vegetable glycerin (if using) together Depending on what type of oil you use, add more or less to make the sugar stick together, but not enough to float on top Gradually add essential oils until you’ve reached the desired scent Store your sugar scrub in a glass container and feel free to decorate with ribbon, stickers, etc To Use: Rub a small amount on hands or body and rinse with warm water  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whipped Body Butter</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/whipped_body_butter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/whipped_body_butter/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients for White Chocolate Body Butter  1/4 cup shea butter 1/4 cup cocoa butter 1/4 cup coconut oil 1/4 cup sweet almond oil 10-20 drops of essential oil  Ingredients for Regular Body Butter  Note: This version does not smell like chocolate /2 cup shea butter 1/4 cup coconut oil 1/4 cup sweet almond oil 10-20 drops of essential oil  Method  Combine all ingredients, except the essential oils, in a small pot or double boiler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meat Stock Concentrate</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/meat_stock_concentrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/meat_stock_concentrate/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  300g lean Gravy Beef, but not totally fat free (Note: try using other meat) 550g of mixed veggies, eg e: carrot, celery, zucchini, tomato, onion, garlic 1-2 sprigs of rosemary, thyme, basil, parsley (or equiv of herbs you like/have on hand) 1x bay leaf 100g of red wine 150g of salt 30g of olive oil (or your preferred oil)  Method  Mince your meat by placing partially frozen meat in the TM bowl and hitting turbo 2-4 times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY Body Lotion</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/diy_body_lotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/diy_body_lotion/</guid>
      <description>Trial 1 (17/05/15) - Aloe Vera Lotion  1 1/2 tablespoons shea butter 8 tablespoons jojoba oil 2 tablespoons grated beeswax 1 cup (250ml) of aloe vera gel (about the same temperature as the oil-beeswax combo) 1 tsp Vitamin E 3 tsp glycerine 8 drops (or more) lemon essential Oils  Method  Melt butter, oil &amp;amp; beewax in a double boiler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy Homemade Lotion</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/easy_homemade_lotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/easy_homemade_lotion/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: g  Base Lotion-Making Formula  1 part oil 2 parts water (or rose water, green tea, aloe-vera gel, etc) 1/4 part beeswax To this, you can also add: 1/8 to 1/4 part cocoa or shea butter, if using a few drops of essential oil or oils of your choice – add them to the water prior to incorporating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Mineral Sunscreen</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/natural_mineral_sunscreen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/natural_mineral_sunscreen/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: g  Ingredients  6 teaspoons (24g) Coconut Oil or shea butter 6 teaspoons (36g) Vegetable Glycerine 2 teaspoons (6g) Titanium Dioxide 2 teaspoons (6g) Zinc Oxide  Method  Measure out dry ingredients into a small mixing bowl and add the glycerine one teaspoon at a time while stirring until evenly combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY Lip Balm</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/diy_lip_balm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/diy_lip_balm/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 tsp. coconut oil 2 1/4 tsp. beeswax (or candellila wax) 2 1/8 tsp. sweet almond oil 2/3 tsp. olive oil Small containers  Method  Pour a couple inches of water into a shallow saucepan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ginger Kisses</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/ginger_kisses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/ginger_kisses/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients &amp;ndash; Biscuits  250g Butter 3/4 cup of Brown Sugar (160g) 1/2 cup of Golden Syrup or Treacle (170g) 5 cups of Plain Flour (780g) 3 cups of Butter Milk (normal milk is fine, they just won’t be as light) 2 Eggs 3 Tablespoons of Ground Ginger 2 Teaspoon of Cinnamon 2 Teaspoon of Mixed Spice 1 Teaspoon of Bicarbonate of Soda  Ingredients &amp;ndash; Icing  1 x 250g Block of Philadelphia Cream Cheese (full Cream) 2 Cups of Pure Icing Sugar (360g) 2 Teaspoons of Ground Ginger  Non-Thermomix Method - Biscuit  Preheat oven to 180 degrees celsius and prepare tray with baking paper In a large mixing bowl cream butter, sugar and syrup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Mint Chocolate Lip Gloss</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_mint_chocolate_lip_gloss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_mint_chocolate_lip_gloss/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 teaspoon coconut oil 1 teaspoon pure almond oil 1 teaspoon cocoa butter 3-4 drops pure vitamin E oil 1-2 drops pure peppermint extract 3-4 semisweet chocolate chips  Method  Place all ingredients in a small heat-safe bowl (glass or metal is good) and set aside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Natural Makeup</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_natural_makeup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_natural_makeup/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 tablespoons zinc oxide (Can use arrowroot powder instead if desired, but it will not offer quite as much coverage) 1 tablespoon arrowroot powder (optional) 1 teaspoon gold mica dust ½ - 1 tsp of desired natural clay powder (optional) I used a pinch of White cosmetic clay, Fuller&amp;rsquo;s Earth Clay and french green clay up to 1 teaspoon finely ground cocoa powder OR bonze mica powder (or both) to get desired color Optional: 1 teaspoon of translucent mica powder can help for really oily skin  Method  Mix all ingredients to get desired color and coverage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Liquid Foundation</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/natural_liquid_foundation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/natural_liquid_foundation/</guid>
      <description>The Base Moisturizer  There are actually two options for the base of this recipe: the simple way or the DIY way.   For a simpler version, use a natural pre-made moisturizer for the base and add colors and pigments as needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-Greasy Homemade Moisturizing Lotion</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/non-greasy_homemade_moisturizing_lotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/non-greasy_homemade_moisturizing_lotion/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup aloe vera gel 1 teaspoon vitamin E oil 3/4 ounce (21 g) beeswax, grated or broken into small pieces 1/2 cup almond or grapeseed oil 1 tablespoon cocoa butter (I added this for a slightly more luxurious lotion during the winter, but this is optional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Tinted Lip Balm</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pink_tinted_lip_balm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pink_tinted_lip_balm/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 tbl grated beeswax. Grate it with a dollar store or old cheese grater. You will never be able to use it for anything else after you grate beeswax on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snickerdoodles (American Biscuits)</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/snickerdoodles_american_biscuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/snickerdoodles_american_biscuits/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  250g Copha (Vegetable Shortening) make sure you copha is a room temperature. 1 1/2 Cups (300g) Sugar 2 Eggs 2 3/4 Cups(470g) Plain Flour 2 Teaspoons Cream of Tartar 1 Teaspoon Bicarbonate of Soda pinch of salt Cinnamon sugar (2 Teaspoons Cinnamon, 1/4 cup castor sugar)  Non-Thermomix Method  Preheat oven to 180ºC and line large baking trays with baking paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken &amp; Vege Pie Filling</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_vege_pie_filling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_vege_pie_filling/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 Onion (quartered) 2 garlic cloves 350g - 400g mixed chopped vege 1 tbsp oil 2 tsp mustard 1 tbsp TMX vege stock 100g frozen veggies 100g cream 100g milk 400g chopped chicken Small handful diced bacon 2 tbsp cornflour 2 tbsp water  Method  ADD ONION, GARLIC &amp;amp; MIXED CHOPPED VEGE TO THE BOWL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fruit Loaf &amp; Rolls</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fruit_loaf_rolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fruit_loaf_rolls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  275g water 5 tsp dried instant yeast 550g bakers flour 1 tsp salt 2 tsp milk powder (optional) 2 tsp bread improver 65g sugar 2 tsp ground cinnamon 2 tsp ground nutmeg 45g soft butter 250g dried fruit of choice  Method  ADD ALL INGREDIENTS TO THE BOWL IN THE ORDER LISTED (EXCEPT THE DRIED FRUIT).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garlic, Cheese &amp; Spinach Naan</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/garlic_cheese_spinach_naan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/garlic_cheese_spinach_naan/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Naan  2 tsp instant dried yeast 500g bakers flour 20g oil 1 tsp salt 3 tsp minced garlic 300g water  Ingredients - Fillings  Shredded baby spinach Grated cheese Ghee or butter  Method  ADD NAAN INGREDIENTS TO THE BOWL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Up &amp; Go</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_up_go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_up_go/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 Weetbix 1 banana (fresh or frozen) 200g milk 1 tsp vanilla 2 tbsp Milo 15g honey 150g ice  Method  ADD ALL INGREDIENTS TO THE BOWL &amp;amp; BLEND 1 MIN 30 SECONDS, SPEED 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Cross Buns</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hot_cross_buns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hot_cross_buns/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Bun Dough  275g water 5 tsp instant dried yeast 550g bakers flour 1 tsp salt 2 tsp milk powder (optional) 2 tsp bread improver 65g sugar 2 tsp ground cinnamon 2 tsp ground nutmeg 45g soft butter 250g sultanas or mixed fruit  Ingredients - Cross Mixture  4 tbsp chilled water 4 tbsp flour  Ingredients - Bun Glaze Mixture  2 tbsp water 2 tbsp sugar  Method  ADD ALL INGREDIENTS TO THE BOWL IN THE ORDER LISTED (EXCEPT THE DRIED FRUIT).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mango &amp; Coconut Bars</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/mango_coconut_bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/mango_coconut_bars/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1000g mango 50g honey 20g lemon 300g cream 50g desicated coconut  Method  ADD MANGO, HONEY &amp;amp; LEMON TO THE BOWL. BLEND 30 SECONDS, SPEED 8. SET ASIDE IN A SEPARATE BOWL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multigrain Bread</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/multigrain_bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/multigrain_bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients-Presoak  100 g mixed grains/seeds 50 g boiling water  Ingredients-Dough  280 g water 1.5 tsp Sugar (optional) 2 tsp dried instant yeast 470 g white bakers flour 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Bread</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/white_bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/white_bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  370 g water 1.5 tsp Sugar (optional) 2 tsp dried instant yeast 620g white bakers flour 2 tsp salt 2 tsp bread improver (optional but helps to produce a fluffy loaf) 1 tbsp oil  Method  ADD ALL INGREDIENTS TO THE BOWL IN THE ORDER LISTED.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custard Tea Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/custard_tea_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/custard_tea_cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Custard  500ml (g) Full Cream Milk 50 g Butter 50g Cornflour 2 Eggs 40g Castor Sugar 1 Teaspoon Vanilla Essence  Ingredients - Cake  250g Butter (softened) 2/3 Cup (140g) Castor Sugar 1 1/2 Cups (260g) Self Raising Flour 2 Eggs 1/2 Cup (60g) Cornflour 2 Teaspoons Vanilla  Method - Custard  Place all custard ingredients into the mixing bowl and cook, 7 minutes/90ºC/speed 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Ingredients Vanilla Ice Cream</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/3_ingredients_vanilla_ice_cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/3_ingredients_vanilla_ice_cream/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 litre Thickend cream 2 teaspoon Vanilla essance 1 Tin of condensed milk  Method  Insert the butterfly Put the Vanilla and the cream into the TM bowl Speed 2 - whilst this is spinning add the condensed milk through the hole on lid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Braided Gluten Free Nutella Bread</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/braided_gluten_free_nutella_bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/braided_gluten_free_nutella_bread/</guid>
      <description>![]({tag&amp;gt;Thermomix Snacks Bread ToTry)
Ingredients  3 cups (420 g) Gluten Free Bread Flour*, plus more for sprinkling 1/4 teaspoon cream of tartar 1 teaspoon (3 g) instant yeast 1/4 cup (50 g) granulated sugar 1/2 teaspoon (3 g) kosher salt 2/3 cup (5 1/3 fluid ounces) warm milk (about 95°F) 2 eggs (120 g, out of shell) at room temperature, beaten 4 tablespoons (56 g) unsalted butter, melted and cooled 1/3 cup (about 100 g) Nutella hazelnut spread, warmed a bit to make it more easily spreadable Egg wash, for brushing (1 egg + 1 tablespoon water, beaten well)  Method   In the bowl of your stand mixer, place the flour, cream of tartar, instant yeast and sugar, and use a handheld whisk to combine well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANZAC Biscuits</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/anzac_biscuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/anzac_biscuits/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  125 grams butter 1 tbsp golden syrup 170 grams brown sugar (recipe is for 220g of sugar but I find 170g is enough) 95 grams rolled oats 90 grams desiccated coconut 150 grams plain flour 1 tsp bicarbonate soda 2 tbsp boiling water 1/2 tsp salt  Method  Preheat oven to 180°C (160°C fan forced).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grain Free ANZAC Biscuits</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/grain_free_anzac_biscuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/grain_free_anzac_biscuits/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  80-100g raw dates, pitted 40g water 1/4 tsp fine sea salt 1/2 tsp bicarb soda 140g coconut oil (slightly melted) 200g almond meal 100g coconut flakes 100g macadamia nuts (or almonds, cashews, or other nuts)  Method  Preheat oven to 170 degrees Celcius, and line baking trays with baking paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spelt ANZAC Biscuits</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spelt_anzac_biscuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spelt_anzac_biscuits/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  160g spelt flour (or gluten free flour) 80-100g Rapadura or coconut sugar 100g rolled oats (or quinoa flakes for Grain Free) 70g dessicated coconut 1/4 tsp fine sea salt 1/2 tsp baking soda 2 Tbspns boiling water 140g coconut oil (slightly melted) 1 Tbspn black molasses  Method  Preheat oven to 180 degrees Celcius.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almond and Cashew Healthy Balls</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/almond_and_cashew_healthy_balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/almond_and_cashew_healthy_balls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  150g cashews 150g almonds 40g shredded coconut 200g dried figs, roughly chopped 3tsp maca powder 3tbl cacao powder 2tbl white sesame seeds 30g agave syrup 50g coconut oil, melted  Method  Add cashews, almonds &amp;amp; coconut to TM bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rosemary and Garlic Roast Lamb</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/rosemary_and_garlic_roast_lamb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/rosemary_and_garlic_roast_lamb/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1.6kg leg of lamb 3 garlic cloves, halved 2 tablespoons fresh rosemary leaves 60ml (1/4 cup) olive oil 1kg chat (small coliban) potatoes, halved 300g (2 cups) frozen baby peas 20g butter 2 tablespoons shredded fresh mint  Ingredients - Wine Gravy  2 tablespoons plain flour 375ml (1 1/2 cups) Campbell&amp;rsquo;s Real Stock Chicken 125ml (1/2 cup) dry white wine  Method  Preheat oven to 200°C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Pepper Rolls (Vegetarian)</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/black_pepper_rolls_vegetarian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/black_pepper_rolls_vegetarian/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Dough  240g water 40g icing sugar 500g flour 1/4tsp salt 50g olive oil  Ingredients - Filling  400g celery stalks 60g bamboo shoots, fresh 500g king oyster mushrooms 50g olive oil 40g soy sauce 10g sugar 1/4tsp allspice, ground 2 tsp black peppercorns 20g corn starch 20g honey 50g sesame seeds, white  Method - Dough  Place all dough ingredients into mixing bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buckwheat and Barley Sticks</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/buckwheat_and_barley_sticks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/buckwheat_and_barley_sticks/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  300g peeled buckwheat, roasted or buckwheat grains, fresh 80g pearl barley or other type of barley 300g water, lukewarm 200g plain flour 70g oil 30g butter  30g fresh yeast or 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garlic Pepper Prawns</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/garlic_pepper_prawns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/garlic_pepper_prawns/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  15g garlic cloves 5g olive oil 10g red chilies, dried, thinly sliced 10g spring onions, thinly sliced 1/2 tsp salt 600g prawns, raw 50g rice wine 1tbl white pepper, ground  Method  Place garlic into mixing bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prawn Ball Soup</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/prawn_ball_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/prawn_ball_soup/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  150g prawns, raw, peeled, aptted dry with a paper towel 2tsp salt 1/2tsp pepper, freshly ground 1.5 tsp potato starch or corn starch 1.5 tsp sugar 10g spring onions, cut into 1cm pieces 500g water  Method  Place prawns, 1/2tsp salt, pepper, starch and sugar into mixing bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salmon Salad Pizza</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/salmon_salad_pizza/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/salmon_salad_pizza/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Pizza Base  500g spelt flour 2tsp sea salt 60g extra virgin olive oil, plus some extra 1 sachet instant yeast (total 8g = 2 tsp) 270g water  Ingredients - Sauce &amp;amp; Topping  250g tomatoes, eg roma, cut into quarters 2 garlic cloves 3-4 sprigs basil, fresh 2-3 sprigs oregano, fresh, or 1/2 tsp dried oregano 2 tsp balsamic vinegar 1tsp sugar or rapudura 1 pinch sea salt 80g tomato puree (concentrated) 1/2 chilli, fresh, deseeded (optional) 190g canned salmon, drained and flaked or smoked salmon 100g mozzarella, grated  Ingredients - Salad Topping  60g red onions 1 bunch flat-leafed parsley, fresh 1 bunch basil, fresh 2tbl extra virgin olive oil 20g lemon juice, fresh 1 pinch sea salt, or to taste 100g black olives, pitted 100g baby leaf salad, mixed  Preparation  Preheat oven to 250 deg C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sesame and Poppy Seed Flatbreads</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sesame_and_poppy_seed_flatbreads/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sesame_and_poppy_seed_flatbreads/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1tbl black sesame seeds, for sprinkling 1tbl white sesame seeds, for sprinkling 1tbl poppy seeds, for sprinkling 100g milk 210g strong bread flour 90g butter, softened, cut into pieces 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Spelt Bread Rolls with Dried Fruit</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sweet_spelt_bread_rolls_with_dried_fruit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sweet_spelt_bread_rolls_with_dried_fruit/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  200g spelt grains 150g mixed dried fruits, eg figs, apricots, prunes 270g milk 40g fresh yeast or 2 sachets dry yeast (total 16g = 4tsp) 40g honey 200g plain flour 20g olive oil 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lime Cheesecake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lime_cheesecake/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lime_cheesecake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients- Base  120g butter, cut into pieces 250g plain biscuits 30g brown sugar  Ingredients - Filing  750g cream cheese 220g castor sugar 1tsp vanilla extract, natural 3 limes, zest and juice of 2 limes, and 1 lime cut into wedges, for serving 3 eggs 1 egg yolk 120g cream, min 30% fat 200g whipped cream for serving  Method - Base  Place butter into mixing bowl and melt 2min/100deg C/speed1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milk and Orange Drink</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/milk_and_orange_drink/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/milk_and_orange_drink/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  380g orange juice, fresh from approx 5 oranges 400g evaporated milk, frozen into cubes 100g sugar  Method  Place all ingredients into mixing bowl, blend 30sec.speed 10. Serve and drink immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nut and Vanilla Crescents</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nut_and_vanilla_crescents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nut_and_vanilla_crescents/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  50g almonds 50g walnuts 280g flour 70g sugar 25g vanilla suagr 2 egg yolks 200g butter, cut into pieces 50g icing sugar, for dusting  Method  Place almonds and walnuts into mixing bowls and grind 5sec/speed 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nutty Twists</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nutty_twists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nutty_twists/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 packagespuff pastry (275g each), rolled into rectangles (25x42cm), refrigerated 200g hazelnuts, with skin, whole 60g sugar 1tbl vanilla sugar, homemade (see below) 1tsp cinnamon, ground 100g cream (20-30% fat) 10g icing sugar  Method  Preheat oven to 210 deg C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pear Tart with Almonds</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pear_tart_with_almonds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pear_tart_with_almonds/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  160g sugar 160g almonds, blanced  Ingredients - Pastry  200g flour 80g butter, cut into pieces 1 egg yolk 20g milk 1tsp salt 1tsp sugar  Ingredients - Syrup  300g water 150g sugar 1 vanilla pod, split lengthwise 20g lemon juice, freshly squeezed 4 pears, peeled and deseeded, cut in halves  Ingredients - Filling  130g butter, softened, cut into pieces 20g corn starch 170g plain yoghurt 10g rum  Method  Place sugar for filling into mixing bowl and pulverise 10sec/speed 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rich Chocolate Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/rich_chocolate_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/rich_chocolate_cake/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Rich_chocolate_cake.jpg  Ingredients  200g dark chocolate, broken into pieces 180g sugar 180g butter, cut into pieces 50g plain flour 1 pinch salt 3 eggs 150g raspberries, frozen, or fresh if vailable  Method  Preheat oven to 190 deg C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanilla Sugar</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/vanilla_sugar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/vanilla_sugar/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 vanilla pod 150g sugar  Method  Split vanilla pod in 2 and again in 2 lengthwise. Place both sugar and vanilla pod into mixing bowl and pulverise 1min/speed 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoghurt and Cookie Ice Cream</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/yoghurt_and_cookie_ice_cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/yoghurt_and_cookie_ice_cream/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  120g chocolate chip cookies 250g sugar 400g plain yoghurt 400g cream, min 30% fat  Method  Place cookies into mixing bowl and press briefly 2 times/closed lid/Turbo. Transfer into a bowl and set aside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Cross Buns - Light &amp; Fluffy</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hot_cross_buns_-_light_fluffy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hot_cross_buns_-_light_fluffy/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Hot_cross_buns.jpg  Ingredients - Dough  30 g fresh yeast or 2tsp dry/instant yeast 620 g bakers flour 50 g sugar 380 g milk 1.5 tsp salt 1-2 tsp cinnamon 1-2 tsp mixed spice 60 g Butter 1 egg 180 g sultanas/currents/cranberries etc  Ingredients - Paste for Crosses  90 g bakers or plain flour 100 g water 1 pinch salt 1 tbsp olive oil  Ingredients - Glaze  2 tbsp water 2 tbsp sugar  Method - Dough  If you&amp;rsquo;re using fresh yeast: In a small bowl cream yeast with 1tsp flour &amp;amp; 1tsp sugar and leave until it bubbles (5-10mins).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garlic &amp; Soy Chicken and Rice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/garlic_soy_chicken_and_rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/garlic_soy_chicken_and_rice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2-3 chicken breasts (or 4 thigh), cut in 2cm pieces 50 g oyster sauce 50 g soy sauce 1 spring onion 2 Garlic Cloves Peeled 200 g basmati rice, (200-400g) vegetables of choice to steam 500g water  Method  Chop garlic and spring onion for 3 seconds, speed 6 Add soy and oyster sauce and mix for 4 seconds, speed 4 Add chicken pieces to marinade mixture and stir for 2 seconds, counter-clockwise operation speed 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avocado Smoothies</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/avocado_smoothies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/avocado_smoothies/</guid>
      <description>Tropical Avocado Smoothie  1 cup water 1/2 avocado, peeled and seed removed 1/2 cup fresh or frozen mango chunks 1/2 cup fresh or frozen pineapple chunks A little honey, maple syrup, or stevia to sweeten (optional)  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seed Chocolate Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chia_seed_chocolate_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chia_seed_chocolate_cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  8 tablespoons Chia seeds 250 ml water 90 g raw cocoa 250 g unsalted butter, softened 10 eggs 350 g almond meal 320 g coconut palm sugar 1 pinch salt 2 teaspoons bicarbonate of soda  Ingredients- Dulcey chocolate ganache  400 g cream 750 g Valrhona Dulcey chocolate 100 g dark chocolate shavings  Method  Preheat the oven to 180c and line two spring mounted cake tins with baking paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Cup Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/three_cup_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/three_cup_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 lb chicken drumsticks 1 tablespoon baking soda, to tenderize the chicken, optional 2 tablespoons dark sesame oil or toasted sesame oil 2-inch piece old ginger, peeled and cut into thin pieces 6 cloves garlic, peeled 1 1/2 tablespoons soy sauce 1 1/2 tablespoons dark sweet soy sauce (kecap manis) 1 1/2 tablespoons Shaoxing wine A big bunch Thai basil leaves  Method  Cut the chicken into pieces and rub them with the baking soda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Pot Pie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_pot_pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_pot_pie/</guid>
      <description>Cauliflower Sauce, in bowl  1 onion, halved 2 garlic cloves 60g duck fat (or ghee/butter if you can have dairy) 800g cauliflower florets 150g leeks, white only, sliced 1 tsp dried thyme 320g chicken broth (or water + 2 Tbspn chicken or vege stock paste)  pepper</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sausage Rolls 2</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sausage_rolls_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sausage_rolls_2/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 large carrot, sliced 1 zucchini 1 apple 1 clove garlic 3 eggs 1 cup bread crumbs 4 tbsp barbecue sauce 250 g sausage mince 500 g pork mince 4 sheets puff pastry, cut in half sesame seed  Method  Wash carrots and cut off ends (no need to peel).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Steamed Buns</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_steamed_buns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_steamed_buns/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  5 tbl vege oil 1 tbl vinegar 1 cup sugar 500ml warm milk 6 cups noodle flour 5 tsp dried yeast  Method  Place all ingredients into TM bowl and mix 6 sec, speed 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pickled carrots</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pickled_carrots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pickled_carrots/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1/2 cup sugar 1/2 teaspoon salt 1/2 cup distilled white vinegar 3 large carrots, julienned on a mandoline or shredded  Method  In a large bowl, stir the sugar and salt into the vinegar until completely dissolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Apple Tart</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/french_apple_tart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/french_apple_tart/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Sweet Pastry Crust  1 1/2 cups (195 grams) all purpose flour 1/4 cup (50 grams) granulated white sugar 1/4 teaspoon salt 1/2 cup (113 grams) unsalted butter, at room temperature 1 large egg, at room temperature  Ingredients - Apricot Glaze  1/2 cup (120 ml) (150 grams) apricot preserves 1 tablespoon Water or Grand Marnier, Cognac, Calvados, or Rum  Ingredients - Apple Filling  1 1/4 cups (300 ml) (300 grams) lightly sweetened apple sauce (homemade or store bought) 1 1/2 pounds (675 grams) firm textured apples (about 3 medium-sized apples) (Granny Smith, Honey Crisp, Braeburn, Golden Delicious, Jonathan, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Apple Tart 2</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/french_apple_tart_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/french_apple_tart_2/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Pastry  1 1/3 cups all purpose flour 1 pinch salt 1/2 cup butter, softened 1 egg yolk 3 tbl cold water or as needed  Ingredients - Frangipane  1/2 cup butter, softened 1/2 cup white sugar 1 egg, beaten 1 egg yolk 1 tbl apple brandy 2/3 cup almonds 2 tbl all-purpose flour  Ingredients - Apple Tart  4 medium sweet apples - peeled &amp;amp; thinly sliced 1 tsp white sugar for decoration 1/4 cup apricot jelly  Methods  In a medium bowl, stir together 1 1/3 cups of flour and salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShaoXing Wine Chicken Thigh and Chinese Sausage Claypot Rice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/shaoxing_wine_chicken_thigh_and_chinese_sausage_claypot_rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/shaoxing_wine_chicken_thigh_and_chinese_sausage_claypot_rice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  4 chicken thighs, about 3/4 lb each 1 cup long grain rice, uncooked 2 Chinese sausage, thinly sliced on the diagonal 1 pack enoki mushrooms, about 7oz, wash and separated 1 scallion, chopped  Ingredients for the Chicken Thigh Marinade  2 tbsp Shaoxing wine 1 tsp fish sauce 2 tsp soy sauce 1/2 tsp sugar 1/2 tsp white pepper 1/2 tsp garlic granule 1/2 tsp salt 2 tsp oil  Ingredients for the Sauce  4 tsp sesame oil 4 tsp soy sauce 2 tsp sugar 2 tsp water 2 tsp fish sauce  Method  In a large bowl, combine the ingredients for the chicken thigh marinade (Shaoxing wine, fish sauce, soy sauce, sugar, white pepper, garlic granule, salt, and oil).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naan Bread</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/naan_bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/naan_bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  200g milk 1 egg, lightly beaten 2 tbl olive oil (can use ghee to be authentic) 80g Greek yoghurt 30g fresh yeast or 2tsp dried yeast 550-560g Lacke bakers flour 1tsp baking powder 1tsp sugar Pinch Pink salt flakes  Method  Combine milk, egg, oil, yoghurt and yeast in Thermo bowl and blend 3 sec/speed 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tandoori Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tandoori_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tandoori_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 tbl cumin seeds 1 tbl coriander seeds 1 tsp black pepercorns 3 tbl paprika 1 tsp cayenne pepper 2 tbl tumeric 2 cloves of garlic 2 red chillies, deseeded 100g onion 2 tbl Extra Virgin Olive Oil 15g ginger, peeled 30g lime juice, fresh 70g tomato paste 80g greek yoghurt sea salt to taste 4-6 piece chicken maryland  Method  Place cumin, coriander, peppercorns, paprika, cayenne &amp;amp; turmeric into Thermomix bowl &amp;amp; dry roast 10 min/Varoma/speed 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biryani Chicken &amp; Rice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/biryani_chicken_rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/biryani_chicken_rice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  4-8 Chicken thighs trimmed and quartered 5g fresh ginger 1 garlic clove Juice of 1 lime 2 coriander roots 150g plain yoghurt 2 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp cinnamon ½ tsp cayenne pepper (less or more – to your preference) 40g tomato paste Salt and pepper  Method  Place everything except the chicken in the bowl and blitz on Speed 9 for 10 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamy Chicken Pasta Bake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamy_chicken_pasta_bake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamy_chicken_pasta_bake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  250g dried maccheroni pasta (see note) 4 cooked chicken drumsticks (refer Honey &amp;amp; Mustard Roasted Chicken Drumsticks) 100g baby spinach leaves 300ml light thickened cream 3/4 cup semi-dried tomatoes 1 1/2 cups grated parmesan cheese 1 cup grated mozzarella cheese  Method  Preheat oven to 200C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crispy Oven Baked French Fries</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crispy_oven_baked_french_fries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crispy_oven_baked_french_fries/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 medium russet potatoes course salt 1 Tbl oil  Method  Start with a couple of medium russet potatoes. Preheat oven to 425 convection. Peal potatoes if desired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honey and Mustard Roasted Chicken Drumsticks</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/honey_and_mustard_roasted_chicken_drumsticks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/honey_and_mustard_roasted_chicken_drumsticks/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 tablespoons extra-light olive oil 1/4 cup honey 1 tablespoon wholegrain mustard 1 orange, juiced 12 chicken drumsticks 450g orange sweet potato, peeled, cut into 2cm pieces 450g desiree potatoes, peeled, cut into 2cm pieces 100g baby spinach leaves  Method  Preheat oven to 240°C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oven Baked Chicken Legs</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/oven_baked_chicken_legs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/oven_baked_chicken_legs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  5-6 drumsticks (about 1.5 ibs) Spices - salt, pepper, garlic powder  Method  Preheat oven to 425 deg F (220 deg C). Pat dry with paper towels. Trim off any extra skin and loose join pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef Pot Roast</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beef_pot_roast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beef_pot_roast/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 tbl oil 1kg piece beef topside, trimmed or chuck steak 32g packet onion soup mix 1 cup liquid beef stock 1 bay leave 1 tbl cornflour 1 tbl water 1 tsp wholegrain mustard  Method  Heat the oil in a large saucepan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef, Bacon &amp; Cheese Pie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beef_bacon_cheese_pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beef_bacon_cheese_pie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1kg beef mince 600g finely diced beef 500g diced bacon 2 large onions diced into large pieces 4 tomatoes diced 1 lge heaped tablespoon garlic 1.5 cups made-up gravy Cornflour to thicken if needed  Method  Spray pie tray/baking tray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Churros 2</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/churros_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/churros_2/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup of water 100g butter 1 cup flour (I ended up adding more as the dough was too wet) 2 eggs  Method  Heat water in a pan and add butter Remove from heat and add flour, mix till dough separates from edges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Cooked Beef, Onion and Mushroom Pie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/slow_cooked_beef_onion_and_mushroom_pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/slow_cooked_beef_onion_and_mushroom_pie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 onion diced 600g mushrooms sliced 1kg diced chuck or blade steak juice of 1 lemon salt to taste corn flour to thicken ( I also used some gravy powder as well for more flavour )  Method  Place onion, mushrooms and steak to slow cooker also add lemon juice, salt and 2 cups of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow Cooker Tater Tot Casserole</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/slow_cooker_tater_tot_casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/slow_cooker_tater_tot_casserole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  0.5kg/1lb ground beef, brown 1 can diced tomatoes 1 packet of frozen Potato Gems/Tater Tots 1 can Cream of Chicken Soup 1 small onion, chopped 2 cups cheddar cheese, shredded  Method  Brown beef and add in chopped onion and tomatoes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Scallion Pancakes</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_scallion_pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_scallion_pancakes/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Dough  400g plain flour 230g water  Method - Dough  Place ingredients into TM bowl and mix on speed 5 for 10 seconds. Knead for one minute with the dial set to closed lid position on interval speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buckwhweat Crepe</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/buckwhweat_crepe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/buckwhweat_crepe/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 eggs 3/4 cup buckwheat flour 1 cup whole wheat flour, + 1 teaspoon ½ teaspoon salt 1 tablespoon canola oil 3 tablespoons salted butter button mushroom and roasted red bell pepper filling, as needed 18 thin slices raclette cheese  Method  Using a handheld mixer, whisk the eggs until foamy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crumpets</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crumpets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crumpets/</guid>
      <description>Crumpets are very similar to pancakes, but they are much smaller. I love the characteristic holes on top. Those holes are a result of the addition of extra baking soda to the yeast batter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet French Crepe</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sweet_french_crepe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sweet_french_crepe/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  5-1/2 Tbs unsalted butter, diced, + extra for greasing the pan 5 cups whole milk 4-1/8 cups all purpose flour 1/4 tsp salt 2 eggs 4 Tbs sugar 1 tsp vanilla extract 1/4 cup lemon juice, pulp free 1 tsp lemon zest, freshly grated 1 tsp orange zest, freshly grated 1/3 cup orange juice, pulp free  Method  In a deep saucepan, melt the butter into 3-½ cups of milk over very low heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetarian Vietnamese Crepe</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/vegetarian_vietnamese_crepe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/vegetarian_vietnamese_crepe/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 3/4 cups rice flour 1/4 cup wheat flour 1 to 1 1/2 cup unsweetened coconut milk 1 cup water 1 tsp turmeric powder 1 tsp superfine sugar 2 scallions, thinly sliced into rings 2 tsp sea salt 2 tsp black peppercorns, freshly ground 1/2 tsp curry powder 8 Tbs canola oil 1 cup dried mung beans 1 block tofu, firm 1 small yellow onion, thinly sliced 1 pack enoki mushrooms, cut in half 2 cups shitake mushrooms, sliced 2 shallots 4 cups fresh bean sprouts 1 Persian cucumber , sliced 1 lettuce 1/2 bunch fresh Thai basil 1/2 bunch fresh Asian mint 3 Tbs pickled garlic 6 dipping bowls nước chấm condiment 2 Tbs fresh red bird chili peppers, sliced  Method  In a bowl wash the mung beans thoroughly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roast Pumpkin</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/roast_pumpkin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/roast_pumpkin/</guid>
      <description>Method  Choose a firm, small pie pumpkin, not more than 3-4 pounds; smaller pumpkins tend to be a bit sweeter. Rinse the pumpkin under warm water, removing any dirt or debris Cut the pumpkin in half on a large cutting board, with a sharp knife Scoop out the seeds with a metal spoon, I use an old measuring spoon that has a nice edge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Hazelnut GIngerbread</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/french_hazelnut_gingerbread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/french_hazelnut_gingerbread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2/3 cup honey 1/2 cup hot milk 1/2 cup butter, softened 2 cups self-rising flour 1/4 cup granulated sugar ¾ teaspoon orange zest ½ teaspoon salt 3/4 teaspoon cinnamon ½ teaspoon ground ginger ¼ teaspoon ground cloves ¼ teaspoon nutmeg ½ cup chopped toasted hazelnuts 1 egg 1 tablespoon Noisette, or hazelnut liquor  Method  Preheat an oven to 350 degrees F (18- degree C) and butter an 8-inch by 8-inch square baking pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mexican Shredded Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/mexican_shredded_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/mexican_shredded_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 Red onion (peeled and halved) 2 garlic cloves ½ -1 whole red chilli (to your preference) 20g oil 2 tsp ground coriander 1 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp smoked paprika 400g tin tomatoes 50g tomato paste 50g vegetable stock paste Handful fresh oregano (or tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tortillas</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tortillas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tortillas/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500g plain flour (or 400g plain and 100g wholemeal) 240g water 50g olive oil Tsp salt  Method  Place all ingredients in bowl and mix for 5 seconds on Speed 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garlic &amp; Coconut Dukka</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/garlic_coconut_dukka/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/garlic_coconut_dukka/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  45 g sesame seeds 90 g raw almonds 20 g granulated garlic 25 g dessicated coconut 5 g Cumin Seeds Whole 5 g coriander seeds Whole 1 tsp ground sea salt  Method  Place sesame, almonds, garlic, coconut, cumin and coriander into TMX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sage &amp; Lemon Salt</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sage_lemon_salt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sage_lemon_salt/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  900g Himalayan salt 2 handful sage leaves zest of 3 lemons  Method  Dehydrate sage leaves &amp;amp; lemon zest overnight. Blend in TM (20sec on sp8). Add salt &amp;amp; blend again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Crepes</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/basic_crepes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/basic_crepes/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  5 eggs 500g plain flour 1 litre skim milk 3 tbl oil 1/2 glass of beer  Method  Pour half of the flour in a big bowl. Add eggs, one at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin Gratin with Parmesan</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pumpkin_gratin_with_parmesan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pumpkin_gratin_with_parmesan/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Butter (for the dish) 1 (4- to 5-pound) sugar pumpkin, stemmed and halved from stem to stern Salt and pepper, to taste 2 teaspoons flour 2 teaspoons fresh thyme leaves 1 egg 1¼ cups heavy cream ½ cup milk 1 cup freshly grated Parmesan Extra Parmesan (for sprinkling)  Method  Set the oven at 400 degrees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY Lip Balm with Olive Oil</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/diy_lip_balm_with_olive_oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/diy_lip_balm_with_olive_oil/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: DIY_lip_balm.jpg  Ingredients  3 tablespoons of extra virgin olive oil 3 tablespoons of beeswax 1 tablespoon of cocoa butter or shea butter 1/2 tsp of vitamin E oil (or about 6 capsules) 1 tsp of honey (optional) 15 drops of peppermint essential oil  Recommended Equipment  empty lip balm tubes ( turkey baster, clean medicine dropper or disposable transfer pipette *small sauce pan glass measuring cup, large ceramic cup or large mixing bowl (glass or metal) grater (for the beeswax) Optional: square stick-on labels  Method  First create a makeshift double boiler by filling a small sauce pan 1/2 way with water and turn the heat to low or medium low.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY Whipped Body Butter</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/diy_whipped_body_butter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/diy_whipped_body_butter/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: DIY_whipped_body_butter.jpg  Ingredients  1/2 cup of cocoa butter OR shea butter 1/4 cup of coconut oil 1/4 cup of jojoba oil 20-40 drops of your favourite essential oils  Method  Fill a small saucepan 1/4-1/2 way with water and heat over medium low.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handmade Lotion Bars</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/handmade_lotion_bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/handmade_lotion_bars/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Handmade_lotion_bars.jpg  Ingredients  2oz. coconut oil 2oz. shea butter (or cocoa butter) 2oz. bees wax pellets 2 capsules vitamin E essential oils for scent (optional) soap mould (plastic or silicone) microwave safe bowl (disposable works great too)  Method  Melt your shea butter, bees wax and coconut oil in the microwave in 20 second intervals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Peppermint Body Butter</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_peppermint_body_butter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/homemade_peppermint_body_butter/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Homemade_body_butter.jpg  Ingredients  6 oz Coconut Oil 2 oz Cocoa Butter Peppermint Essential Oil (or fragrance of your choice)– use therapeutic grade oils if you can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almond &amp; Orange Zest Biscotti</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/almond_orange_zest_biscotti/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/almond_orange_zest_biscotti/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  ½ cup butter 1 cup sugar 1 tablespoon baking powder 3 whole eggs 1 egg white, beaten (optional) 1 orange, peel grated, or as explained in recipe 1 teaspoon vanilla extract ¼ teaspoon salt 3 cups flour 2 cups whole bark on almonds, toasted 2 tablespoons or more of sparkling sugar (or Demerera)  Method  Prepare orange peel: 1)peel orange without any pith; 2) slice peels into slivers or threads of peeling;3) place in small bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almond Biscotti</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/almond_biscotti/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/almond_biscotti/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  125 grams raw sugar 250 grams Plan Flour 250 grams raw almonds 3 egg whites 2 teaspoons vanilla extract 1 teaspoon baking powder 1 orange peel, grated  Method  Place raw sugar into TM bowl for 3 seconds on speed 9 to make caster sugar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galette Des Rois</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/galette_des_rois/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/galette_des_rois/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Almond Filling  1 cup (100g) almond flour 1/2 cup (100g) sugar pinch salt zest of 1/2 orange (unsprayed) 3 1/2 ounces (100g) unsalted butter, cubed, at room temperature 2 large eggs, at room temperature 2 teaspoon rum 1/8 teaspoon almond extract 1 pound (450g) puff pastry, divided in two pieces, chilled a whole almond or piece of candied fruit to be the fève  Ingredients - glaze  1 egg yolk 1 teaspoon milk  Method  To make the almond filling, in a medium bowl, or in the bowl of a stand mixer, combine the almond flour, sugar, salt, and orange zest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walnut Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/walnut_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/walnut_cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 1/4 cup very finely chopped walnuts 1/3 cup flour 3 eggs 3/4 cup sugar 1/3 cup butter pinch of salt  Method  In a bowl, mix together chopped and nuts with half of the sugar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Baguettes</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/french_baguettes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/french_baguettes/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 tsp salt 650g bakers flour 350g warm water 2tsp granulated yeast  Method  Place ingredients into Thermomix bowl in the order listed. (We are keeping salt away from the yeast).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swedish Cinnamon Buns</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/swedish_cinnamon_buns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/swedish_cinnamon_buns/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  310 grams milk 180 grams Butter, unsalted 220 grams sugar, raw 1/2 teaspoon cardamon pods 1 Yeast, packet 655g grams plain or bakers flour 1 egg, beaten  Method  Place sugar and cardamon in TM bowl and mil for 15 sec speed 9, reserve to the side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meat Stock Paste</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/meat_stock_paste/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/meat_stock_paste/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  300g meat pieces, sinew free, cut into pieces, partially frozen 300g mixed roots and vegetables (eg celery stalk, carrots, onions, garlic, tomatoes), cut into pieces 4 sprigs fresh mixed herbs (eg sage, rosemary), leaves only 150g rock salt 120g red wine 1 dried bay leaf 1 whole clove  Method  Place meat pieces into mixing bowl and mince 10sec/speed 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gournet Beef Casserole</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/gournet_beef_casserole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/gournet_beef_casserole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 kg chuck or blade steak - cut into 2cm cubes 1 tsp brown sugar 1 tbl flour 1 tbl TMX stock concentrate 1 tbl tomato paste pinch nutmeg 1 large onion 2 clove garlic 1 tbl malt vinegar 1 tsp Worcestershire sauce 200g mushrooms 150ml dry red wine 150ml water 1 tbl cornflour blended with small amount water  Method   Place onion and garlic in TMX chop 3 sec speed 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cabbage Soup</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cabbage_soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cabbage_soup/</guid>
      <description>Winnie&amp;rsquo;s simplified version (Dec 2014)  Note: The following is the quantity for 1 batch in TM which is for 3 meals. Best to prepare double the quantities and cook 2 batches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana Ice Cream with Caramel Sauce</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/banana_ice_cream_with_caramel_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/banana_ice_cream_with_caramel_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Banana_ice_cream_caramel.jpg  Ingredients  250g cream 250g milk (I used skim/hilo) 200g sugar (this made it quite sweet so probably 150g would be enough) 1 tsp vanilla paste 2 egg yolks 2 ripe bananas caramel sauce (use your preferred favourite - I had some left over from making my cupcakes - Recipe here)  Method  Add all ingredients except caramel sauce to the bowl and cook for 7 minutes at 80deg Speed 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basil and Lime Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/basil_and_lime_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/basil_and_lime_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 garlic 15g fresh basil 10g lime juice (1 lime) you can add zest also 1 tbsp Worcestershire sauce 1 tbsp soy sauce 1 tsp Dijon mustard 1 tsp jalepenos (more if you wish) 20g oil 4-8 chicken thighs sliced thick Vegetables of choice (snow peas, cabbage, zucchini, capsicum)  Method  Add all ingredients (except chicken and vegetables) to the bowl and blitz on Speed 6 for 20 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef and Feta Gozleme</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beef_and_feta_gozleme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beef_and_feta_gozleme/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - dough  250g low fat (or non fat) Greek Yoghurt 300g Self Raising Flour Pinch of Salt  Method - dough  Place all ingredients into the bowl and knead for 1 minute on Interval.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Ever Beef Pie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/best_ever_beef_pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/best_ever_beef_pie/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Best_ever_beef_pie.jpg  Ingredients  2 onions peeled and halved 2 garlic cloves 20g oil 30g balsamic vinegar 1 heaped tsp cumin powder 1 heaped tsp smoked paprika 1kg Gravy Beef diced 80g tomato paste 40g plain flour 50g Worcestershire sauce 30g balsamic vinegar 1 beef stock cube (or 1tbsp TMX Veg Stock) 200g water Salt and pepper to taste   NOTE: THE DOUBLE UP ON THE BALSAMIC VINEGAR IS NOT A MISTAKE ITS HOW I DO IT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Butter Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/butter_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/butter_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 Onion 1 inch of ginger 4 cloves of garlic 1 red chilli 20g oil 80-100g tandoori paste 200g yoghurt (non fat greek) 170g tomato paste 1 tab of ground almonds or cashews 750g-1kg chicken thigh diced  Method  Add onion, ginger, garlic, chilli to the bowl and chop for 5sec on Speed 7 Add oil and sauté for 3 min 100degrees, speed 1 Add ground nuts, tandoori paste, tomato paste, yoghurt and mix for 10 sec speed 7 Add chicken and cook for 20 min, 100 degrees, reverse, speed soft  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cacao Crunch</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cacao_crunch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cacao_crunch/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Cacao_crunch.jpg  Ingredients  1 egg white 100g caster sugar 45g grapeseed oil 2 tablespoon water ½ tsp vanilla bean paste 65g plain flour 15g cacao powder ¼ tsp bicarb soda ¼ tsp salt Choc bits  Method  Preheat oven to 160deg and line a lamington tray with baking paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caramel Chicken Noodles</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/caramel_chicken_noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/caramel_chicken_noodles/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 onion peeled and halved 20g ginger 15g garlic ½ red chilli (optional) 20g oil 60g brown sugar 60g rice wine vinegar 70g soy sauce 1 tsp salt 30g TMX stock 350g water 2 tbsp corn flour mixed in some water 6 chicken thighs trimmed and diced Vegetables for steaming (snow peas, carrot, broccoli, capsicum) 350g packet noodles  Method  Add onion ginger, garlic and chilli (if using) to bowl and chop on Speed 6 for 3 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carrot Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/carrot_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/carrot_cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Cake  250 grams walnuts 400 grams carrots, washed and roughly chopped 2 eggs 220 grams raw sugar 160 grams EVOO (olive oil) 1 tsp vanilla essence 1/2 tsp mixed spice 1/4 tsp salt 200 grams plain flour 1 tsp bicarb soda  Ingredients - Icing  220 grams raw sugar, milled 10 sec, sp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheese Biscuits (with Dukkah)</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheese_biscuits_with_dukkah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheese_biscuits_with_dukkah/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  300g plain flour 200g butter (diced small) 200g cheese (cheddar, tasty, colby etc) (diced small) tsp salt 1/4 tsp cayenne pepper dukkah - optional  Method  Add all ingredients into the bowl and mix on Speed 8 for 20 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken and Chick Pea Rissoles</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_and_chick_pea_rissoles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_and_chick_pea_rissoles/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500g chicken breast diced 2 spring onions 1 handful of fresh parsley 1 garlic clove 1 tin of chick peas rinsed and drained 100g breadcrumbs 50g EDC dukkah  Method  Add onions, parsley and garlic to the bowl and chop on Speed 7 for 3 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken and Whatever Vege Pie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_and_whatever_vege_pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_and_whatever_vege_pie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 leek chopped 1 garlic clove Handful of parsley 500g diced chicken 500g sweet potato 500g water 70g plain flour 50g wholegrain mustard 50g vegetable stock or chicken stock paste 100g cream Big pinch of thyme Broccoli Spinach leaves 2-3 medium potatoes sliced thin and drizzled in oil 1 qty EDC shortcrust pastry  Method  Add leek, garlic and parsley to bowl and chop on Speed 6 for 3 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken, Leek and Roast Pumpkin Strudel</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_leek_and_roast_pumpkin_strudel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_leek_and_roast_pumpkin_strudel/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500g cubed pre-roasted pumpkin ½ a shredded roast chicken 1 leek sliced 1 clove garlic Sliced green onion tops 50g butter 1 puff pastry sheet 250g cheese 50g flour 1tsp quirky’s chicken stock paste or TMX vege stock 200g milk  Method  Add garlic to TMX bowl with and chop for 5 seconds at Speed 7 Add leek and butter and sauté for 4 minutes at 100 degrees Speed 1 Add flour, milk, stock paste and cheese and cook for 10 minutes at 90 deg on Speed 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Fried Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_fried_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_fried_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500g chicken breasts sliced (can also be made with chicken wings) 1 small onion peeled and halved 1 large clove garlic peeled ¼ cup fish sauce 2 tbsp soy sauce 1 tbsp brown sugar ¼ tsp Chinese five spice ½ tsp cayenne ½ tsp white pepper Plain flour for dusting Vegetable oil for deep frying  Method  Put onion and garlic into TMX and chop Speed 5 for 5 seconds, open lid, scrape down and chop again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Leftover Quiche</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/christmas_leftover_quiche/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/christmas_leftover_quiche/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 qty of EDC shortcrust pastry 200g cream Block of Feta Cheese (approx. 200g) 4 large free range eggs 1 onion oil Christmas meat leftover – diced (smoked salmon, turkey, chicken or ham) Grated cheddar  Method  Make your shortcrust pastry as per EDC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Churros</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/churros/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/churros/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Churros.jpg  Ingredients  190g plain flour sifted pinch salt 310g water (boiled) 160g butter 4 eggs Oil for frying 100g caster sugar 2 tsp cinnamon sugar  Method  Add sugar and cinnamon to bowl and mix on Speed 5 for 10 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamy Beef and Thyme</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamy_beef_and_thyme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamy_beef_and_thyme/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 large onion (peeled and halved) 2 garlic cloves Fresh Thyme (approx. leaves from 10 sprigs) 1 tsp sweet paprika 50g TMX stock 100g white wine 150g water 100g cream 20g flour (50g for pie) 800-1000g gravy beef diced Salt and pepper to taste  Method  Add onion and garlic to bowl and chop on Speed 6 for 3 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamy Mustard Chicken Spaghetti</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamy_mustard_chicken_spaghetti/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamy_mustard_chicken_spaghetti/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500g Chicken Thighs diced 1 onion 2 cloves of garlic 10g oil 4 rashers of bacon diced 3 tbsp seeded mustard 800g water 2 tbsp TMX vegetable stock 300g cream 300g pasta 1 cup of peas Salt and pepper to taste Parmesan to garnish  Method  Add onion and garlic to bowl and chop for 5 seconds on Speed 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crunchy Honey Soy Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crunchy_honey_soy_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crunchy_honey_soy_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Flour Mix  150g plain flour 1 tsp salt 1 tsp white pepper 1 tsp ground ginger 1 tbsp dried thyme ½ tbsp dried sage 1 tbsp smoked paprika ¼ tsp cayenne pepper  &amp;lt;!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ginger Snaps</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/ginger_snaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/ginger_snaps/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Ginger_snaps.jpg  Ingredients  50g butter 40g sugar 60g golden syrup 1tsp ground ginger ½ cup flour 1tsp baking powder  Method  Put butter, sugar and golden syrup into TMX bowl and cook 37 degrees 7 minutes speed 2 Add remainder of ingredients and mix 5 seconds speed 5 Scrape down sides and mix again speed 5 for 5 seconds Drop tsp amounts on lined baking tray leaving enough room to spread to double in size and bake for 10 minutes at 180 degrees taking care not to burn as they turn quick!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ice Magic Chocolate Sauce</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/ice_magic_chocolate_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/ice_magic_chocolate_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  100g coconut oil 10g cocoa or cacao powder tiny pinch salt 1 teaspoon vanilla paste 20g maple syrup or honey (more if you want a sweeter sauce)  Method  Add all ingredients to the bowl and cook for 3 minutes at 50 deg on Speed 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Katsu Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/katsu_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/katsu_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Katsu.jpg  Ingredients - Flour Mix   4 - 8 chicken thighs
  3 eggs
  2 tbsp soy sauce
  Plain flour</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lamb Kofta</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_kofta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_kofta/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 garlic clove Handful each of fresh parsley, coriander and mint 50g red onion 1 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp ground coriander 1 tin of lentils (rinsed and drained) 25g TMX stock paste 500g lamb mince  Method - Marinade  Add garlic, onion and herbs to the bowl and blitz on Speed 7 for 3 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lamb Rogan Josh</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_rogan_josh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_rogan_josh/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Marinade  15g ginger 5 cloves garlic 1tsp turmeric 1tsp black peppercorns (or crushed black pepper) 250g plain yoghurt 1kg lamb forequarter chops meat chopped from bones  Method - Marinade  Add garlic and ginger and pepper corns to TMX bowl and chop 5 seconds speed 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lamb Shanks in Tomato Sauce</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_shanks_in_tomato_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_shanks_in_tomato_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  6 Lamb Shanks 2 carrots chopped 2 celery stalks chopped 1 large onion 1 large garlic clove 1200g water 5 rosemary sprigs Prosciutto 400g tin tomatoes 1 heaped tbsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon and Coriander Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_and_coriander_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_and_coriander_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  90g olive oil 60g onion 5g garlic 2 stalks of coriander leaves and roots 5g cumin seeds 100g lemon juice 2 tsp smoked paprika 2 bay leaves  Method  Add all ingredients to TMX and blitz on Speed 8 for 30 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon and Herb Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_and_herb_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_and_herb_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  •50g lemon juice handful of favourite herbs (parsley, sage, basil, coriander, oregano) 20g TMX stock 20g olive oil pinch salt 1 garlic clove red chilli - optional  Method  Add all ingredients to bowl and blitz on Speed 8 for 50 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Chicken and Rosemary Risotto</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_chicken_and_rosemary_risotto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_chicken_and_rosemary_risotto/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 onion peeled and halved 1 garlic clove 3 sprigs of rosemary (leaves only) 20g oil 400g Arborio rice 100g white wine 4 chicken thighs trimmed and sliced 1100g water 2 heaped spoonfuls of TMX stock paste 50g lemon juice Grated Parmesan cheese Spinach leaves  Method  Add onion, rosemary and garlic to bowl and chop for 3 seconds on Speed 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malaysian Chicken and Prawn Curry (Laksa Paste)</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/malaysian_chicken_and_prawn_curry_laksa_paste/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/malaysian_chicken_and_prawn_curry_laksa_paste/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Laksa Paste   2-4 Red Chillies
  50g fresh coriander leaves and roots
  40g fresh ginger
  3 garlic cloves
  2 lemongrass stalks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maple Baked Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/maple_baked_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/maple_baked_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Marinade  50g djon mustard 20g mayonnaise 50g maple syrup 40g rice wine vinegar 1/2 tsp cayenne pepper 1 garlic salt and pepper to taste Chicken thighs, drumsticks or wings  Method  Add everything to the bowl and blitz on Speed 7 for 10 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi Purpose Breadcrumbs</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/multi_purpose_breadcrumbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/multi_purpose_breadcrumbs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients •3 slices bread
 50g salami 30g semi dried tomatoes 1 brown onion 200g cubed cheese 2 cloves garlic ½ bunch parsley Salt &amp;amp; Pepper  Method  Place all ingredients into TMX bowl and chop 10 seconds using spatula to help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nigella&#39;s Mughlai Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nigella_s_mughlai_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nigella_s_mughlai_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Marinade  60g almonds 1 onion 25g fresh ginger 3 garlic cloves ½ -2 red chillies (Don’t go crazy otherwise the spices will get lost!) Olive oil 2 tsp ground cumin 2 tsp ground coriander 1 tsp garam masala 4 cardamom pods 1 cinnamon stick 4 cloves 2 fresh bay leaves 200g greek yoghurt 60g chicken stock paste or vegetable stock paste 1 tsp sugar 1 tsp salt 6-8 chicken thigh (cut in quarters) 100g cream  Method  Add almonds to a dry bowl and mill on Speed 8 for 8 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pad Thai Noodles</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pad_thai_noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pad_thai_noodles/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Peanuts 1-2 Chicken thighs (diced) 200g prawns (optional) 4 spring onions sliced Bok choy sliced Handful of bean sprouts 1 packet of rice noodles 2 tbsp palm sugar (or brown sugar) 2 tbsp fish sauce 1 tsp tamarind paste Chilli to taste Juice of 1 lime Coriander to garnish  Method  Place peanuts in bowl and crush on Speed 5 for 3-5 seconds (depending on how you like them).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peppered Beef and Mushroom Stew</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/peppered_beef_and_mushroom_stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/peppered_beef_and_mushroom_stew/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  700g Chuck steak or gravy beef cubed 2 carrots peeled and chopped 250g mushrooms sliced 2 cloves garlic 1 onion peeled and quartered 10g olive oil 20g cornflour 1tbsp tomato paste 250g beef stock liquid 3 tbsp soy sauce 3 tbsp Worcestershire sauce 3 tbsp fish sauce 1 tsp mixed herbs 1 tsp ground black pepper  Method  Put garlic and onion in TMX bowl and chop 5 seconds speed 7 Scrape down sides, add olive oil and sauté 5 minutes 100 degrees speed 1 Add remainder of ingredients and cook 50 minutes reverse speed soft 100 degrees  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peri Peri Sauce</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/peri_peri_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/peri_peri_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 dried red chillis (could use more or less) 1 red capsicum 30g lemon juice 2 tbsp smoked paprika 80g balsamic vinegar 4 garlic cloves 2 tsp salt 2 tbsp oregano 90g olive oil Pepper to taste 2-4 chicken breasts (or thighs)  Method  Add all ingredients except chicken to bowl and blitz on Speed 8 for 30 seconds or until preferred consistency is reached.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pork and Chorizo Sauce</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pork_and_chorizo_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pork_and_chorizo_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cloves garlic 1 onion 1 celery stick chopped 1 chorizo sausage chopped and skin removed 20g oil 1 tin tomatoes 80g tomato paste 200g water 30g TMX stock paste Salt and pepper to taste Handful fresh herbs 500g pork mince Feta and fresh herbs to serve  Method  Add garlic, onion, celery and chorizo to bowl and chop on Speed 7 for 5 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quinoa and Banana Bread</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/quinoa_and_banana_bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/quinoa_and_banana_bread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Dry Ingredients  250g flour 100g caster sugar 1 tsp baking powder 1 tsp bicarb soda 1 tsp cinnamon Pinch salt  Ingredients - Wet Ingredients  50g butter 150g ripe bananas 1 egg 1 cup cooked quinoa 70g low fat greek yoghurt  Method  Preheat oven to 160deg and spray or grease a muffin or mini loaf pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roast Lamb Marinade</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/roast_lamb_marinade/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/roast_lamb_marinade/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  30g soy sauce 30g worcestershire sauce (homemade is awesome - recipe available at Stephberg.com) 1 large garlic clove 3 rosemary sprigs (leaves only) small handful of mint leaves 30g olive oil (optional)  Method  Put everything into the bowl and blitz on Speed 7 for 10 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sausage Rolls</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sausage_rolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sausage_rolls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 small brown onion 1 clove garlic 1 carrot 1 celery stick 1 tsp fennel seeds 1 tbsp dried oregano 30g Worcestershire sauce 50g bread crumbs 600g mince (pork/beef) 2 sheets Puff pastry  Method  Preheat oven to 180deg and line a tray with baking paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spicy Mexican Pulled Beef</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spicy_mexican_pulled_beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spicy_mexican_pulled_beef/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  750g Chuck steak diced into 1cm cubes 1 shallot peeled and cut in half 2 cloves garlic 1 cup tinned tomatoes 1tbsp tomato paste 1 tsp TMX vege stock concentrate 1 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp ground coriander 1 tsp paprika ½ tsp cayenne pepper 1 tbs jalapeno’s (pickled jar variety) or 1 red chilli but jalapenos are the best!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sri Lankan Curry</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sri_lankan_curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sri_lankan_curry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 large onion, peeled and quartered 2 garlic cloves, peeled 2cm ginger 1 teaspoon dried red chili 1 teaspoon cumin 1 teaspoon coriander 1 teaspoon turmeric 20g oil 400g coconut cream 100g vegetable stock 600g potatoes, peeled and diced evenly 150g carrots, chopped 400g mixed vegetables, chopped (cauliflower, mushroom, broccoli, zucchini etc)  Method  Place onion, garlic, ginger and chili in TM bowl chop 3 seconds/speed 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sri Lankan Curry 2 (Dani Ramirez)</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sri_lankan_curry_2_dani_ramirez/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sri_lankan_curry_2_dani_ramirez/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - roasted curry power  2 tablespoons coriander seed 1 teaspoon fennel seed 1 tablespoon cumin seed 1 teaspoon black pepper 3 cardamon pods Sprig of curry leaves 1 teaspoon ground turmeric 1 teaspoon ground chilli powder 1/2 teaspoon cinnamon 1 teaspoon ground roasted rice Note: You will have more curry powder then needed in this recipe, store in an air-tight jar for up to 2 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sticky Vietnamese Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sticky_vietnamese_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sticky_vietnamese_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  700g chicken thigh fillet 1 small red onion 2 cloves garlic 20g oil 2 lemon grass stalks (white part only) 120g white sugar 2cm ginger 30g lime juice 30g fish sauce 30g soy sauce 1/4tsp white pepper 10g chinese cooking wine ¼ tsp dried chilli flakes  Method  Put peeled garlic, onion, lemon grass and ginger into TMX bowl and chop for 3 seconds at Speed 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Ice Cream 1</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/strawberry_ice_cream_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/strawberry_ice_cream_1/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  400 g Frozen Strawberries 400 g Frozen Milk, in cubes 150 g Sugar 1 Lemon Juice  Method  Wash strawberries well and freeze them. Freeze milk in cubes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Ice Cream 2 (with Yoghurt)</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/strawberry_ice_cream_2_with_yoghurt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/strawberry_ice_cream_2_with_yoghurt/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  300 g Frozen Strawberries 150 g Yogurt (made with Thermomix) 50 g Sugar (I use a bit of sugar but I don&amp;rsquo;t use lemon)  Method  Wash strawberries very well, cut into small pieces and freeze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Ice Cream 3</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/strawberry_ice_cream_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/strawberry_ice_cream_3/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  150 grams white sugar (reduce to 130g) 2 egg yolks 500 grams full fat cream 1 teaspoon vanilla extract 1 pinch salt 200 grams strawberries, hulled  Method  Place sugar into mixing bowl and mill 2 sec/speed 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Jelly</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/strawberry_jelly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/strawberry_jelly/</guid>
      <description>Method  Add 250g of fresh strawberries (leaves removed), 50g icing sugar and 100g water to the bowl and blitz on Speed 8 for 30 seconds (or until well combined). Add 50g boiling water to 1 tbsp of gelatine and mix well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teriyaki Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/teriyaki_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/teriyaki_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  120g soy sauce 90g sugar 90g sake or white wine 100g mirin 90g water 1 tbsp corn flour 2 garlic cloves 20g ginger 500-1000g chicken thighs diced  Method  Add all ingredients except chicken into bowl and mix on Speed 8 for 30 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thai Chicken Rissoles</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thai_chicken_rissoles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thai_chicken_rissoles/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  15g fresh ginger 1 large clove of garlic 1 tsp of lemongrass (masterfoods) 1 small bunch of coriander (including stem) 25g sweet chilli sauce 1 tsp fish sauce 500g diced chicken breast  Method  Add ginger and garlic to bowl and blitz on Speed 8 for 3 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tin Tomato Sauce</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tin_tomato_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tin_tomato_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 tins of tomatoes (I used the chopped ones) Clove of garlic 10g ginger 1 tablespoon of ezy sauce I small tub/tin of tomato paste 2 onions (peeled and halved) 50 to 100 g sugar (to taste) 1 teaspoon salt 2 apples quartered  Method  Put onions in Thermomix with garlic and ginger and chop for 5 seconds on Speed 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato Passata</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tomato_passata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tomato_passata/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Tomato_passata.jpg  Ingredients  1 brown onion 2 cloves of garlic 1-1.5kg fresh tomatoes chopped 30-50g balsamic vinegar 1 heaped tablespoon TMX stock handful of fresh herbs (or use dried) thyme, basil, sage, oregano 2 bay leaves salt to taste  Method  Add onion and garlic to bowl and chop on Speed 7 for 3 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato Sauce</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tomato_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tomato_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Tomato_sauce.jpg  Ingredients  1 clove of garlic 1 red onion (peeled and halved) 1kg fresh tomatoes (halved) 100g red capsicum (chopped) 1 small red apple (cored and halved) 100g tomato paste 150g sugar 100g balsamic vinegar 20-40g horseradish cream 4 bay leaves Tsp salt  Method  Add garlic and onion to bowl and chop for 3 seconds on Speed 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/whiskey_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/whiskey_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2tbsp olive oil 2 cloves of garlic 15g fresh ginger Pinch of salt ¼ tsp cayenne pepper 1 granny smith – peeled and cored 45g whiskey or bourbon 50g brown sugar 100g tomato sauce 20g apple cider vinegar 200g water 80g soy sauce 2 tbsp corn flour 6 trimmed and diced chicken thighs  Method  Add all ingredients EXCEPT chicken and corn flour to the bowl and mix on Speed 8 for 40 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Veloute</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_veloute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_veloute/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - steamed chicken &amp;amp; rice  1 litre water 2-3 tablespoons TM vege stock concentrate 250 grams white rice 2 carrots, peeled into tagliatelle 1 zucchini, peeled into tagliatelle 500-600 grams chicken tenderloins Fresh herbs  Ingredients - Veloute Sauce  3 tablespoons crame frache 1 tablespoon Dijon mustard 50-100 grams cornflour  Method  Weigh 1000g water into TM bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate ice cream</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_ice_cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_ice_cream/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Chocolate_Ice_Cream.jpg  Ingredients  4 Egg Yolks 150 g Sugar 200 g Full-Fat Milk 250 g Fresh Whipping Cream 100 g Dark Chocolate 1 Pinch Salt  Method  Put chocolate pieces into the bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salmon Veloute</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/salmon_veloute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/salmon_veloute/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  zest from 1 lemon or lime 2 sprigs fresh dill 2 cloves garlic 500 grams salmon fillet, fresh 2 onions 20 grams oilve oil 1 leek washed, white part only 1 kenebec potato, or other floury potato 1 small sweet potato 1 sprig Brocolli 1 small tomato 1- 2 tablespoons vegetable stock concentrate 500 grams water 2 teaspoons dijon-style mustard 2 tablespoons sour cream cracked pepper, to taste salt, to taste 2 carrots, sliced length ways really thinly with a peeler or v slicer 1 zucchini, sliced length ways really thinly with a peeler or v slicer  Method  Chop 1 garlic clove, zest &amp;amp; dill for 10 sec/ speed 10, scrape out of TM bowl &amp;amp; spread on top of the salmon pieces that are in the Varoma dish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oatmeal Smoothies</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/oatmeal_smoothies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/oatmeal_smoothies/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup ice 1/2 cup frozen raspberries 1/2 cup plain low fat yogurt 1 banana 1/2 cup old-fashioned rolled oats 1 tablespoon honey 1 cup coconut water (or other liquid, such as juice)  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 2 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gratin Dauphinois</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/gratin_dauphinois/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/gratin_dauphinois/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500ml milk 250ml cream 1 garlic clove, half finely sliced, half left whole Pinch freshly grated nutmeg 140g gruyere, grated Butter, for greasing Sea salt and freshly ground white pepper Chopped flat-leaf parsley, to serve  Method  Bring the milk and cream to the boil in a large saucepan over medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kale Chips</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/kale_chips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/kale_chips/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 large bunch curly kale (about 200g. after thick stems removed) 1 fresh red bell pepper, medium sized (sweet pepper, capsicum) about 20-25 g. nutritional yeast flakes (equal to one full measuring cap) (NOT baker’s yeast!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hawaiian Pulled Pork</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hawaiian_pulled_pork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hawaiian_pulled_pork/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3-4lbs Pork Shoulder 1 can crushed or cubed pineapple (in water) 1 tbl grated ginger (or 1/2 tsp ginger powder)  Method  Put pork in a crock pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hawaiian Pulled Pork Sandwich</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hawaiian_pulled_pork_sandwich/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hawaiian_pulled_pork_sandwich/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2.5 lbs pork butt, cut into 2 inch pieces 1 medium onion, finely chopped 1/2 cup ketchup 1/3 cup cider vinegar 1/4 cup packed brown sugar 1/4 cup tomato paste 2 tbsp sweet paprika 1 tbsp red pepper flakes 2 tbsp Worcestershire sauce 1 15oz can Pineapple, discard the sauce 3 tsp salt 2 tsp black pepper 1 avocado, optional  Method  Cut the pork butt into 2 inch pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Beetroot Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pink_beetroot_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pink_beetroot_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  a couple of chunks of raw beetroot 2 apples, quartered (deseeded if you like) 1 orange, peeled 1 lime, peeled 1 large carrot, quartered 1 stalk celery, quartered 200g ice 300ml Natural Raw C coconut water 200ml water  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool It Green Juice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cool_it_green_juice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cool_it_green_juice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1/2 apple, peeled and cored 1/2 lime, peeled 4 large romaine lettuce leaves 1/2 cucumber 3 stalks mint  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cucumber Cooler Juice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cucumber_cooler_juice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cucumber_cooler_juice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 1/2 cucumber (or 1 English cucumber) 1 lime, peeled 6 mint leaves  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.5 minutes.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go-Go Goji</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/go-go_goji/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/go-go_goji/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup homemade Brazil nut milk 1 cup or 4 kale leaves 1 banana 1/2 cup frozen strawberries 1 tbl goji berries  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Greens Juice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/good_greens_juice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/good_greens_juice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  4 leaves romaine lettuce 1/2 lemon, peeled 1/2 cucumber 1/2 apple, peeled 1/2 cup chopped pineapple, peeled and cored 1/2 cup basil  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kale Energizer Juice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/kale_energizer_juice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/kale_energizer_juice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups kale 1/2 yellow apple, peeled and cored 1/3 cucumber 1 stalk celery 1/2 lemon, peeled  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pina Colada</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pina_colada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pina_colada/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1/2 cup canned coconut milk 1 cup chopped pineapple, peeled and cored 1/2 cup or 2 kale leaves 1 inch slice fresh ginger  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pineapple Express Juice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pineapple_express_juice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pineapple_express_juice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 stalks celery 1 cup chopped pineapple, peeled and cored 4-5 kale leaves 1/2 lime, peeled 1/4 cucumber  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skin Tonic Juice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/skin_tonic_juice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/skin_tonic_juice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cucumber 1/2 lemon, peeled 1 cup Purslane 1/2 mango, peeled and pit removed Handful of cilantro  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bee-utiful</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/the_bee-utiful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/the_bee-utiful/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup almond milk 1/2 avocado, peeled 1/2 cup kale 1tsl bee pollen 1 tbl raw honey  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Green Kiss</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/the_green_kiss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/the_green_kiss/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup coconut water 1/2 pear 1/2 avocado, peeled 1 cup spinach 1 tbl flax seeds 1/2 - 1 cup water  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Kiwi</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/the_kiwi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/the_kiwi/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1/2 cup coconut milk 1/2 cup coconut water 1 kiwi, peeled 1/4 avocado, peeled Juice of 1/2 lime 1/2 cup spinach  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watermelon Medley Juice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/watermelon_medley_juice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/watermelon_medley_juice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 1/2 cups watermelon 1/2 cucumber 1 cup kale (3-4 small leaves with stems) 6 mint leaves 1 inch slice fresh ginger  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acai Green</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/acai_green/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/acai_green/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 1/2 cups almond milk 1/2 cup blueberries 1 pack (about 3.5 oz) frozen unsweetened acai 1 cup spinach 1/4 avocado, peeled 1 tsp chia seeds 1 scoop pea protein  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Green Juice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/all_green_juice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/all_green_juice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  4 stalks celery 1/2 cucumber 2 leaves kale 1 leaf chard, any variety (with stem) 1 handful of spinach 1/2 cup parsley 1/2 lemon, peeled 1 inch slice ginger  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Pie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/apple_pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/apple_pie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 apple, peeled 1 cup kale 1 cup nut milk of choice 1/2 tsp cinnamon 1/4 lemon, peeled 1/4 cup walnuts  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beet It Juice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beet_it_juice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beet_it_juice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 Beetroots 1 lemon, peeled 1 1/2 inch slice fresh ginger 1 carrot 1 cup or 3 leaves kale (stem included)  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C Booster</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/c_booster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/c_booster/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 orange, peeled and seeded 1 cup kale 1/2 lemon, peeled 1 tbl raw honey 1 inch slice fresh ginger, grated into the blender  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cilantro Fiesta Juice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cilantro_fiesta_juice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cilantro_fiesta_juice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  6 leaves romaine lettuce 1/2 cup cilantro (coriander leaves) 1/2 lime, peeled 1 1/2 cups chopped pineapple, peeled and cored  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coconut Greens</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/coconut_greens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/coconut_greens/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 whole young coconut (scope out flesh) 1 cup or 1 big handful kale 3 ice cubes  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copacabana</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/copacabana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/copacabana/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 whole coconut (scoop out flesh) 1 cup spinach 1 frozen banana  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.5 minutes.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dandelion Bliss</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/dandelion_bliss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/dandelion_bliss/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup water 1 cup chopped cucumber 1 cup dandelion greens 1/2 green apple 1/2 lemon, peeled  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dandelion Detox</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/dandelion_detox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/dandelion_detox/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 1/2 cups coconut water 1/4 avocado, peeled 1 cup dandelion greens 1/2 cup frozen blueberries 1 tbl raw cacao powder 1 tbl hemp powder or seeds  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall into Winter Greens</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fall_into_winter_greens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fall_into_winter_greens/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup water 1/3 bulb fennel 1 cup or 3 leaves kale (stems removed) 1/2 pear  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.5 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grapefruit Greens</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/grapefruit_greens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/grapefruit_greens/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup water 1 cup or 4 large leaves romaine lettuce 1 stalk celery 1/3 cucumber 1/2 grapefruit, peeled 1/2 lime, peeled 1/3 cup coriander leaves  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Goddess Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/green_goddess_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/green_goddess_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup coconut water 1 cup chopped pineapple, peeled and cored 3 leaves romaine lettuce 2 leaves kale 1/2 lime, peeled 1/4 cup coriander leaves  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Master</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/green_master/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/green_master/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup or 3 leaves kale 1/4 green apple 1/2 lemon, peeled 1 inch slice fresh ginger 1/4 tsp cayenne pepper 1 tbl real maple syrup 1/2 cup water 1/2 cup freshly made apple juice  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Mojito</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/green_mojito/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/green_mojito/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup water 1 cup chopped pineapple, peeled and cored 1/2 lime, peeled 1 cup or 1 big handful of spinach Leaves of 2 stalks (about 1/4 cup) mint 6 ice cubes  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Power Bliss</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/green_power_bliss/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/green_power_bliss/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup almond milk 1/2 pear 1/4 avocado, peeled 1 packed cup spinach 1/4 cup coconut water 1 tsp chia seeds 1 scoop pea protein powder (or hemp protein or brown rice protein) 1 cup pure water  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenest Green</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/greenest_green/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/greenest_green/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 1/2 cups water 1 stalk celery 1/2 cucumber 1/2 avocado 1 cup or 4 leaves romaine lettuce 1/3 cup parsley 1/2 lemon, peeled Pinch of sea salt  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hail to the Kale</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hail_to_the_kale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hail_to_the_kale/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup coconut water 1 cup kale 1/2 pear 1/4 avocado, peeled 1/2 cucumber 1/2 lemon, peeled Handful of coriander leaves 1/2 inch slice ginger 1 scoop protein powder 1/2 to 1 cup water, as needed to reach desired consistency  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunity Green Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/immunity_green_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/immunity_green_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup coconut water 2 leaves romaine lettuce 1/2 green apple (Granny Smith) 1/4 cucumber 1/4 avocado, peeled 1/2 lemon, peeled 1/2 inch slice fresh ginger 1/2 cup fresh parsley 1 serving probiotic powder 3-4 ice cubes (optional)  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kiwi, Spinach &amp; Avocado</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/kiwi_spinach_avocado/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/kiwi_spinach_avocado/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 1/2 cups coconut water 1 cup spinach 2 kiwis, peeled 1/2 avocado, peeled  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.5 minutes.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OJ &amp; Greens Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/oj_greens_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/oj_greens_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup freshly squeezed orange juice 1 carrot 1 inch slice fresh ginger 1 inch slice fresh turmeric or 1/4 tsp turmeric powder 1/2 lemon, peeled 1 tbl raw honey 1 cup or 4 leaves romaine lettuce  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peachy Green</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/peachy_green/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/peachy_green/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1/2 cup coconut milk Juice of 1 orange 1 peach, pit removed 1 cup or 4 large leaves romaine lettuce  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pineapple Greens</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pineapple_greens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pineapple_greens/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 1/2 cups coconut water 1 cup chopped pineapple, peeled and cored 1/2 cucumber 1 cup or 3-4 leaves romaine lettuce 3 ice cubes  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Breakfast</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/power_breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/power_breakfast/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup cold green tea (unsweetened) 3/4 cup kale 1/2 cup frozen blueberries 1/3 cup rolled oats 1/2 banana 1 medjool date or 1 tbl raw honey  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purple &amp; Green</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/purple_green/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/purple_green/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup coconut milk 1/2 cup fresh or frozen blueberries 1 cup spinach 1/2 tsp cinnamon 1/4 avocado 1 scoop pea protein Water (optional)  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refresh Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/refresh_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/refresh_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 1/2 cups coconut water 1/2 cup kale 1/2 cup spinach 1/2 cup romaine lettuce 1/2 lime, peeled leaves from 2 stems of mint  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeds of Change</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/seeds_of_change/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/seeds_of_change/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup almond milk 1 tbl hemp seeds 1 tbl flax seeds 1 tbl chia seeds 1 inch slice fresh ginger 1 cup spinach 1 frozen banana  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweet Almond Kale</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sweet_almond_kale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sweet_almond_kale/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup kale 1 1/2 cups almond milk 1/2 banana (fresh or frozen) 1/2 cup mango (fresh or frozen) 1/4 tsp cinnamon  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Wonder</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/winter_wonder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/winter_wonder/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup almond milk 1 persimmon 1 cup or 1 handful of spinach 1/2 tsp cinnamon 1/4 tsp cardamom 1/2 tsp vanilla extract 1 medjool date  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Crumble 2</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/apple_crumble_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/apple_crumble_2/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Crumble  100g butter, cut into pieces, plus some extra 80g sugar 150g flour 1 pinch salt  Ingredients - Filling  600g apples, cored, cut into quarters 1 tbl lemon juice 40g sugar 1tsp ground cinnamon  Method  Preheat oven to 180deg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bechamel Sauce</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/bechamel_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/bechamel_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  40g butter 40g flour 500g milk 1/2tsp salt 2 pinches pepper 2 pinches nutmeg  Method  Place butter into mixing bowl and melt 3min,100deg,sp1. Add flour, lightly sauté 3min,100deg,sp1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Stock Paste</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_stock_paste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_stock_paste/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  300g chicken thigh fillets 200g mixed white vegetables (celeriac, onion, garlic, leek), cut into pieces 4 sprigs mixed fresh herbs (rosemary, thyme, parsley), leaves only 150g coarse sea salt 100g white wine 1 dried bay leave 1 clove 5 coriander seeds  Method  Place chicken pieces into mixing bowl, mince 5sec, sp7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Custard</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_custard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_custard/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  50g dark chocolate, cut into pieces 500g milk 20g sugar 20g corn flour (starch) 1 egg (optional)  Method  Place dark chocolate into mixing bowl and grate 10sec,sp4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Mousse</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_mousse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_mousse/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Chocolate_Mousse.jpg  Ingredients  100g sugar (reduce to 80g) 200g dark chocolate, cut into pieces or 6tbl Van Houten Cacao powder 100g cream, min 30% fat 4 eggs 1 pinch salt  Method  Place sugar into MC bowl, pulverise 10sec,sp10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codfish fillets with Citrus Butter</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/codfish_fillets_with_citrus_butter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/codfish_fillets_with_citrus_butter/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  700g water 400g potatoes, cut into pieces 600g zucchini, cut into 0.5cm slices 4 codfish fillets 1 organic orange 1 organic lemon Salt &amp;amp; pepper 80g butter, cut into pieces, plus some extra 1 tsp aniseed 3 sprigs parsley, fresh leaves only, chopped  Method  Pour water into mixing bowl, insert simmering basket and weigh potatoes into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cream Cheese Spread</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cream_cheese_spread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cream_cheese_spread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1-2 garlic cloves 80g red capsicum, cut into pieces 80g yellow capsicum, cut into pieces 100g cucumber, deseeded, cut into pieces 400g cream cheese, full or reduced fat 1/4tsp curry powder 1/2 tsp hot paprika 1/2tsp salt 1/4 tsp pepper  Method  Place garlic clove into MC bowl, chop 5sec,sp5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eggs, boiled</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/eggs_boiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/eggs_boiled/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500g water 4 eggs  Method  Pour water into mixing bowl, insert simmering basket, place 4eggs into it, insert MC and steam. Time as indicated in the list below , Varoma, sp1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fish Stock Paste</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fish_stock_paste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fish_stock_paste/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500g fish and seafood, mixed, fresh (preferred salt water: codfish, angler, bass, scampi, prawns) 240g coarse sea salt  Method  Clean fish (skinned, boned) and seafood (peeled) well and pat dry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garlic and Herb Dip</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/garlic_and_herb_dip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/garlic_and_herb_dip/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Garlic_and_herb_dip.jpg  Ingredients  Small bunch fresh Parsley 1 small clove garlic 2 shallots/spring onions 250g cream cheese 2 tbls yoghurt, or 10–20 g Milk (optional)  Method  Place parsley, garlic and shallots/spring onions into TM bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herb Salt</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/herb_salt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/herb_salt/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  40g dried mixed herbs (rosemary, thyme, basil, parsley, savory, lovage) 200g sea salt  Method  Place herbs and sea salts into mixing bowl, pulverise 30-40sec, sp9. Transfer into jam jar with a twist-off lid and store into a dry place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hollandaise Sauce</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hollandaise_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hollandaise_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  130g butter, cut into pieces 50g white wine 1tbl lemon juice 1 pinch pepper 4 egg yolks  Method  Insert butterfly. Place all ingredients into MC bowl. Beat 5-6min/70deg,sp2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ketchup</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/ketchup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/ketchup/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1kg ripe tomatoes, cut into quarters 180g red capsicum, cut into pieces 130g red onions, cut into halves 2 garlic cloves 100g red wine vinegar 1 pinch nutmeg 10 mustard seeds 10 black peppercorns 1 dried bay leaf 1 tsp hot paprika  1 pinch cayenne pepper</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mango Chutney</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/mango_chutney/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/mango_chutney/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 tbl Sichuan pepper 2 garlic cloves 10g ginger, cut into thin slices 80g onions, cut into halves 20g water 250g raw cane sugar 700g mangoes, peeled, cored, cut into pieces 120g vinegar 1 tsp salt 1/2tsp tumeric 100g raisins  Method  Place Sichuan pepper into mixing bowl, toast 6min,Varoma,Reverse,sp1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Home Scents</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/natural_home_scents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/natural_home_scents/</guid>
      <description>Notes  Add fragrance to your home using simmering waters infused with spices, herbs &amp;amp; fruit.  Scent #1  Oranges, cinnamon &amp;amp; cloves (allspice and anise are optional). This scent carries into multiple rooms better, and it can be reheated to scent your rooms for several days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potato and Vegetable Puree</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/potato_and_vegetable_puree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/potato_and_vegetable_puree/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  600g water 650g potatoes, floury, cut into pieces 350g vegetables, eg carrots, cut into pieces 200g milk 1/2tsp salt 1 pinch nutmeg 30g butter  Method  Place water into MC bowl, insert simmering basket and weigh potatoes into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potato Cakes with Apple Sauce</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/potato_cakes_with_apple_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/potato_cakes_with_apple_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1kg potatoes, cut into pieces 150g onions, cut into quarters 1 tbl lemon juice 1tsp salt 1/4 tsp pepper 20g starch 20g oat flakes 1 egg  frying oil</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tumeric Tea</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tumeric_tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tumeric_tea/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Tumeric_tea.jpg  Ingredients  1/3 cup or 80ml good raw honey 1 1/2 tsp dried tumeric Lemon lots of freshly ground black pepper  Method  Work the turmeric into the honey until it forms a paste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetable Salt</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/vegetable_salt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/vegetable_salt/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  50g soup vegetables, freeze-dried (carrot, leek, celery, parsnip, lovage, onion, parsley), in small pieces 1 tbl turmeric 1 tbl sweet paprika 1 tsp garlic flakes 1 tbl sea salt 1/2 tsp black peppercorns  Method  Place all ingredients into mixing bowl and grind 10se, sp10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chewy Chocolate Cookies</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chewy_chocolate_cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chewy_chocolate_cookies/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  150 grams macadamias 150 grams medjool dates, seeds removed 1 tablespoon cacao or cocoa or carob  Method  Preheat oven to 180 Degrees Celcius. Line an oven tray with baking paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coconut Milk Yoghurt</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/coconut_milk_yoghurt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/coconut_milk_yoghurt/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Coconut_milk_yoghurt.jpg  My Improved version - 26 Jan 2014 Ingredients  1 can of 560ml Coconut Cream 1 can of 560ml Coconut Milk 60g Potato Starch (Arrowroot) 120g Natural Yoghurt culture  Method  In Thermomix, blend coconut cream and potato starch for 10sec, sp4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wholefood Simply Ginger Cookies</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/wholefood_simply_ginger_cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/wholefood_simply_ginger_cookies/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup (or 150g) macadamias 1 cup (or 150g) medjool dates 1 tablespoon ground ginger 2 teaspoon of coconut flour  Method  Preheat your oven to 180 degrees Celcuis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberries and Yoghurt Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/strawberries_and_yoghurt_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/strawberries_and_yoghurt_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup frozen strawberries 1/2 cup reduced fat Greek yoghurt 1 frozen banana 1 cup water 2 tsp Acai powder 2 tsp chia seeds  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almond Butter and Jelly Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/almond_butter_and_jelly_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/almond_butter_and_jelly_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups spinach 2 cups almond milk, unsweetened 1 cup red grapes 2 frozen banana 4 tbl almond butter  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberries Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/blueberries_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/blueberries_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 1 1/2 cups reduced fat milk 1/2 cup reduced fat natural yoghurt 1 frozen banana 3/4 cup frozen blueberries 1 tbl honey 1 tbl LSA (optional)  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cacao Banana Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cacao_banana_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cacao_banana_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 Tbsp Cacao Powder 1 Tbsp Chia Seeds 2 Bananas (small) 1 Cup fresh organic Strawberries, trimmed 1 cup plain Almond Milk  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cacao Cherry Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cacao_cherry_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cacao_cherry_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup cherries, pits removed 1 medium banana, peeled 2 cups fresh baby spinach (or other leafy green) 1 tablespoon cacao powder 4 to 6 ounces of filter water  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cacao Coconut Green Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cacao_coconut_green_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cacao_coconut_green_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Meat and water from one young, Thai coconut 1 cup fresh pineapple, cubed 1 tablespoon cacao powder (UK friends can buy cacao powder here) 2 cups fresh baby spinach (or other leafy green) 3 to 4 ice cubes to chill (optional)  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cacao Mango Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cacao_mango_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cacao_mango_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 Tbsp Cacao Powder 1 Tbsp Chia Seeds 2 Bananas (small) 1 Cup frozen mango 1 cup water 1 cup plain Cashew/Almond Milk  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Covered Cherry</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_covered_cherry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_covered_cherry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups fresh spinach 2 cups almond milk, unsweetened 2 cups cherries, pitted 2 cups banana 1 tsp cinnamon 3 tbl cacao powder  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Dipped Strawberries Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_dipped_strawberries_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_dipped_strawberries_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups fresh kale, stems removed 2 cups almond milk, unsweetened 2 cups strawberries 2 frozen banana 3 tbl cacao powder  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coconut Dream Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/coconut_dream_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/coconut_dream_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups kale, stems removed 2 cups coconut milk, unsweetened 1 cup mango 1 cup pineapple 1 frozen banana 2 tbl coconut flakes, unsweetened  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cream Machine Green Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cream_machine_green_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cream_machine_green_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups fresh spinach 1 cup water 1/2 avocado 1/2 cup frozen mango 1/2 frozen banana  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dreamsicle Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/dreamsicle_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/dreamsicle_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups fresh spinach 1 cup orange juice 1 cup water 2 oranges 2 frozen banana 1 tsp vanilla extract  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fruit Leather</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fruit_leather/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fruit_leather/</guid>
      <description>1 - Apple Fruit Leather Ingredients  4 apples 150g water  Method  Preheat oven on lowest temperature Line baking tray with baking paper Peel, core and cut apples into quarters Chop 20 seconds / speed 4 Add water, cook 90 degrees / speed 4 / 9 minutes Blend, speed 9 / 30 seconds Spread evenly over baking tray Bake in oven for 4 hours  2 - Strawberry Rollups Fruit Leather Ingredients  1 punnet strawberries 1 tbl caster sugar (optional)  Method  Preheat oven to lowest temperature Line a baking tray with baking paper Remove the leaves from the strawberries Place strawberries and sugar into mini chopper, and blitz until strawberries are smooth Pour strawberry puree onto baking tray Place in oven and cook for 3 hours or until the mix is dried and not sticky Chop into desired size and place in an airtight container  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healthy Cacao Green Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/healthy_cacao_green_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/healthy_cacao_green_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 mango, peeled and pitted 1 cup frozen blueberries 3 cups baby spinach 1/4 cup cacao nibs (or 2 tablespoons cacao powder) 8 ounces of filtered almond milk sweetener (optional)  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peachy Cobbler Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/peachy_cobbler_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/peachy_cobbler_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups fresh spinach 2 cups almond milk, unsweetened 2 cups peaches 1 cup apple 1 frozen banana  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pineapple, Kale &amp; Coconut Oil Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pineapple_kale_coconut_oil_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pineapple_kale_coconut_oil_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Title  Try this nutrient-packed green smoothie with fresh cut pineapple, kale and coconut oil. Coconut oil has some amazing health benefits such as increasing metabolism and endurance— which is great if you workout or are running after little ones all day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Flamingo Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pink_flamingo_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pink_flamingo_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups fresh spinach 2 cups almond milk, unsweetened 2 cups strawberries 1 cup mango  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creamy Hemp Pesto</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamy_hemp_pesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamy_hemp_pesto/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: HempPestoPasta.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Ingredients - Cashew Cream  1 cup cashews 3/4 cup water  Ingredients - Pesto  2 cups fresh basil, packed 1/3 cup hemp seeds 2 garlic cloves 2/3 cup extra virgin olive oil zest of 1 lemon pinch of salt and pepper 1/2 cup cashew cream  Method - Cashew Cream  Blend cashews and water in a Thermomix until ultra smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheesy Potato Bake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheesy_potato_bake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheesy_potato_bake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  60g butter 1/4 cup plain flour 2 1/3 cups milk 2 cups grated tasty cheese 1.2kg Sebago potatoes, peeled, thinly sliced  Method  Preheat oven to 180°C. Grease a 6cm deep, 24cm square baking dish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pomegranate Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pomegranate_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pomegranate_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup water 1/4 cup raw cashews or almonds 1 cup pomegranate seeds 1 tbl raw honey (or maple syrup or dates - or none if you think it is sweet enough!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aloe Vera Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/aloe_vera_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/aloe_vera_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup of coconut milk or almond milk 1 medium aloe vera leaf, filleted (approximately 1/2 cup) 1/2 cup fresh or frozen blueberries 1/2 cup fresh or frozen mango chunks 1 handful of fresh basil 1tbl agave (optional)  Add-Ons  1 tbl coconut oil 1 serving protein powder of your choice 1/4 cup coconut shreds or flakes  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Aloe Vera Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/green_aloe_vera_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/green_aloe_vera_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup Kale leaves, stems removed 1 cup water 1 medium aloe vera leaf, filleted (approximately 1/2 cup) 1/2 cup frozen orange 1/2 cup frozen mango chunks 1tbl agave 2tsp Chia seeds 1/2tsp Maca powder 1tsp Mana powder  Method  Blend Kale leaves &amp;amp; water until leaves are broken down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueberry Yoghurt Green Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/blueberry_yoghurt_green_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/blueberry_yoghurt_green_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Note  I love the way this tastes like it has yoghurt in it, but is completely dairy free! The secret is the creamy cashew or almond milk with lime and banana - so simple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cucumber Orange Juice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cucumber_orange_juice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cucumber_orange_juice/</guid>
      <description>Note  Cucumber is another great addition to green juices. This is a great one for the kids, as it&amp;rsquo;s sweet, not too thick, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t taste too &amp;lsquo;green&amp;rsquo;.  Ingredients  half a cucumber (peeled) 2 green apples (quartered) 1 orange (peeled) 1 lime (peeled) 1 frozen banana (quartered) 2 big handfuls of ice 2 big handfuls of cos lettuce 300g water 2 tsp of Vital Veggie Powder  Method  Blend on speed 10 for 2 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favourite Green Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/favourite_green_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/favourite_green_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 or 2 frozen bananas, quartered 2 apples, quartered (no need to peel or de-seed) 1 lime, peeled, include some peel 2 handfuls of ice 300g coconut water 2 or 3 big handfuls of fresh greens (kale, baby spinach, English spinach, cos or butter lettuce)  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 2 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fruity Green Boost Juice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fruity_green_boost_juice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fruity_green_boost_juice/</guid>
      <description>Note  This one can really just be a mixture of whatever fruit you need to use up in your fruit basket. Get creative and see what you can come up with!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Coconut Boost Juice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/green_coconut_boost_juice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/green_coconut_boost_juice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  a couple of big handfuls of kale flesh of a young coconut coconut water (from young coconut) a frozen banana or two, quartered (depending how thick you like it) 1 lime (peeled) 2 teaspoons of mesquite powder 300g water a couple of handfuls of ice  Method  Blend in the Thermomix on speed 10 for 2 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lime and Parsley Juice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lime_and_parsley_juice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lime_and_parsley_juice/</guid>
      <description>Note  This may sound a bit scary, but it really is deliciously refreshing!  Ingredients  60g rapadura (or more if not adding stevia) 300g ice 2 limes (peeled) a big handful of organic parsley 1/2 tsp green stevia powder (opt) 300g water  Method  Grind up Rapadura for 20 sec speed 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purple Power Green Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/purple_power_green_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/purple_power_green_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Note  For a brighter, prettier purple smoothie, try this one!  Ingredients  300g frozen blueberries 2 nectarines or peaches, deseeded 1 frozen banana, quartered 2 big handfuls cos lettuce 2 big handfuls of ice 300g coconut water or water  Method  Blend for 2 minutes speed 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dragon Fruit Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/dragon_fruit_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/dragon_fruit_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Dragon_fruit_smoothie.jpg  Ingredients  1 frozen banana 1 medium Dragon fruit 35g blueberries 60g plain Greek yoghurt 1tsp Acai powder 1tbl coconut sugar (optional) 1.5 cups water  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fruity Nut Balls</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fruity_nut_balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fruity_nut_balls/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Fruity_nut_balls.jpg  Ingredients  1 cup of natural muesli 1/2 cup of macadamia 1 drop Young Living Orange essential oil Pinch of salt 1 tsp honey  Method  Grind muesli with macadamia nuts in food processor until fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goji Berry Mango Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/goji_berry_mango_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/goji_berry_mango_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1.5 cups frozen mango flesh 1/3 cup goji berries 50g plain Greek yoghurt 1.5 cups water 1tbl coconut oil 1tbl agave 1/2 tsp maca powder Pinch of salt  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Smoothie Formula</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/green_smoothie_formula/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/green_smoothie_formula/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 cups Leafy Greens - Spinach, Kale, Romaine, Bok Choy, Swiss Chard, Collards, Dandelion 2 cups Liquid Base - Water, Coconut Water, Coconut Milk, Almond Milk 3 cups Ripe Fruit - Banana, Mango, Berries, Orange, Avocado, Peach, Pear, Apple, Pineapple, Grapes  Method  Blend leafy greens &amp;amp; liquid base together first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maca Green Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/maca_green_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/maca_green_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Maca_green_smoothie_1.jpg
  1 cup fresh kale, stems removed
  1 cup almond milk
  1 frozen banana
  ½ green apple</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Muesli</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/natural_muesli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/natural_muesli/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1/2 cup shredded coconut 1/2 cup dried figs 1/2 cup dried apricots 1/2 cup raisins or sultanas 1/4 cup dried cranberries 1/2 cup dried dates 1/2 cup sunflower seeds 1/2 cup activated almonds 1/2 cup activated walnuts 1/2 cup activated cashews  Method  Blend all ingredients in food processor to desired texture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raw Cacao Bliss Balls</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/raw_cacao_bliss_balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/raw_cacao_bliss_balls/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  110g Almonds raw, nuts 110g pitted dates 20g pepitas (pumpkin seeds) 35g shredded Coconut 20g goji berries 20g raw organic cacao powder 1tbl chia seeds  Method  Place almonds into TM bowl, Blend 20sec,sp9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical Fruit Smoothie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tropical_fruit_smoothie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tropical_fruit_smoothie/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Tropical_fruit_smoothie.jpg  Ingredients  1 frozen banana 1 cup frozen mango flesh 1 cup frozen pineapple slices 1.5 cups water 1tbl agave 1tbl coconut sugar 2tsp chia or hemp seeds  Method  Blend all ingredients in a blender until smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical Mango Matcha Smoothie Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tropical_mango_matcha_smoothie_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tropical_mango_matcha_smoothie_cake/</guid>
      <description>Original image caption: Tropical Mango Matcha Smoothie  Description  Do you have a picky eater in your household who refuses to eat their veggies? The trick is all in the presentation!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft Butter</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/soft_butter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/soft_butter/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Refer website above  Method    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quinoa, Oat &amp; Coconut Cookies</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/quinoa_oat_coconut_cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/quinoa_oat_coconut_cookies/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  125g Butter, Unsalted 40g Rapadura Sugar, or Sweetner 30g Maple syrup 95g quinoa flakes 90g rolled oats 60g coconut flakes 1 egg 50g Cacao Nibs or Choc Bits, (Optional)  Method  Preheat the oven to 170°C (338°F) and line a baking tray with greaseproof paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Kebab</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_kebab/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_kebab/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Moorish Dressing  5 garlic cloves 60g mustard, eg mild Dijon mustard 3tbl (70g) tomato sauce 1tsp salt 2tbl oregano, dried 20g lemon juice (from half a lemon) 50g extra virgin olive oil 1tbl 10g) white wine vinegar  1 pinch black pepper, ground</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoked Salmon and Dill Cream</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/smoked_salmon_and_dill_cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/smoked_salmon_and_dill_cream/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  400g smoked salmon, in slices 500g cream, min 30% fat 1tbl dill, fresh, snipped 1tsp salt 2 pinches black pepper, ground  Method  Place salmon into TM bowl and chop 10 sec/sp6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stir-Fried Tomatoes and Squid</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/stir-fried_tomatoes_and_squid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/stir-fried_tomatoes_and_squid/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  10g garlic cloves 10g olive oil 200g tomatoes, cut into bite-size pieces 200g squid, whole, medium, cut into 4cm pieces 100g snow peas  1/4tsp salt
Method  Place garlic into TM bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cambodian Marinated Braised Beef (with a Thai twist)</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cambodian_marinated_braised_beef_with_a_thai_twist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cambodian_marinated_braised_beef_with_a_thai_twist/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500 grams beef (I use poterhouse) trimmed  Ingredients - Marinade  2 tablespoons dark soy sauce 2 tablespoons fish sauce 1 chilli 2 cloves garlic 1 bunch coriander (about 4 pieces) 2 tablespoons oyster sauce 1-2 teaspoons fresh ground black pepper 40 grams ginger Juice of 1 lime 1 teaspoon palm sugar (I use one small block of Jeeny&amp;rsquo;s brand).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Nuggets</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_nuggets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_nuggets/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  200g chicken breasts, skinless, cut into pieces 1/2 tsp salt 1/2 tsp granulated garlic or one clove garlic 2 slices white bread (without crust) 60g cream cheese 60g milk 1 egg, beaten with 50g water 100 breadcrumbs oil for frying  Method  Place chicken pieces, salt and garlic into TM bowl and chop 5sec/sp 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stewed Ribs with Spring Onions</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/stewed_ribs_with_spring_onions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/stewed_ribs_with_spring_onions/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  50g sugar or brown sugar 10g olive oil 600g pork spare ribs, 10cm long each, approx. 12 pieces 50g soy sauce 40g water 1000g spring onions, cut into 5cm pieces 10g fresh coriander  Method  Place sugar into mixing bowl and pulverise 15sec/sp 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Date Choc Bar</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/date_choc_bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/date_choc_bar/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  100g Almond 500g Dates 25g Cocoa Powder 2tbsp honey  Method  Preheat oven to 170C on fan forced. Soak dates in hot water for at least 10 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dates Bar</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/dates_bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/dates_bar/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients for filling  2 1/2 cups pitted dates, cut up - soaks in hot water for at least 10mins 1tsp bicarbonate of soda 250g boiling water 50g raw sugar 35g walnuts, optional  Ingredients for Crumble  200g plain flour 1 teaspoon salt 1/2 teaspoon baking soda 140g rolled oats 125g brown sugar 125g butter, softened 2 tablespoons water  Method  Roughly chop walnuts in TM bowl for 2secs/Sp6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meatballs</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/meatballs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 onion - peeled and quartered 2 cloves of garlic big bunch of fresh herbs; basil, oregano, parsley etc 2 slices of bread 600g mince beef 400g tinned tomatoes 1 tbsp stock concentrate 100ml red wine 1 tbsp tomato paste cheese for topping 180g rice (quantity is adjustable)  Method  Make breadcrumbs by placing bread (I use the crust ends that no-one likes) into TM bowl and chop Speed 7 for 10 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Dumplings and Chive Pancakes with Dipping Sauce</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_dumplings_and_chive_pancakes_with_dipping_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_dumplings_and_chive_pancakes_with_dipping_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Chinese_dumplings_with_dipping_sauce.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Dough Ingredients  500g plain flour 350g boiling water  Method  Place the flour into the Thermomix bowl, mix on speed 5 for 10 seconds to lighten and aerate it slightly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Pancakes</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_pancakes/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Dumpling dough from [[Chinese Dumplings and Chive Pancakes with Dipping Sauce]] Spring onions, finely sliced Salt (Prefer Himalayan, but we used vegetable) Oil  Method  Rest dough for 30 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Tart</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_tart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_tart/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Chocolate_tart.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Ingredients Crust  25g hazelnuts 80g butter 50g sugar 1 egg 180g flour  Topping  200g good quality dark chocolate (cut into pieces) 150g cream 2 egg yolks 50g sugar  Method  Place nuts into TM bowl and mill 10sec/speed 9 Add other crust ingredients and knead 30 sec/speed 5 to form dough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Pie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_pie/</guid>
      <description>Original image caption: From website.  Ingredients  2 cups white sugar 5 tablespoons cocoa powder 1/4 cup plain flour 1 x 395g can evaporated milk 1 tsp vanilla extract 4 egg yolks 1/4 cup butter 1 x 23cm sweet pie shell  Method  Preheat oven to 180 degrees In a saucepan, whisk together 2 cups sugar, cocoa and flour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinach and Feta Filo Pie (Jamie Oliver)</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spinach_and_feta_filo_pie_jamie_oliver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spinach_and_feta_filo_pie_jamie_oliver/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Spinach_and_fetta_filo_pie.jpg Original image caption: Taken on 28/09/2013.  Ingredients  100g pine nuts 5 eggs 300g feta cheese 50g Cheddar cheese dried oregano 1 lemon a good knob of butter 400g pre-washed spinach 1x 270g pack of filo pastry cayenne pepper 1 whole nutmeg  Method   Pre-heat your oven to 200°C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Dumplings</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_dumplings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_dumplings/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients - Dough  400 g flour 250-300 g boiling water (this can vary depending on the flour)  Method - Dough  Place flour and water into the TM bowl, with dial set to closed lid position, knead for 1 to 2 minutes on Interval speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoghurt (Greek)</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/yoghurt_greek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/yoghurt_greek/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  40g Raw sugar 2 litres of whole milk 1/2 cup Skim milk Powder 1/2 cup of Natural yoghurt ( I used George&amp;rsquo;s Natural Yoghurt)  Method  Add Raw sugar to TM bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Seconds Orange and Yoghurt Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/30_seconds_orange_and_yoghurt_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/30_seconds_orange_and_yoghurt_cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  225g plain flour 2 tsp baking powder 200g white sugar 1 tsp ground cardamom 1 whole orange, skin still on, top and bottom removed and sliced into quarters (use Valencia if possible as the skin is thinner).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Seconds Whole Orange Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/30_seconds_whole_orange_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/30_seconds_whole_orange_cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 whole orange, cut into quarters 225g butter 3 eggs 200g sugar (reduced to 180g) 300g self-raising flour (or 2 cups plain flour and 4 tsp baking powder)  Method  Preheat oven to 180C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Kofta with Cashew Cream</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_kofta_with_cashew_cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_kofta_with_cashew_cream/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients for Kofta  1 clove garlic Pinch of saffron threads 1 leek a good sprinkle of chives Small handful parsley 6-8 brussel sprouts 1 teaspoon salt 200g bread crumbs 800g chicken mince  Ingredients for Cashew Cream  300g of cashews 300g water 1 clove garlic 1 teaspoon citric acid 1 teaspoon of salt  Method for Kofta  Add garlic, saffron, leek, chives, parsley and brussel sprouts to TM bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kofta and Cucumber Yoghurt</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/kofta_and_cucumber_yoghurt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/kofta_and_cucumber_yoghurt/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients for Kofta  1 onion, halved 1 clove garlic 600g lamb mince 1 1/4 tsp cumin seeds 3/4 tsp Ground Coriander 1 1/4 tsp paprika 1/4 tsp chilli flakes pinch salt parsley, handful  Ingredients for Cucumber Yoghurt  1 clove garlic, small parsley, handful 200 g natural yoghurt 1/2 lemon, juiced salt &amp;amp; pepper, to taste  Method for Kofta  Place coriander, cumin seeds, paprika, salt &amp;amp; chilli flakes into the TMX bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lamb Kofta Meatballs in Curry Sauce</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_kofta_meatballs_in_curry_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_kofta_meatballs_in_curry_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500g lamb mince 1 medium onion, coarsely grated 2 garlic cloves, crushed 25g (1/3 cup) fresh white breadcrumbs finely grated zest 1 lemon 3 tablespoons chopped coriander 3 tablespoons chopped mint, plus extra handful, to serve 3 tablespoons light flavoured oil 4 tablespoons korma curry paste 1 tablespoon finely chopped ginger 400g tin diced tomatoes 180ml (3/4 cup) coconut milk 1 cinnamon stick 1 red onion, finely sliced naan bread, warmed  Method   Place the mince, onion, garlic, breadcrumbs, lemon zest, coriander and mint in a large mixing bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Yoghurt Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_yoghurt_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_yoghurt_cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients for Cake  180g vegetable oil 2 eggs Zest 1 lemon 20g lemon juice 280g natural or Greek yoghurt 280g sugar 300g self-raising flour  Ingredients for Cake Syrup  120g sugar 60g lemon juice  Method for Cake  Place sugar and lemon zest in the TM bowl and mill for 10 seconds on speed9 Add remaining ingredients and mix on speed 4 for 10 seconds Place in ring cake tin and bake at 180C for 35mins  Method for Cake Syrup  Place sugar and lemon in TM bowl and cook for 3mins at 80deg on Gentle stir setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mix Berry Yoghurt Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/mix_berry_yoghurt_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/mix_berry_yoghurt_cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  125g butter, softened 2 teaspoons vanilla essence 150g raw sugar 3 eggs ¾ cup (110g) self-raising flour 1/3 cup (50g) plain flour 40g almonds 200g plain yogurt 1/3 cup (50g) frozen blueberries 1/3 cup (40g) frozen raspberries  Method  Preheat the oven to moderate (180°C).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoghurt</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/yoghurt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/yoghurt/</guid>
      <description>I use the recipe from the Every Day Cookbook (EDC) – but I personally find that recipe quite “wordy” and very confusing for beginner yoghurt makers. (I’m saying this from personal experience!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoghurt - Berries Jam</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/yoghurt_-_berries_jam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/yoghurt_-_berries_jam/</guid>
      <description>Recipe 1 - Ingredients  500g frozen berries 100g Raw Sugar or Coconut Sugar  Method  Add Frozen berries &amp;amp; sugar in TM bowl. Pulverise 8 secs speed 9, then cook for 20mins, Varoma temp, speed 1 with MC off (keep an eye as may boil up into top well, you can always drop temp to 100 degrees for a while) Once cooked transfer to a container to cool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoghurt Flavouring</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/yoghurt_flavouring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/yoghurt_flavouring/</guid>
      <description>When making any Yogurt please refer to original post for the general tips and method.  Vanilla Yoghurt (sweetened) Ingredients  1.5ltr Full Cream Milk 50g Raw Sugar 20g Vanilla Extract 100- 200ml Yoghurt Starter  Method  Simply add sugar and Vanilla during initial heating process, I have used Vanilla beans which are split to release bean flavour more, but find a lot of the vanilla is wasted as it floats, therefore when you remove any ‘skin’ during the milk cooling the Vanilla is lost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Ravioli</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_ravioli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_ravioli/</guid>
      <description>Original image caption: From website.  This delicious and delicate chicken mousse is steamed in lettuce leaves instead of pasta!
Ingredients  170g chicken breast, sinews removed, diced 30g egg white 500g whipping cream 1tsp good fine sea salt frozen peas 300g + 100g boiling water carrots, peeled and cut in chunks, cooked in lightly salted water until tender sea salt and pepper cos lettuce leaves, 1 large leaf per serving  Method - Chicken Mousse  Chop the chicken 6 seconds/Speed 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soya Bean Milk</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/soya_bean_milk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/soya_bean_milk/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  100 grams dried soya beans soaked in water overnight or at least 6 hours, (change the soaking water at least once and do a final rinse with fresh water 1 litre water 60 grams Chinese rock sugar or raw sugar 2-3 pandan leaves, (optional)  Method  Place drained beans and 500 grams of water into Closed lid and cook for 6 minutes at 80 degrees counter-clockwise operation on speed 1-2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple and Blueberry Jalousie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/apple_and_blueberry_jalousie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/apple_and_blueberry_jalousie/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Apple and blueberry jalousie 1224px.jpg Original image caption: Taken on 24/08/2013.  Ingredients  400g can pie apple, drained 125g fresh blueberries 1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon 2 1/2 tablespoons caster sugar 2 sheets frozen ready-rolled puff pastry, halved 2 tablespoons almond meal (ground almonds) 1 egg, lightly beaten Icing sugar mixture and whipped cream, to serve  Method  Preheat oven to 200°C/180°C fan-forced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheesy Gnocchi Bolognaise</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheesy_gnocchi_bolognaise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheesy_gnocchi_bolognaise/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 tablespoon olive oil 1 brown onion, finely chopped 2 garlic cloves, crushed 750g lean beef mince 600ml bottle Italian tomato pasta sauce 625g packet fresh gnocchi 150g grated cheese  Method  Preheat oven to 200°C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermomix Pizza Dough</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thermomix_pizza_dough/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thermomix_pizza_dough/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Thermomix_pizza_dough.jpg Original image caption: From website. (Serving suggestion)  Ingredients  280 g. water or milk (or combination thereof) 1 tbsp granulated yeast (instant or regular) 25 g.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft Chinese Bread Rolls</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/soft_chinese_bread_rolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/soft_chinese_bread_rolls/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Soft_chinese_bread_rolls.jpg Original image caption: Taken on 22/06/2013.  Ingredients Roux  150g water 30g baker&amp;rsquo;s flour  Remaining dough  380g baker&amp;rsquo;s flour 210g water 3 tsp dried yeast 2 tbsp powdered milk (optional) 1 tsp salt 40g sugar 30g oil or butter  Method  Place water and flour for the roux into TM bowl and cook for 3 minutes at 70°C on speed 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lasagne</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lasagne/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lasagne/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Lasagne_1.jpg Original image caption: Taken on 15/06/2013.  Ingredients  3 eggs 300g plain flour 1 tbsp extra virgin olive oil  Method  Place all ingredients into TM bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Almond Tea</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_almond_tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_almond_tea/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  100g Chinese almonds (sweet - South Almonds) 1 tablespoon Chinese almonds (bitter - North almonds) (Mine are premixed, so I just used 100g of my mix) 10g white rice (original recipe states 20g, just adjust the amount for the desired thickness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hokkaido Milk Toast</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hokkaido_milk_toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hokkaido_milk_toast/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients   270g bread flour
  45g castor sugar
  pinch of salt
  5g non-dairy creamer powder or milk powder
  5g dried yeast</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft &amp; Fluffy Bread (TangZhong Method)</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/soft_fluffy_bread_tangzhong_method/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/soft_fluffy_bread_tangzhong_method/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients for TangZhong  50g bread flour 125g milk 125g water  Method for TangZhong  Place all ingredients in the Thermomix and cook at 70°C, speed 2, 10-15 minutes until the mixture becomes a paste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pizza Bianca with Potato and Rosemary</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pizza_bianca_with_potato_and_rosemary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pizza_bianca_with_potato_and_rosemary/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Pizza_bianca_with_potato_and_rosemary.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Pizza dough  Place water and yeast into mixing bowl and heat 1 min/37°C/speed 1. Add flour and salt and mix 6 sec/speed 6 then knead 1½ min//.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef with Oyster Sauce</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beef_with_oyster_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beef_with_oyster_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients for Marinade  1/2 teaspoon baking soda 1 teaspoon sugar 1 tablespoon cornflour 1 tablespoon soy sauce 3 tablespoons water 2 tablespoons vegetable oil  Ingredients  500g (1lb) lean beef (scotch or fillet) 8 tablespoons oil 500g broccoli, cut into small pieces 2 teaspoons rice wine 1/2 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon sugar 3 spring onions, cut into 2cm lengths 15 slices fresh ginger 2 tablespoons oyster sauce 1 tablespoon water 1 teaspoon sugar 1/2 teaspoon cornflour 1/2 teaspoon sesame oil  Method  Slice the beef very thinly into 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Rice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spanish_rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spanish_rice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 tablespoons oil 2 tablespoons chopped onion 1 teaspoon crushed garlic 1 cup rice 1 3/4 cup chicken stock 1 cup tinned tomatoes ¼ cup peas ¼ cup corn  Method    Heat oil in a large, non-stick saucepan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garlic Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/garlic_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/garlic_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  8 chicken wings or 8 pieces of chicken 4 tbsp olive oil 4-6 cloves garlic 1tsp flour a large glass of white wine 50 ml chicken stock salt 1 tbsp chopped fresh parsley a few strands of saffron a few whole peppercorns  Method  Heat the oil in a frying pan add the chicken wings or pieces and garlic cloves and fry until the garlic turns golden and the chicken brown Remove the whole garlic cloves and set aside Pour the wine into the frying pan and stir whilst adding the flour and a pinch of salt Add the chicken stock and cover and simmer for 15 mins on a low heat In a mortar make a paste using the whole garlic cloves, parsley, saffron and a few peppercorns Add the paste to the frying pan then cover and simmer for another 15 mins  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spanish Omelette</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spanish_omelette/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spanish_omelette/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Spanish_omelette.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Ingredients  1 medium sebago potato 1 tablespoon olive oil 20g butter 1 medium red onion, thinly sliced 4 eggs 2 tablespoons chopped flat-leaf parsley salad, to serve  Method  Prick potato all over with a fork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta Neapolitan</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pasta_neapolitan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pasta_neapolitan/</guid>
      <description>Original image caption: From the pasta man atthe market  Filling Ingredients  5 medium tomatos 2 cloves garlic, sliced, not crushed 1 small onion, sliced 1cup basil leaves 1/4cup white wine 1 packet (525g) of fresh pasta 100g ricotta cheese (from deli)*Parmesan cheese Butter salt &amp;amp; pepper  Sauce Method  Cut tomatos in quarters and put into a bowl of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nutella Mug Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nutella_mug_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nutella_mug_cake/</guid>
      <description> Original image filename: Nutella mug cake.jpg Original image caption: Mmm&amp;hellip; this is definitely one for the cookbook!
(Taken on 12/04/13)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Umami Paste</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/umami_paste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/umami_paste/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  300g Roma tomatoes, cubed 90g Parmesan, cubed 80g toasted walnuts 5g Dulse sea vegetable, flakes (available online here; http://www.seaveg.co.uk/dulse.html) 5g good Balsamic vinegar 2-3 anchovy fillets  Method  Place tomatoes into Thermomix bowl and cook for 10 min/100°C/Reverse + speed 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beetroot Muffins with Cream Cheese Icing</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beetroot_muffins_with_cream_cheese_icing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beetroot_muffins_with_cream_cheese_icing/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Beetroot_muffins_with_cream_cheese_icing.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Ingredients for Muffins  200g cooked mashed beetroot 125g butter 120g caster sugar 3 eggs (room temperature) 120g milk / buttermilk / cream 240g self-raising flour 1 teaspoon ground ginger ½ cup chopped almonds or walnuts (optional)  Ingredients for Cream Cheese Icing  125g Cream Cheese 60g sugar Juice of one lemon  Method for Muffins  Pre-heat oven to 180 degrees and prepare approximately 18 hole muffin tins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salted Caramel Ice Cream</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/salted_caramel_ice_cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/salted_caramel_ice_cream/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Salted caramel ice cream 2.jpg Original image caption: Taken on 16/03/2013.  Ingredients  250g raw sugar (Note: Too sweet. Reduce to 200g next time. Tried again on 29/09/13.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana, Oat and Spelt Pancakes</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/banana_oat_and_spelt_pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/banana_oat_and_spelt_pancakes/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Banana_oat_and_spelt_pancakes.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Ingredients  2 ripe bananas, quartered 10g coconut oil (liquefied) 1 tbsp golden flaxseeds (linseeds) 140g whole oats 120g wholemeal spelt flour 1 pinch salt 40-50g Raw caster sugar 1/2 tsp bicarb soda 1 tsp baking powder 1 large egg 2 MC of low-fat natural or vanilla yoghurt 2 MC of skim milk 2 tsp vanilla bean paste or extract sliced fresh fruit of choice (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Roast Potatoes Ever</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/best_roast_potatoes_ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/best_roast_potatoes_ever/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Best_roast_potatoes_ever.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Ingredients  1kg potatoes peeled and quartered rock salt fresh mixed herbs cold pressed olive oil 500g water  Method  Peel all the potatoes and cut into quarters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken and Leek Pie</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_and_leek_pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_and_leek_pie/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Chicken_leek_pie.jpeg Original image caption: From website.  Filling Ingredients  1 tablespoon (20g) olive oil 400g Skinless chicken breast,diced 100g lean shortcut bacon, diced 90g pieces thinly sliced leek 1 clove garlic 1 tablespoon (20g) butter 1 tablespoon plain flour 75g chicken stock (I use a 1/3 cup of water with half a tablespoon of tmx chicken stock paste) 75g white wine 75g cream salt and pepper to taste 1/4 teaspoon nutmeg (optional) 20g chedder cheese, grated  Pie Crust Ingredients  8 portion puff pastry Ready Rolled or Page 121 of the EveryDay Cookbook  Filling Method  Add leeks and garlic clove to TM bowl, chop 5sec/Speed 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken with 40 cloves of garlic</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_with_40_cloves_of_garlic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_with_40_cloves_of_garlic/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Chicken_with_40_cloves_of_garlic.jpg  Ingredients  1 organic chicken, chopped into pieces 40 cloves of garlic, unpeeled 1/2 cup white wine or Verjuice or apple juice or chicken stock (I usually use a mixture of apple juice and chicken stock) 3 Tablespoons extra virgin olive oil fresh thyme (or 1 teaspoon dried thyme) fresh sage, chopped finely (or 1/2 teaspoon dried sage) fresh parsley, chopped finely 4 small bay leaves 1 teaspoon herb salt &amp;amp; some freshly ground pepper (may need more salt if using apple juice)  Method  Scatter 40 garlic cloves over the bottom of a casserole dish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Date and Pecan Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/date_and_pecan_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/date_and_pecan_cake/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Date_and_pecan_cake.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Ingredients  375g pitted dates 375g water 1 tablespoon coffee 2/3 cup coconut 30 pecans  Method  Place dates, water and coffee into TM bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honey Mustard Chicken Parcels</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/honey_mustard_chicken_parcels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/honey_mustard_chicken_parcels/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Honey_mustard_chicken_parcels.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Ingredients  600g chicken diced 1 onion halved 20g wholegrain mustard 1/2 tablespoon Vegetable stock paste 30g honey 20g flour 100g water 150ml cream 30g olive oil 1 package puff pastry 2 carrots  Method   Put onion and carrot in TM bowl and chop for 5 seconds at Speed 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pineapple Tarts</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pineapple_tarts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pineapple_tarts/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Pineapple_tarts.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Filling Ingredients  1kg fresh pineapple,roughly chopped 300g sugar 1 cinnamon quill 4 cloves  Pastry Ingredients  250 g plain flour 1 egg, plus extra for brushing 120g unsalted butter pinch salt  Filing Method  Place pineapple into TM bowl and chop 3 sec/speed 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steamed Whole Chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/steamed_whole_chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/steamed_whole_chicken/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Steamed_whole_chicken.jpg Original image caption: Mmmm&amp;hellip; YUMMY!  Ingredients  1 whole chicken onion lemon garlic ginger  Method  Stuff chicken with onion, lemon, galic and ginger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato Sauce (Paste)</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tomato_sauce_paste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tomato_sauce_paste/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  50g extra virgin olive oil 2 cloves garlic 1 small onion 1 small carrot 1kg tomatoes or lkg tinned tomatoes ( 3 x 400g cans) 30g sugar 1 tbspn TM stock concentrate Salt and Pepper A few basil leaves  Method   Add onion, garlic, and carrot to TM bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Osso Buco</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/osso_buco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/osso_buco/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Osso_buco.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Ingredients  8 x 200g osso buco (veal shin) sea salt and cracked black pepper plain (all-purpose) flour, for dusting ¼ cup (60ml) olive oil 1 brown onion, chopped 2 cloves garlic, crushed ⅓ cup (90g) tomato paste 2 cups (500ml) red wine 2 cups (500ml) beef stock hot buttered toast, to serve chopped parsley leaves, to serve  Method  Heat a large deep frying pan over medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snack Sticks</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/snack_sticks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/snack_sticks/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 cup of grated tasty cheese (if using - can be grated first in Thermomix) 230g spelt flour (w/meal, white, or mixture) 1/2 tsp salt 1/2 tsp mustard powder (opt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luxurious Homemade Moisturiser</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/luxurious_homemade_moisturiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/luxurious_homemade_moisturiser/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Luxurious_homemade_moisturiser.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Ingredients  130g apricot oil 260g macadamia oil 50g beeswax pellets or a block of beeswax chopped up in small pieces 2 Tbspns rosewater or orange flower water (available from Chemists - although grocery store rose water essence will work too) 4 Tbspns distilled or boiled water 1/4 to 1/2 tsp lavender or rose essential oil; or orange essential oil if using orange water 1 Vitamin E capsule (squeezed out)  Method  Weigh oils and beeswax into the Thermomix bowl and cook for 15 minutes at 60C, speed 2, or until all the beeswax is melted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Fondants</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_fondants/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate_fondants/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Chocolate_fondants.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Ingredients  180g dark chocolate (mon 50% cocoa), broken into pieces 180 g butter , roughly chopped 2 eggs 2 egg yolks 40g plain flour 80g sugar vanilla ice cream (see tips), to serve Fresh strawberries, to serve icing sugar, to dust  [To Try](/Category/To Try) Desserts</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dairy-Free Ice Cream</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/dairy-free_ice_cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/dairy-free_ice_cream/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  100g raw cashews 100g ice Vanilla bean paste A little pure maple syrup  Method  Grind up 100g raw cashews to powder. Add 100g ice and grind top speed until pulverised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dairy-Free Spelt Scones</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/dairy-free_spelt_scones/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/dairy-free_spelt_scones/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Dairy_free_spelt_scones.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Ingredients  440g plain spelt flour 4tsp baking powder 1/2tsp fine sea salt 60g olive oil 230g rice-almond milk or other milk substitute 1 tsp apple cider vinegar (optional)  Method  Preheat oven to 220°C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nectarine Ice Cream</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nectarine_ice_cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nectarine_ice_cream/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  400g ice 100g raw cashews or blanched almonds 2 frozen bananas 2 fresh, ripe nectarines 10 drops vanilla stevia liquid (orother liquid sweetwner to taste woth some vanilla extract)  Method   Grind up 400g ice for 10 secs sp 9 (or until fine).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nut-Free Chocolate Spread</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nut-free_chocolate_spread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nut-free_chocolate_spread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  100g dark dairy free chocolate (eg Green &amp;amp; Black&amp;rsquo;s 70% cocoa choc) 30g coconut oil (or ghee or butter) 30g rice malt syrup (or honey) 100g thick coconut cream (eg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spicy BBQ Chicken All-in-One Dinner</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spicy_bbq_chicken_all-in-one_dinner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spicy_bbq_chicken_all-in-one_dinner/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Spicy_BBQ_chicken_all_in_one_dinner.jpg  Sauce Ingredients  2 cloves garlic 80g tomato sauce 60g apple cider vinegar 30g butter, ghee or oil 2 tsp seeded or Dijon mustard 2 Tbspns Tamari 2 Tbspns lemon juice 20g Rapadura or 15g honey 1 tsp herb salt 1-2 tsp chilli powder 2 tsp smoked paprika  Other Ingredients  1 kg chicken thighs, fat removed 900g water 400g basmati rice or 350g quinoa (rinsed) or fill basket with thinly sliced potatoes(skin on)  Sliced Vegetables  carrots broccoli green beans red capsicum frozen peas and corn if you&amp;rsquo;re in a hurry  Method  Mince garlic in Thermomix bowl on speed 7 for 3 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thermomix &#39;Fried&#39; Rice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thermomix_fried_rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thermomix_fried_rice/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Thermomix_fried_rice.jpg  Rice  400g of raw rice (or less if you want a smaller batch) 400g coconut milk 500g water (for white or basmati rice) or 700g water (for brown rice)  Meat  100g - 200g of cubed chicken or fish and/or prawns (you can marinate it for a little while first in some soy sauce, curry powder, garlic, ginger, and honey, or whatever marinade you prefer)  Vegetables  1 sliced onion/shallots/leeks carrots, sliced or julienned celery, sliced kohlrabi, thin strips or julienned broccoli/cauliflower florets cabbage, shredded spinach/silverbeet, sliced frozen peas &amp;amp; corn cashews or slivered almonds (opt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacones</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/bacones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/bacones/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Bacones.png  The classic ice-cream cone with a porky twist!
Ingredients  1.5 kg bacon 2 L vanilla ice-cream Butcher&amp;rsquo;s string  Method  Chuck the ice-cream and 1 kg of bacon into a blender and blend thouroughly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy No-Bake Chocolate Cheesecake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/easy_no-bake_chocolate_cheesecake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/easy_no-bake_chocolate_cheesecake/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Easy_no_bake_chocolate_cheesecake.jpg  Bring a great big smile to Mum&amp;rsquo;s face with this luscious, chocolatey-everything delight. No cooking required!
Ingredients  200g Arnott’s Choc Ripple biscuits 80g butter, melted 200g dark chocolate, chopped 2 Tbsp cocoa powder 60ml hazelnut-flavoured liqueur, such as Frangelico 150ml thickened cream, at room temperature 300g cream cheese, at room temperature 150g caster sugar 200g extra dark chocolate, for decorating Extra cocoa powder, for dusting Whipped cream, to serve  Method  Line a 20cm springform cake tin with baking paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hash Browns</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hash_browns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hash_browns/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Hash Browns.jpg Original image caption: Picture taken on 26/01/2012.  Ingredients  6 medium (about 1.2kg) desiree potatoes, peeled 2 tbs plain flour 1 egg, lightly whisked Pinch of salt Vegetable oil, to shallow-fry  Method  Preheat oven to 120°C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chargrilled Pork Neck with Vermicelli Noodles</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chargrilled_pork_neck_with_vermicelli_noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chargrilled_pork_neck_with_vermicelli_noodles/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500 g pork neck, finely slice across the grain into 3mm pieces 6 white part spring onion, finely sliced &amp;amp; pounded in mortar &amp;amp; pestle to a paste 2 tablespoons sugar 1 tablespoon honey 4 tablespoons fish sauce 1 teaspoon freshly ground pepper 2 garlic cloves, finely diced 2 tablespoons vegetable oil 250 g rice vermicelli noodle (cook as packet instructions) 5 mint leaves, sliced 5 perilla leaves, sliced 5 Vietnamese mint leaves, sliced 1 Lebanese cucumber, halved &amp;amp; sliced 2 handful bean sprouts 4 tablespoons spring onion oil 4 tablespoon fried red Asian shallots 4 tablespoons crushed roasted peanuts ½ cup dipping fish sauce 12 bamboo skewers, soaked in water for 20 minutes or 12 wooden chopsticks sliced down the middle  Method  In a large mixing bowl, combine sugar, fish sauce, honey &amp;amp; pepper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chargrilled Pork Sausage Skewers (Nem Nuong)</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chargrilled_pork_sausage_skewers_nem_nuong/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chargrilled_pork_sausage_skewers_nem_nuong/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  300 g minced pork 300 g fish paste (from Asian fishmonger) 12 spring onions, sliced 2 garlic cloves, finely diced 1 tsp freshly ground pepper ½ tsp salt 1 tbsp sugar 1 tbsp fish sauce ½ cup vegetable oil 12 wooden chopsticks, soaked in water for 20 minutes 12 sheets rice paper 1 bunch perilla leaf, picked 1 bunch Vietnamese mint, picked 1 bunch mint, picked 1/2 bunch garlic chives, sliced into 5 cm legths 3 star fruit, finely sliced 1 cucumber, halves &amp;amp; finely sliced lengthways Hoisin dipping sauce 125 ml hoisin sauce 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemongrass Chilli Chicken (Ga Xao Xa Ot)</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemongrass_chilli_chicken_ga_xao_xa_ot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemongrass_chilli_chicken_ga_xao_xa_ot/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500 g chicken thigh fillets, cut into bite size pieces 3 tbsp fish sauce 1.5 tbsp sugar 2 lemon grass stalks, white part only, finely diced 4 garlic cloves, finely diced 2 long red chilli, finely diced 3 tbsp vegetable oil 1/2 onion, cut into wedges 1 cup young coconut juice 3 coriander sprigs for garnish  Method  In a mixing bowl combine fish sauce, sugar and mix until sugar has dissolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pork Spare Ribs Slow Braised in Medicinal Broth</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pork_spare_ribs_slow_braised_in_medicinal_broth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pork_spare_ribs_slow_braised_in_medicinal_broth/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Pork_spare_ribs_slow_braised_medicinal_broth.jpg  Ingredients  300 g short spare ribs, chopped into bite sizes pieces 5 g dried ginseng 5 g dried lotus seeds 5 g dried goji berries 5 g dried black prune 5 g dried lilly petals 5 g pearl barely 5 g dried raisins 5 g dried longon 5 g dried white vegetable root ½ teaspoon salt  Method  In a mixing bowl, rub the pork ribs with salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salmon Patties</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/salmon_patties/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/salmon_patties/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  500g potato, mashed 1/4 cup (60ml) hot milk 210g can red salmon 1/4 cup (20g) grated parmesan 1/4 cup (35g) plain flour 1 egg, lightly beaten 3/4 cup (50g) breadcrumb 2 tbl olive oil  Method  Mash potato with hot milk and butter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Crumble</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/apple_crumble/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/apple_crumble/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Apple_crumble.jpg Original image caption: From website.  This warming fruit dessert is quick and easy to make. We don&amp;rsquo;t like the crumble topping to go soggy, so the apple layer is moist but not watery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guacamole</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/guacamole/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/guacamole/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 parts Avocado 1 part Sour cream Sweet chilli sauce to taste Salt and cracked pepper (optional)  Method  Mix avocado and sour cream. Top with sweet chilli sauce, just a thin film.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mum&#39;s special sauce</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-special-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-special-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Good for serving with chicken and pork. Cooked version is good for steamed fish.
Ingredients  1 tbsp light soy sauce 1 tbsp dark soy sauce 1 tbsp oyster sauce 1 tsp sugar 1 tsp sesame oil Fried red onions (optional) Chopped spring onions  Method (raw version)  Mix everything together and serve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fettuccine Carbonara</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fettuccine_carbonara/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fettuccine_carbonara/</guid>
      <description>The Italian name, carbonara, comes from the word for coal. This dish is believed to have been created by coal miners, or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the black pepper on the pasta which resembles coal dust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tau yu bak</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/tau-yu-bak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/tau-yu-bak/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 kg pork collar butt, cut into large pieces 1 head garlic, separated into cloves with skin on 1 tbsp sugar 1 tbsp cooking caramel 2 tbsp light soy sauce 2 tbsp dark soy sauce Pepper 1 tsp five-spice powder (optional) Hard-boiled eggs  Method  Add garlic, sugar, cooking caramel, light soy sauce, dark soy sauce, five-spice powder and pepper to a large pot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nachos</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nachos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nachos/</guid>
      <description>Avocado Dip Ingredients  2 avacados, mashed Juice of 1 lime or 1/2 lemon 3 spirng onions, finely chopped (I used Spanish onion - Fui) 2 tbsp cream (or olive oil - I like cream best) 2 tbsp chopped coriander 1/2 tsp chilli sauce or a few drops of tabasco  Method  Combine all ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crispy Skin Chicken with Spiced Salt</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crispy_skin_chicken_with_spiced_salt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crispy_skin_chicken_with_spiced_salt/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Size 13 chicken 2 teaspoons dark soy sauce Oil, for deep frying Spiced salt 1 tablespoon coarse kitchen salt 1/4 teaspoon five spice powder  Method Step 1 Remove any fat from inside of chicken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curry puffs</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/curry-puffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/curry-puffs/</guid>
      <description>This recipe makes 72 curry puffs. Can halve or quarter the quantity to make less.
Ingredients  1.4 kg pork mince 1 kg potato, cut into 1cm cube 1 medium onion, finely chopped 2 tbsp coriander powder 2 tbsp curry powder, substitute with coriander powder for non-spicy version 2 tsp tumeric powder Salt and pepper Soy sauce (optional) 12 sheets puff pastry 2 eggs, for glazing  Method  Partially cook cubed potato in microwave oven for 10min on High with a little bit of water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese New Year cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/chinese-new-year-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 1994 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/chinese-new-year-cake/</guid>
      <description>Makes 2 cakes of a reasonable size.
Ingredients  3 x 500 g packets of glutinous rice flour 900 g sugar 6 cups warm water  Method  Fry sugar until dissolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laksa</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/laksa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 1993 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/laksa/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Pre-prepared rempah Chopped dried shrimp Coconut milk Coconut cream Bean sprouts White noodles Prawns, meat and shells separated Stuffed fried bean curd with fish meat Fish cake Fish balls Vegetables (cabbage, beans, tomato, cauliflower, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beef rendang</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/beef-rendang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 1993 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/beef-rendang/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Beef, cut into chunks 2-3 red onions Chilli Galangal Turmeric Belacan Cumin Coriander powder Coconut milk Salt Dessicated coconut  Method  Grind red onions, lemongrass, chilli, galangal, turmeric and belacan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assam chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/assam-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/assam-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Rempah  Belacan Chilli Onions Lemongrass Galangal Turmeric   Chicken pieces (can substitute with pork) Tamarind juice Tomato Sugar Mint leaves  Method  Grind rempah ingredients and fry in lots of oil until fragrant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assam fish</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/assam-fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/assam-fish/</guid>
      <description>This dish is a bit soury.
Ingredients  Rempah  Belacan Chilli Onions Lemongrass Galangal Turmeric   Tamarind paste Fish fillet Pineapple pieces  Method  Grind rempah ingredients and fry in lots of oil until fragrant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ah Tai&#39;s tau yu bak</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/ah-tais-tau-yu-bak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/ah-tais-tau-yu-bak/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Pork (fatty cut like pork belly), cut in large chunks with fat and skin Onion, finely chopped Dark soy sauce Cinnamon stick Cloves 1 star anise 2-3 cloves garlic A bit of sugar Pinch of salt  Method  Fry onion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ayam kapitan</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/ayam-kapitan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/ayam-kapitan/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Chicken pieces Pre-prepared rempah Coconut milk  Method  Marinate chicken pieces with ground rempah. Fry marinated chicken in a pot on low heat until chicken is cooked. Add in some coconut milk then serve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curry prawns</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/curry-prawns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/curry-prawns/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Pre-prepared rempah Pineapple cubes Coconut milk Coconut cream Prawns  Method  Fry rempah in lots of oil. Add pinapple cubes and coconut milk. Simmer. Add prawns and coconut cream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lo bak kor</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/lo-bak-kor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/lo-bak-kor/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  2 radishes, grated Dried shrimp, soaked then finely chopped 1 packet rice flour  Method  Fry chopped dried shrimp in a pan until crispy. Scoop some out for topping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sambal ikan bilis</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/sambal-ikan-bilis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/sambal-ikan-bilis/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Rempah  Red onions Lemongrass Galangal Turmeric Belacan Chilli powder   Tamarind paste Sugar Ikan bilis, washed and rinsed to remove salt  Method  Fry ikan bilis in oil on low heat until crisp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/tomato-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/tomato-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Chicken fillets, cut into pieces Onion, finely chopped/ground Chilli, ground Tomato Vinegar Tomato sauce Sugar  Method  Marinate chicken pieces with salt. Fry the pieces until slightly browned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vegetable curry</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/vegetable-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/vegetable-curry/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Rempah  Onion Chilli Lemongrass Galangal Turmeric Belacan Dried shrimp   Coconut milk Coconut cream Vegetables  Small tofu Fish balls Bean curd sheet Cabbage Long bean Carrot Eggplant    Method  Grind rempah ingredients together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Babika (Indonesian Cake)</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/babika_indonesian_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 1990 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/babika_indonesian_cake/</guid>
      <description>Desserts
Ingredients  1 cup glutenous rice flour 1 cup dessicated coconut 1 cup coconut milk (1/2 cup in powder form) 3/4 cup sugar 1 pinch salt 1 egg 1 tbls margarine Pandan leaves or vanilla  Method  Beat egg with sugar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownies</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/brownies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/brownies/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  200 g butter 1/2 cup cocoa 2 cups brown sugar (can be reduced to 1 3/4) 1 teaspoon imitation vanilla essence 1 cup plain flour 2 eggs  Method  Turn the oven to 180°C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Butter Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/butter_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/butter_cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  125g butter, very well softened 1 tsp vanilla extract 1 cup castor sugar 3 eggs 1 1/2 cups plain (all-purpose) flour, sifted 1/2 tsp baking powder, sifted 1/4 tsp bicarbonate of soda, sifted 1/2 cup milk  Methods  Preheat the oven to 150 deg C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate-Chip Cookies</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate-chip_cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chocolate-chip_cookies/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  175g butter, softened 3/4 cup brown sugar 1/2 cup caster sugar 1 egg 1 tsp vanilla essence 2 cup plain flour, sifted 1 tsp baking powder 1 pinch salt 1 cup chocolate chips  Method  Pre-heat the oven to 180°C and line two baking trays with baking paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coconut Tarts</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/coconut_tarts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/coconut_tarts/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  6 tbl butter 1/2 cup sugar 1 egg 2 tbl milk 1 1/2 cup coconut  Method  Mix all the ingredients. Bake at 200°C for 25 minutes.  Notes  Use short crust pastry shells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congee</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/congee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/congee/</guid>
      <description>Winnie&amp;rsquo;s simplified version  Add 200g rice to TMX bowl and mill for 5 secs/sp 9. Add a small piece of roughly chopped ginger. Mill again for 5 secs/sp 9. Scrape down sides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coriander chicken</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/coriander-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/coriander-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 kg chicken thigh fillets 2 cloves crushed garlic Salt and pepper to taste 1 tbsp soy sauce 2 tbsp coriander powder 1 tsp turmeric powder  Method  Marinate chicken in rest of the ingredients for at least 2 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creme Caramel</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creme_caramel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creme_caramel/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Creme_caramel_2.jpg   Preheat the oven to 150 deg C. Place the sugar and water in a saucepan over low heat and stir until the sugar is dissolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lo mai gai</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/lo-mai-gai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/lo-mai-gai/</guid>
      <description>Note to self: look up non-Bessemer method
Ingredients  1 tbsp oil 1 onion, finely chopped 1 clove garlic, finely chopped Dried prawns, pre-soaked in water Dried shiitake mushrooms, pre-soaked in water, finely chopped Minced meat or sliced meat Soy sauce Oyster sauce Salt Lup chong Glutinous rice Equal volume of water to rice Small chicken thigh strips  Method (Bessemer version)  Soak glutinous rice in water for at least 2 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melting Moments</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/melting_moments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/melting_moments/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  175g butter, softened 1/4 cup icing sugar 1 tsp vanilla extract 1 cup plain (all-purpose) flour, sifted 1/4 cup cornflour (cornstarch), sifted  Filling  60g butter, softened 1 cup icing sugar 2 tsp lemon juice 2 tsp finely grated lemon rind  Method  Preheat the oven to 180 deg C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanna&#39;s steamed eggs</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/nannas-steamed-eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/nannas-steamed-eggs/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  5 eggs 1 cup mince 2½ cup warm water Chives Seasoning (light soy)  Method  Mix everything together in a dish. Microwave on high for 10 minutes.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Okonomiyaki</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/okonomiyaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/okonomiyaki/</guid>
      <description>Ingrediients  400 grams cabbage (~half a small head) 60 grams scallions (~2 scallions), thinly sliced 1 carrot 10 grams katsuobushi 140 grams flour - all-purpose (~1 cup) 2 large eggs 1/2 cup dashi or cold water 9 slices bacon Okonomiyaki sauce Mayonnaise  Method  Remove the core and tough parts of the stems from the cabbage and shred it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peppermint Creams</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/peppermint_creams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/peppermint_creams/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 egg white 350g white icing sugar + extra for shaping 3 drops peppermint essence 2 drops green food colouring 125g dark chocolate, broken into peices  Method  Whisk the egg white until frothy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poppy Seed Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/poppy_seed_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/poppy_seed_cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1/3 cup (50g) poppy seeds 3/4 cup milk 185g butter 2 tsp vanilla essence 1 cup castor sugar 3 eggs 2 cup self-raising flour  Method  Grease a 14cm x 21cm loaf pan, line base and sides with paper; grease paper well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pringles</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pringles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pringles/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1 c warm water ( note: needs double ) 1/4 tsp salt 1 c instant mashed potatoes (powdered kind works better than the flake or pearl kind) 1 c rice flour 1 Tbsp cornstarch 1/4 tsp of baking powder Peanut or coconut oil for deep frying  Instructions  Dissolve the salt in the water, then add to dry ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortbread</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/shortbread/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/shortbread/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  220g chilled butter, chopped 2/3 cup caster (superfine) sugar 2 cups plain (all-purpose) flour 1/2 cup rice flour 1 tsp vanilla extract 1 egg  Method  Preheat the oven to 160 deg C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow Peas</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/snow_peas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/snow_peas/</guid>
      <description>*DO NOT MICROWAVE.
  &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-size:5em&amp;quot;&amp;gt;👺&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;**</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teriyaki Sauce</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/teriyaki_sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/teriyaki_sauce/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  1/2 cup soy sauce 1/2 cup mirin 2 tbls sugar  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thai Fish Cake</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thai_fish_cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thai_fish_cake/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  225g salmon fillet 3 tbls Grand Palace red curry paste 2 tbls fish sauce 1 egg 3 tbls cornstarch 1/4 tsp baking soda 6 kaffir lime leaves, sliced very thin (or use basil leaves) 3 cup oil for deep frying Garnishes: Green leaf lettuce, cucumber, sliced tomatoes  Method  Remove all bones from fish and slice the meat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thai Spareribs</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thai_spareribs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thai_spareribs/</guid>
      <description>Original image filename: Thai_spareribs.jpg Original image caption: From website.  Ingredients  6 lbs spareribs, cut into 2 rib portions boiling water 2 large lemongrass, stalks 1/2 cup soy sauce 6 tablespoons soy sauce 1/2 cup brown sugar (packed) 1/2 cup dry sherry or 1/2 cup sake 2 tablespoons peanut sauce (Thai) 2 tablespoons sesame oil 4 large garlic cloves, peeled 1 1/2 inches piece fresh ginger, peeled, chopped 3/4 cup unsweetened coconut milk  Method  Preheat oven to 350°F Arrange ribs in single layer in large roasting pan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Gooey Caramel Brownie Mug Cake Sundae</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/the_ultimate_gooey_caramel_brownie_mug_cake_sundae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/the_ultimate_gooey_caramel_brownie_mug_cake_sundae/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Cake  2 tablespoons unsalted butter (30g) 2 tablespoons chocolate chips (half bittersweet and half semisweet) 1/8 teaspoon salt 2 tablespoons all-purpose flour 1/4 teaspoon baking powder 1 large egg 1/2 teaspoon vanilla extract 1/2 teaspoon instant espresso powder 2 tablespoons sugar 1 tablespoon unsweetened cocoa powder 1 square of your favorite dark chocolate bar  Topping (optional)  3 Werther’s Original® Baking Caramels 2 teaspoons milk melted chocolate chips vanilla bean ice cream or gelato crushed toasted nuts crushed cookie whipped cream  Method   NOTE (from website): I used a big espresso mug for this cake, but you can use any regular size coffee mug that’s microwave safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turmeric rice</title>
      <link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/turmeric-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/turmeric-rice/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  3 cups rice (rice measuring cup, not metric cup) 3 tablespoons coconut cream powder ½ teaspoon turmeric powder Pinch salt  Method  Wash rice. Add enough water for the quantity of rice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
