<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Main on Lam Family Cookbook</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/categories/main/</link><description>Recent content in Main on Lam Family Cookbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jarodl.am/cookbook/categories/main/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lo mai gai</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/lo-mai-gai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/lo-mai-gai/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 metric cups glutinous rice 2 pieces lup chong, sliced ⅓ cup dried shrimp, re-hydrated in water then finely chopped ~10 dried shiitake mushrooms, re-hydrated then thickly sliced 3 chicken thigh fillets, cut into large cubes 1 onion, diced 1 clove garlic, crushed Fried onion Sauce (for chicken and rice): Light soy sauce Dark soy sauce Oyster sauce Cooking caramel Sesame oil Pepper Method Rinse then soak glutinous rice in water for at least 2 hours.</description></item><item><title>Dad's pork crackling</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/dads-pork-crackling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/dads-pork-crackling/</guid><description>Ingredients Pork belly Salt Oil (olive oil or similar) Five-spice powder (optional) Method A few days beforehand, place the pork belly on a plate and rub a generous amount of salt onto the skin.</description></item><item><title>Egg rolls</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/egg-rolls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/egg-rolls/</guid><description>Ingredients Omelette 3 eggs Salt Pepper Sesame oil Filling Pork mince Spring onion Crushed garlic Soy sauce Cooking wine Oyster sauce Sesame oil Pepper Corn flour or egg (for binding) Sugar Method Mix the filling ingredients in a mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>Son-in-law eggs</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/son-in-law-eggs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/son-in-law-eggs/</guid><description>Called &amp;ldquo;kai look koei&amp;rdquo; in Thai. Mum learned this in a Thai cooking class decades ago. This recipe is from her old recipe notes.
Ingredients 6 eggs, hard boiled 3 tbsp oil 2 tbsp chopped onion 3 tbsp brown sugar 2 tsp fish sauce 2 tbsp vinegar Fresh chilli and coriander to garnish Method Cover bottom of pan with oil and fry the halved eggs yolk side down.</description></item><item><title>Stuffed eggplant</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stuffed-eggplant/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stuffed-eggplant/</guid><description>Ingredients Eggplant Filling Pork mince Spring onion Crushed garlic Soy sauce Cooking wine Oyster sauce Sesame oil Pepper Corn flour or egg (for binding) Sugar Sauce 2 tbsp corn flour Oyster sauce Sesame oil Water Sugar, garlic, five spice (optional) Method Mix the filling ingredients in a mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>Stuffed mushroom</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stuffed-mushroom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stuffed-mushroom/</guid><description>Ingredients Dried shiitake mushrooms Filling Pork mince Spring onion Crushed garlic Soy sauce Cooking wine Oyster sauce Sesame oil Pepper Corn flour or egg (for binding) Sugar Marinade Five spice powder Salt Pepper Sesame oil Cooking wine Soy sauce (not too much, the mushrooms are already salty) Sauce 2 tbsp corn flour Oyster sauce Sesame oil Water Sugar, garlic, five spice (optional) Method Mix the filling ingredients in a mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>Sweet corn soup</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/sweet-corn-soup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/sweet-corn-soup/</guid><description>Mum&amp;rsquo;s classic sweet corn soup recipe.
Ingredients 1 can corn kernels 1 can creamed corn Finely diced chicken Soup seasoning (dashi, salt, pepper, sesame oil, etc.), adjust according to available ingredients 1 tsp corn flour (approx) 1 egg Method Boil about 1 cup water in pot.</description></item><item><title>Mum's mapo tofu</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-mapo-tofu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-mapo-tofu/</guid><description>This recipe was adapted by Mum from cousins' grandpa who used to run a Taiwanese restaurant.
Ingredients 1 pack soft tofu Minced pork Diced onion Crushed garlic and ginger Sliced chilli Method Cut soft tofu into diamonds and soak in water.</description></item><item><title>Mum's Malaysian curry</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-malaysian-curry/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-malaysian-curry/</guid><description>Ingredients Aromatics Chopped onion Garlic and ginger Curry/kaffir lime leaves Lemongrass, bruised Curry powder+water paste Whole chicken, chopped Potato, chopped Coconut cream Method Fry aromatics in a deep pot.</description></item><item><title>Stir fried kang kung</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stir-fried-kang-kung/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/stir-fried-kang-kung/</guid><description>Method Fry aromatics: Diced onion Garlic and ginger Shrimps Cut chilli Add kang kung Fry until wilted, add salt and pepper and sesame oil to taste</description></item><item><title>Hokkien noodles</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/hokkien-noodles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/hokkien-noodles/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 packet (~1 kg) Hokkien noodles Chicken thigh fillets, roughly chopped Soy sauce Oyster sauce Sesame oil Cooking caramel (karamel masakan) Bok choy, leaves and stems separated, stems cut in half.</description></item><item><title>Three Cup Chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/three_cup_chicken/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/three_cup_chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 lb chicken drumsticks 1 tablespoon baking soda, to tenderize the chicken, optional 2 tablespoons dark sesame oil or toasted sesame oil 2-inch piece old ginger, peeled and cut into thin pieces 6 cloves garlic, peeled 1 1/2 tablespoons soy sauce 1 1/2 tablespoons dark sweet soy sauce (kecap manis) 1 1/2 tablespoons Shaoxing wine A big bunch Thai basil leaves Method Cut the chicken into pieces and rub them with the baking soda.</description></item><item><title>ShaoXing Wine Chicken Thigh and Chinese Sausage Claypot Rice</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/shaoxing_wine_chicken_thigh_and_chinese_sausage_claypot_rice/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/shaoxing_wine_chicken_thigh_and_chinese_sausage_claypot_rice/</guid><description>Ingredients 4 chicken thighs, about 3/4 lb each 1 cup long grain rice, uncooked 2 Chinese sausage, thinly sliced on the diagonal 1 pack enoki mushrooms, about 7oz, wash and separated 1 scallion, chopped Ingredients for the Chicken Thigh Marinade 2 tbsp Shaoxing wine 1 tsp fish sauce 2 tsp soy sauce 1/2 tsp sugar 1/2 tsp white pepper 1/2 tsp garlic granule 1/2 tsp salt 2 tsp oil Ingredients for the Sauce 4 tsp sesame oil 4 tsp soy sauce 2 tsp sugar 2 tsp water 2 tsp fish sauce Method In a large bowl, combine the ingredients for the chicken thigh marinade (Shaoxing wine, fish sauce, soy sauce, sugar, white pepper, garlic granule, salt, and oil).</description></item><item><title>Naan Bread</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/naan_bread/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/naan_bread/</guid><description>Ingredients 200g milk 1 egg, lightly beaten 2 tbl olive oil (can use ghee to be authentic) 80g Greek yoghurt 30g fresh yeast or 2tsp dried yeast 550-560g Lacke bakers flour 1tsp baking powder 1tsp sugar Pinch Pink salt flakes Method Combine milk, egg, oil, yoghurt and yeast in Thermo bowl and blend 3 sec/speed 7.</description></item><item><title>Tandoori Chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tandoori_chicken/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/tandoori_chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 tbl cumin seeds 1 tbl coriander seeds 1 tsp black pepercorns 3 tbl paprika 1 tsp cayenne pepper 2 tbl tumeric 2 cloves of garlic 2 red chillies, deseeded 100g onion 2 tbl Extra Virgin Olive Oil 15g ginger, peeled 30g lime juice, fresh 70g tomato paste 80g greek yoghurt sea salt to taste 4-6 piece chicken maryland Method Place cumin, coriander, peppercorns, paprika, cayenne &amp;amp; turmeric into Thermomix bowl &amp;amp; dry roast 10 min/Varoma/speed 2.</description></item><item><title>Creamy Chicken Pasta Bake</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamy_chicken_pasta_bake/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamy_chicken_pasta_bake/</guid><description>Ingredients 250g dried maccheroni pasta (see note) 4 cooked chicken drumsticks (refer Honey &amp;amp; Mustard Roasted Chicken Drumsticks) 100g baby spinach leaves 300ml light thickened cream 3/4 cup semi-dried tomatoes 1 1/2 cups grated parmesan cheese 1 cup grated mozzarella cheese Method Preheat oven to 200C.</description></item><item><title>Crispy Oven Baked French Fries</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crispy_oven_baked_french_fries/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crispy_oven_baked_french_fries/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 medium russet potatoes course salt 1 Tbl oil Method Start with a couple of medium russet potatoes. Preheat oven to 425 convection. Peal potatoes if desired.</description></item><item><title>Honey and Mustard Roasted Chicken Drumsticks</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/honey_and_mustard_roasted_chicken_drumsticks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/honey_and_mustard_roasted_chicken_drumsticks/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tablespoons extra-light olive oil 1/4 cup honey 1 tablespoon wholegrain mustard 1 orange, juiced 12 chicken drumsticks 450g orange sweet potato, peeled, cut into 2cm pieces 450g desiree potatoes, peeled, cut into 2cm pieces 100g baby spinach leaves Method Preheat oven to 240°C.</description></item><item><title>Oven Baked Chicken Legs</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/oven_baked_chicken_legs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/oven_baked_chicken_legs/</guid><description>Ingredients 5-6 drumsticks (about 1.5 ibs) Spices - salt, pepper, garlic powder Method Preheat oven to 425 deg F (220 deg C). Pat dry with paper towels. Trim off any extra skin and loose join pieces.</description></item><item><title>Roast Pumpkin</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/roast_pumpkin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/roast_pumpkin/</guid><description>Method Choose a firm, small pie pumpkin, not more than 3-4 pounds; smaller pumpkins tend to be a bit sweeter. Rinse the pumpkin under warm water, removing any dirt or debris Cut the pumpkin in half on a large cutting board, with a sharp knife Scoop out the seeds with a metal spoon, I use an old measuring spoon that has a nice edge.</description></item><item><title>Basic Crepes</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/basic_crepes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/basic_crepes/</guid><description>Ingredients 5 eggs 500g plain flour 1 litre skim milk 3 tbl oil 1/2 glass of beer Method Pour half of the flour in a big bowl. Add eggs, one at a time.</description></item><item><title>Pumpkin Gratin with Parmesan</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pumpkin_gratin_with_parmesan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pumpkin_gratin_with_parmesan/</guid><description>Ingredients Butter (for the dish) 1 (4- to 5-pound) sugar pumpkin, stemmed and halved from stem to stern Salt and pepper, to taste 2 teaspoons flour 2 teaspoons fresh thyme leaves 1 egg 1¼ cups heavy cream ½ cup milk 1 cup freshly grated Parmesan Extra Parmesan (for sprinkling) Method Set the oven at 400 degrees.</description></item><item><title>Basil and Lime Chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/basil_and_lime_chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/basil_and_lime_chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 garlic 15g fresh basil 10g lime juice (1 lime) you can add zest also 1 tbsp Worcestershire sauce 1 tbsp soy sauce 1 tsp Dijon mustard 1 tsp jalepenos (more if you wish) 20g oil 4-8 chicken thighs sliced thick Vegetables of choice (snow peas, cabbage, zucchini, capsicum) Method Add all ingredients (except chicken and vegetables) to the bowl and blitz on Speed 6 for 20 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Beef and Feta Gozleme</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beef_and_feta_gozleme/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beef_and_feta_gozleme/</guid><description>Ingredients - dough 250g low fat (or non fat) Greek Yoghurt 300g Self Raising Flour Pinch of Salt Method - dough Place all ingredients into the bowl and knead for 1 minute on Interval.</description></item><item><title>Best Ever Beef Pie</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/best_ever_beef_pie/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/best_ever_beef_pie/</guid><description>Original image filename: Best_ever_beef_pie.jpg Ingredients 2 onions peeled and halved 2 garlic cloves 20g oil 30g balsamic vinegar 1 heaped tsp cumin powder 1 heaped tsp smoked paprika 1kg Gravy Beef diced 80g tomato paste 40g plain flour 50g Worcestershire sauce 30g balsamic vinegar 1 beef stock cube (or 1tbsp TMX Veg Stock) 200g water Salt and pepper to taste NOTE: THE DOUBLE UP ON THE BALSAMIC VINEGAR IS NOT A MISTAKE ITS HOW I DO IT.</description></item><item><title>Butter Chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/butter_chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/butter_chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 Onion 1 inch of ginger 4 cloves of garlic 1 red chilli 20g oil 80-100g tandoori paste 200g yoghurt (non fat greek) 170g tomato paste 1 tab of ground almonds or cashews 750g-1kg chicken thigh diced Method Add onion, ginger, garlic, chilli to the bowl and chop for 5sec on Speed 7 Add oil and sauté for 3 min 100degrees, speed 1 Add ground nuts, tandoori paste, tomato paste, yoghurt and mix for 10 sec speed 7 Add chicken and cook for 20 min, 100 degrees, reverse, speed soft</description></item><item><title>Caramel Chicken Noodles</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/caramel_chicken_noodles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/caramel_chicken_noodles/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 onion peeled and halved 20g ginger 15g garlic ½ red chilli (optional) 20g oil 60g brown sugar 60g rice wine vinegar 70g soy sauce 1 tsp salt 30g TMX stock 350g water 2 tbsp corn flour mixed in some water 6 chicken thighs trimmed and diced Vegetables for steaming (snow peas, carrot, broccoli, capsicum) 350g packet noodles Method Add onion ginger, garlic and chilli (if using) to bowl and chop on Speed 6 for 3 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Chicken and Chick Pea Rissoles</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_and_chick_pea_rissoles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_and_chick_pea_rissoles/</guid><description>Ingredients 500g chicken breast diced 2 spring onions 1 handful of fresh parsley 1 garlic clove 1 tin of chick peas rinsed and drained 100g breadcrumbs 50g EDC dukkah Method Add onions, parsley and garlic to the bowl and chop on Speed 7 for 3 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Chicken and Whatever Vege Pie</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_and_whatever_vege_pie/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_and_whatever_vege_pie/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 leek chopped 1 garlic clove Handful of parsley 500g diced chicken 500g sweet potato 500g water 70g plain flour 50g wholegrain mustard 50g vegetable stock or chicken stock paste 100g cream Big pinch of thyme Broccoli Spinach leaves 2-3 medium potatoes sliced thin and drizzled in oil 1 qty EDC shortcrust pastry Method Add leek, garlic and parsley to bowl and chop on Speed 6 for 3 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Chicken, Leek and Roast Pumpkin Strudel</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_leek_and_roast_pumpkin_strudel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_leek_and_roast_pumpkin_strudel/</guid><description>Ingredients 500g cubed pre-roasted pumpkin ½ a shredded roast chicken 1 leek sliced 1 clove garlic Sliced green onion tops 50g butter 1 puff pastry sheet 250g cheese 50g flour 1tsp quirky’s chicken stock paste or TMX vege stock 200g milk Method Add garlic to TMX bowl with and chop for 5 seconds at Speed 7 Add leek and butter and sauté for 4 minutes at 100 degrees Speed 1 Add flour, milk, stock paste and cheese and cook for 10 minutes at 90 deg on Speed 3.</description></item><item><title>Chinese Fried Chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_fried_chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chinese_fried_chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 500g chicken breasts sliced (can also be made with chicken wings) 1 small onion peeled and halved 1 large clove garlic peeled ¼ cup fish sauce 2 tbsp soy sauce 1 tbsp brown sugar ¼ tsp Chinese five spice ½ tsp cayenne ½ tsp white pepper Plain flour for dusting Vegetable oil for deep frying Method Put onion and garlic into TMX and chop Speed 5 for 5 seconds, open lid, scrape down and chop again.</description></item><item><title>Christmas Leftover Quiche</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/christmas_leftover_quiche/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/christmas_leftover_quiche/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 qty of EDC shortcrust pastry 200g cream Block of Feta Cheese (approx. 200g) 4 large free range eggs 1 onion oil Christmas meat leftover – diced (smoked salmon, turkey, chicken or ham) Grated cheddar Method Make your shortcrust pastry as per EDC.</description></item><item><title>Creamy Beef and Thyme</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamy_beef_and_thyme/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamy_beef_and_thyme/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 large onion (peeled and halved) 2 garlic cloves Fresh Thyme (approx. leaves from 10 sprigs) 1 tsp sweet paprika 50g TMX stock 100g white wine 150g water 100g cream 20g flour (50g for pie) 800-1000g gravy beef diced Salt and pepper to taste Method Add onion and garlic to bowl and chop on Speed 6 for 3 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Creamy Mustard Chicken Spaghetti</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamy_mustard_chicken_spaghetti/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/creamy_mustard_chicken_spaghetti/</guid><description>Ingredients 500g Chicken Thighs diced 1 onion 2 cloves of garlic 10g oil 4 rashers of bacon diced 3 tbsp seeded mustard 800g water 2 tbsp TMX vegetable stock 300g cream 300g pasta 1 cup of peas Salt and pepper to taste Parmesan to garnish Method Add onion and garlic to bowl and chop for 5 seconds on Speed 7.</description></item><item><title>Crunchy Honey Soy Chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crunchy_honey_soy_chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crunchy_honey_soy_chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients - Flour Mix 150g plain flour 1 tsp salt 1 tsp white pepper 1 tsp ground ginger 1 tbsp dried thyme ½ tbsp dried sage 1 tbsp smoked paprika ¼ tsp cayenne pepper &amp;lt;!</description></item><item><title>Katsu Chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/katsu_chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/katsu_chicken/</guid><description>Original image filename: Katsu.jpg Ingredients - Flour Mix 4 - 8 chicken thighs
3 eggs
2 tbsp soy sauce
Plain flour</description></item><item><title>Lamb Kofta</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_kofta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_kofta/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 garlic clove Handful each of fresh parsley, coriander and mint 50g red onion 1 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp ground coriander 1 tin of lentils (rinsed and drained) 25g TMX stock paste 500g lamb mince Method - Marinade Add garlic, onion and herbs to the bowl and blitz on Speed 7 for 3 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Lamb Rogan Josh</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_rogan_josh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_rogan_josh/</guid><description>Ingredients - Marinade 15g ginger 5 cloves garlic 1tsp turmeric 1tsp black peppercorns (or crushed black pepper) 250g plain yoghurt 1kg lamb forequarter chops meat chopped from bones Method - Marinade Add garlic and ginger and pepper corns to TMX bowl and chop 5 seconds speed 7.</description></item><item><title>Lamb Shanks in Tomato Sauce</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_shanks_in_tomato_sauce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_shanks_in_tomato_sauce/</guid><description>Ingredients 6 Lamb Shanks 2 carrots chopped 2 celery stalks chopped 1 large onion 1 large garlic clove 1200g water 5 rosemary sprigs Prosciutto 400g tin tomatoes 1 heaped tbsp.</description></item><item><title>Lemon and Coriander Chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_and_coriander_chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_and_coriander_chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 90g olive oil 60g onion 5g garlic 2 stalks of coriander leaves and roots 5g cumin seeds 100g lemon juice 2 tsp smoked paprika 2 bay leaves Method Add all ingredients to TMX and blitz on Speed 8 for 30 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Lemon and Herb Chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_and_herb_chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_and_herb_chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients •50g lemon juice handful of favourite herbs (parsley, sage, basil, coriander, oregano) 20g TMX stock 20g olive oil pinch salt 1 garlic clove red chilli - optional Method Add all ingredients to bowl and blitz on Speed 8 for 50 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Lemon Chicken and Rosemary Risotto</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_chicken_and_rosemary_risotto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemon_chicken_and_rosemary_risotto/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 onion peeled and halved 1 garlic clove 3 sprigs of rosemary (leaves only) 20g oil 400g Arborio rice 100g white wine 4 chicken thighs trimmed and sliced 1100g water 2 heaped spoonfuls of TMX stock paste 50g lemon juice Grated Parmesan cheese Spinach leaves Method Add onion, rosemary and garlic to bowl and chop for 3 seconds on Speed 7.</description></item><item><title>Malaysian Chicken and Prawn Curry (Laksa Paste)</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/malaysian_chicken_and_prawn_curry_laksa_paste/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/malaysian_chicken_and_prawn_curry_laksa_paste/</guid><description>Ingredients - Laksa Paste 2-4 Red Chillies
50g fresh coriander leaves and roots
40g fresh ginger
3 garlic cloves
2 lemongrass stalks</description></item><item><title>Maple Baked Chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/maple_baked_chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/maple_baked_chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients - Marinade 50g djon mustard 20g mayonnaise 50g maple syrup 40g rice wine vinegar 1/2 tsp cayenne pepper 1 garlic salt and pepper to taste Chicken thighs, drumsticks or wings Method Add everything to the bowl and blitz on Speed 7 for 10 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Multi Purpose Breadcrumbs</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/multi_purpose_breadcrumbs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/multi_purpose_breadcrumbs/</guid><description>Ingredients •3 slices bread
50g salami 30g semi dried tomatoes 1 brown onion 200g cubed cheese 2 cloves garlic ½ bunch parsley Salt &amp;amp; Pepper Method Place all ingredients into TMX bowl and chop 10 seconds using spatula to help.</description></item><item><title>Nigella's Mughlai Chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nigella_s_mughlai_chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/nigella_s_mughlai_chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients - Marinade 60g almonds 1 onion 25g fresh ginger 3 garlic cloves ½ -2 red chillies (Don’t go crazy otherwise the spices will get lost!) Olive oil 2 tsp ground cumin 2 tsp ground coriander 1 tsp garam masala 4 cardamom pods 1 cinnamon stick 4 cloves 2 fresh bay leaves 200g greek yoghurt 60g chicken stock paste or vegetable stock paste 1 tsp sugar 1 tsp salt 6-8 chicken thigh (cut in quarters) 100g cream Method Add almonds to a dry bowl and mill on Speed 8 for 8 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Pad Thai Noodles</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pad_thai_noodles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pad_thai_noodles/</guid><description>Ingredients Peanuts 1-2 Chicken thighs (diced) 200g prawns (optional) 4 spring onions sliced Bok choy sliced Handful of bean sprouts 1 packet of rice noodles 2 tbsp palm sugar (or brown sugar) 2 tbsp fish sauce 1 tsp tamarind paste Chilli to taste Juice of 1 lime Coriander to garnish Method Place peanuts in bowl and crush on Speed 5 for 3-5 seconds (depending on how you like them).</description></item><item><title>Peppered Beef and Mushroom Stew</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/peppered_beef_and_mushroom_stew/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/peppered_beef_and_mushroom_stew/</guid><description>Ingredients 700g Chuck steak or gravy beef cubed 2 carrots peeled and chopped 250g mushrooms sliced 2 cloves garlic 1 onion peeled and quartered 10g olive oil 20g cornflour 1tbsp tomato paste 250g beef stock liquid 3 tbsp soy sauce 3 tbsp Worcestershire sauce 3 tbsp fish sauce 1 tsp mixed herbs 1 tsp ground black pepper Method Put garlic and onion in TMX bowl and chop 5 seconds speed 7 Scrape down sides, add olive oil and sauté 5 minutes 100 degrees speed 1 Add remainder of ingredients and cook 50 minutes reverse speed soft 100 degrees</description></item><item><title>Pork and Chorizo Sauce</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pork_and_chorizo_sauce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pork_and_chorizo_sauce/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 cloves garlic 1 onion 1 celery stick chopped 1 chorizo sausage chopped and skin removed 20g oil 1 tin tomatoes 80g tomato paste 200g water 30g TMX stock paste Salt and pepper to taste Handful fresh herbs 500g pork mince Feta and fresh herbs to serve Method Add garlic, onion, celery and chorizo to bowl and chop on Speed 7 for 5 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Roast Lamb Marinade</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/roast_lamb_marinade/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/roast_lamb_marinade/</guid><description>Ingredients 30g soy sauce 30g worcestershire sauce (homemade is awesome - recipe available at Stephberg.com) 1 large garlic clove 3 rosemary sprigs (leaves only) small handful of mint leaves 30g olive oil (optional) Method Put everything into the bowl and blitz on Speed 7 for 10 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Spicy Mexican Pulled Beef</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spicy_mexican_pulled_beef/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spicy_mexican_pulled_beef/</guid><description>Ingredients 750g Chuck steak diced into 1cm cubes 1 shallot peeled and cut in half 2 cloves garlic 1 cup tinned tomatoes 1tbsp tomato paste 1 tsp TMX vege stock concentrate 1 tsp ground cumin 1 tsp ground coriander 1 tsp paprika ½ tsp cayenne pepper 1 tbs jalapeno’s (pickled jar variety) or 1 red chilli but jalapenos are the best!</description></item><item><title>Sticky Vietnamese Chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sticky_vietnamese_chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/sticky_vietnamese_chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 700g chicken thigh fillet 1 small red onion 2 cloves garlic 20g oil 2 lemon grass stalks (white part only) 120g white sugar 2cm ginger 30g lime juice 30g fish sauce 30g soy sauce 1/4tsp white pepper 10g chinese cooking wine ¼ tsp dried chilli flakes Method Put peeled garlic, onion, lemon grass and ginger into TMX bowl and chop for 3 seconds at Speed 6.</description></item><item><title>Strawberry Jelly</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/strawberry_jelly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/strawberry_jelly/</guid><description>Method Add 250g of fresh strawberries (leaves removed), 50g icing sugar and 100g water to the bowl and blitz on Speed 8 for 30 seconds (or until well combined). Add 50g boiling water to 1 tbsp of gelatine and mix well.</description></item><item><title>Teriyaki Chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/teriyaki_chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/teriyaki_chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 120g soy sauce 90g sugar 90g sake or white wine 100g mirin 90g water 1 tbsp corn flour 2 garlic cloves 20g ginger 500-1000g chicken thighs diced Method Add all ingredients except chicken into bowl and mix on Speed 8 for 30 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Thai Chicken Rissoles</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thai_chicken_rissoles/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thai_chicken_rissoles/</guid><description>Ingredients 15g fresh ginger 1 large clove of garlic 1 tsp of lemongrass (masterfoods) 1 small bunch of coriander (including stem) 25g sweet chilli sauce 1 tsp fish sauce 500g diced chicken breast Method Add ginger and garlic to bowl and blitz on Speed 8 for 3 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Whiskey Chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/whiskey_chicken/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/whiskey_chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 2tbsp olive oil 2 cloves of garlic 15g fresh ginger Pinch of salt ¼ tsp cayenne pepper 1 granny smith – peeled and cored 45g whiskey or bourbon 50g brown sugar 100g tomato sauce 20g apple cider vinegar 200g water 80g soy sauce 2 tbsp corn flour 6 trimmed and diced chicken thighs Method Add all ingredients EXCEPT chicken and corn flour to the bowl and mix on Speed 8 for 40 seconds.</description></item><item><title>Gratin Dauphinois</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/gratin_dauphinois/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/gratin_dauphinois/</guid><description>Ingredients 500ml milk 250ml cream 1 garlic clove, half finely sliced, half left whole Pinch freshly grated nutmeg 140g gruyere, grated Butter, for greasing Sea salt and freshly ground white pepper Chopped flat-leaf parsley, to serve Method Bring the milk and cream to the boil in a large saucepan over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Hawaiian Pulled Pork</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hawaiian_pulled_pork/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hawaiian_pulled_pork/</guid><description>Ingredients 3-4lbs Pork Shoulder 1 can crushed or cubed pineapple (in water) 1 tbl grated ginger (or 1/2 tsp ginger powder) Method Put pork in a crock pot.</description></item><item><title>Hawaiian Pulled Pork Sandwich</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hawaiian_pulled_pork_sandwich/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hawaiian_pulled_pork_sandwich/</guid><description>Ingredients 2.5 lbs pork butt, cut into 2 inch pieces 1 medium onion, finely chopped 1/2 cup ketchup 1/3 cup cider vinegar 1/4 cup packed brown sugar 1/4 cup tomato paste 2 tbsp sweet paprika 1 tbsp red pepper flakes 2 tbsp Worcestershire sauce 1 15oz can Pineapple, discard the sauce 3 tsp salt 2 tsp black pepper 1 avocado, optional Method Cut the pork butt into 2 inch pieces.</description></item><item><title>Cheesy Potato Bake</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheesy_potato_bake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheesy_potato_bake/</guid><description>Ingredients 60g butter 1/4 cup plain flour 2 1/3 cups milk 2 cups grated tasty cheese 1.2kg Sebago potatoes, peeled, thinly sliced Method Preheat oven to 180°C. Grease a 6cm deep, 24cm square baking dish.</description></item><item><title>Spinach and Feta Filo Pie (Jamie Oliver)</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spinach_and_feta_filo_pie_jamie_oliver/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spinach_and_feta_filo_pie_jamie_oliver/</guid><description>Original image filename: Spinach_and_fetta_filo_pie.jpg Original image caption: Taken on 28/09/2013. Ingredients 100g pine nuts 5 eggs 300g feta cheese 50g Cheddar cheese dried oregano 1 lemon a good knob of butter 400g pre-washed spinach 1x 270g pack of filo pastry cayenne pepper 1 whole nutmeg Method Pre-heat your oven to 200°C.</description></item><item><title>Lamb Kofta Meatballs in Curry Sauce</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_kofta_meatballs_in_curry_sauce/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lamb_kofta_meatballs_in_curry_sauce/</guid><description>Ingredients 500g lamb mince 1 medium onion, coarsely grated 2 garlic cloves, crushed 25g (1/3 cup) fresh white breadcrumbs finely grated zest 1 lemon 3 tablespoons chopped coriander 3 tablespoons chopped mint, plus extra handful, to serve 3 tablespoons light flavoured oil 4 tablespoons korma curry paste 1 tablespoon finely chopped ginger 400g tin diced tomatoes 180ml (3/4 cup) coconut milk 1 cinnamon stick 1 red onion, finely sliced naan bread, warmed Method Place the mince, onion, garlic, breadcrumbs, lemon zest, coriander and mint in a large mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>Cheesy Gnocchi Bolognaise</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheesy_gnocchi_bolognaise/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/cheesy_gnocchi_bolognaise/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 tablespoon olive oil 1 brown onion, finely chopped 2 garlic cloves, crushed 750g lean beef mince 600ml bottle Italian tomato pasta sauce 625g packet fresh gnocchi 150g grated cheese Method Preheat oven to 200°C.</description></item><item><title>Lasagne</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lasagne/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lasagne/</guid><description>Original image filename: Lasagne_1.jpg Original image caption: Taken on 15/06/2013. Ingredients 3 eggs 300g plain flour 1 tbsp extra virgin olive oil Method Place all ingredients into TM bowl.</description></item><item><title>Beef with Oyster Sauce</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beef_with_oyster_sauce/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/beef_with_oyster_sauce/</guid><description>Ingredients for Marinade 1/2 teaspoon baking soda 1 teaspoon sugar 1 tablespoon cornflour 1 tablespoon soy sauce 3 tablespoons water 2 tablespoons vegetable oil Ingredients 500g (1lb) lean beef (scotch or fillet) 8 tablespoons oil 500g broccoli, cut into small pieces 2 teaspoons rice wine 1/2 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon sugar 3 spring onions, cut into 2cm lengths 15 slices fresh ginger 2 tablespoons oyster sauce 1 tablespoon water 1 teaspoon sugar 1/2 teaspoon cornflour 1/2 teaspoon sesame oil Method Slice the beef very thinly into 2.</description></item><item><title>Spanish Rice</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spanish_rice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spanish_rice/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 tablespoons oil 2 tablespoons chopped onion 1 teaspoon crushed garlic 1 cup rice 1 3/4 cup chicken stock 1 cup tinned tomatoes ¼ cup peas ¼ cup corn Method Heat oil in a large, non-stick saucepan.</description></item><item><title>Garlic Chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/garlic_chicken/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/garlic_chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 8 chicken wings or 8 pieces of chicken 4 tbsp olive oil 4-6 cloves garlic 1tsp flour a large glass of white wine 50 ml chicken stock salt 1 tbsp chopped fresh parsley a few strands of saffron a few whole peppercorns Method Heat the oil in a frying pan add the chicken wings or pieces and garlic cloves and fry until the garlic turns golden and the chicken brown Remove the whole garlic cloves and set aside Pour the wine into the frying pan and stir whilst adding the flour and a pinch of salt Add the chicken stock and cover and simmer for 15 mins on a low heat In a mortar make a paste using the whole garlic cloves, parsley, saffron and a few peppercorns Add the paste to the frying pan then cover and simmer for another 15 mins</description></item><item><title>Spanish Omelette</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spanish_omelette/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/spanish_omelette/</guid><description>Original image filename: Spanish_omelette.jpg Original image caption: From website. Ingredients 1 medium sebago potato 1 tablespoon olive oil 20g butter 1 medium red onion, thinly sliced 4 eggs 2 tablespoons chopped flat-leaf parsley salad, to serve Method Prick potato all over with a fork.</description></item><item><title>Pasta Neapolitan</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pasta_neapolitan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/pasta_neapolitan/</guid><description>Original image caption: From the pasta man atthe market Filling Ingredients 5 medium tomatos 2 cloves garlic, sliced, not crushed 1 small onion, sliced 1cup basil leaves 1/4cup white wine 1 packet (525g) of fresh pasta 100g ricotta cheese (from deli)*Parmesan cheese Butter salt &amp;amp; pepper Sauce Method Cut tomatos in quarters and put into a bowl of water.</description></item><item><title>Chicken with 40 cloves of garlic</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_with_40_cloves_of_garlic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chicken_with_40_cloves_of_garlic/</guid><description>Original image filename: Chicken_with_40_cloves_of_garlic.jpg Ingredients 1 organic chicken, chopped into pieces 40 cloves of garlic, unpeeled 1/2 cup white wine or Verjuice or apple juice or chicken stock (I usually use a mixture of apple juice and chicken stock) 3 Tablespoons extra virgin olive oil fresh thyme (or 1 teaspoon dried thyme) fresh sage, chopped finely (or 1/2 teaspoon dried sage) fresh parsley, chopped finely 4 small bay leaves 1 teaspoon herb salt &amp;amp; some freshly ground pepper (may need more salt if using apple juice) Method Scatter 40 garlic cloves over the bottom of a casserole dish.</description></item><item><title>Osso Buco</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/osso_buco/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/osso_buco/</guid><description>Original image filename: Osso_buco.jpg Original image caption: From website. Ingredients 8 x 200g osso buco (veal shin) sea salt and cracked black pepper plain (all-purpose) flour, for dusting ¼ cup (60ml) olive oil 1 brown onion, chopped 2 cloves garlic, crushed ⅓ cup (90g) tomato paste 2 cups (500ml) red wine 2 cups (500ml) beef stock hot buttered toast, to serve chopped parsley leaves, to serve Method Heat a large deep frying pan over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Hash Browns</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hash_browns/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/hash_browns/</guid><description>Original image filename: Hash Browns.jpg Original image caption: Picture taken on 26/01/2012. Ingredients 6 medium (about 1.2kg) desiree potatoes, peeled 2 tbs plain flour 1 egg, lightly whisked Pinch of salt Vegetable oil, to shallow-fry Method Preheat oven to 120°C.</description></item><item><title>Chargrilled Pork Neck with Vermicelli Noodles</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chargrilled_pork_neck_with_vermicelli_noodles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chargrilled_pork_neck_with_vermicelli_noodles/</guid><description>Ingredients 500 g pork neck, finely slice across the grain into 3mm pieces 6 white part spring onion, finely sliced &amp;amp; pounded in mortar &amp;amp; pestle to a paste 2 tablespoons sugar 1 tablespoon honey 4 tablespoons fish sauce 1 teaspoon freshly ground pepper 2 garlic cloves, finely diced 2 tablespoons vegetable oil 250 g rice vermicelli noodle (cook as packet instructions) 5 mint leaves, sliced 5 perilla leaves, sliced 5 Vietnamese mint leaves, sliced 1 Lebanese cucumber, halved &amp;amp; sliced 2 handful bean sprouts 4 tablespoons spring onion oil 4 tablespoon fried red Asian shallots 4 tablespoons crushed roasted peanuts ½ cup dipping fish sauce 12 bamboo skewers, soaked in water for 20 minutes or 12 wooden chopsticks sliced down the middle Method In a large mixing bowl, combine sugar, fish sauce, honey &amp;amp; pepper.</description></item><item><title>Chargrilled Pork Sausage Skewers (Nem Nuong)</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chargrilled_pork_sausage_skewers_nem_nuong/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/chargrilled_pork_sausage_skewers_nem_nuong/</guid><description>Ingredients 300 g minced pork 300 g fish paste (from Asian fishmonger) 12 spring onions, sliced 2 garlic cloves, finely diced 1 tsp freshly ground pepper ½ tsp salt 1 tbsp sugar 1 tbsp fish sauce ½ cup vegetable oil 12 wooden chopsticks, soaked in water for 20 minutes 12 sheets rice paper 1 bunch perilla leaf, picked 1 bunch Vietnamese mint, picked 1 bunch mint, picked 1/2 bunch garlic chives, sliced into 5 cm legths 3 star fruit, finely sliced 1 cucumber, halves &amp;amp; finely sliced lengthways Hoisin dipping sauce 125 ml hoisin sauce 1.</description></item><item><title>Lemongrass Chilli Chicken (Ga Xao Xa Ot)</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemongrass_chilli_chicken_ga_xao_xa_ot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/lemongrass_chilli_chicken_ga_xao_xa_ot/</guid><description>Ingredients 500 g chicken thigh fillets, cut into bite size pieces 3 tbsp fish sauce 1.5 tbsp sugar 2 lemon grass stalks, white part only, finely diced 4 garlic cloves, finely diced 2 long red chilli, finely diced 3 tbsp vegetable oil 1/2 onion, cut into wedges 1 cup young coconut juice 3 coriander sprigs for garnish Method In a mixing bowl combine fish sauce, sugar and mix until sugar has dissolved.</description></item><item><title>Salmon Patties</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/salmon_patties/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/salmon_patties/</guid><description>Ingredients 500g potato, mashed 1/4 cup (60ml) hot milk 210g can red salmon 1/4 cup (20g) grated parmesan 1/4 cup (35g) plain flour 1 egg, lightly beaten 3/4 cup (50g) breadcrumb 2 tbl olive oil Method Mash potato with hot milk and butter.</description></item><item><title>Mum's special sauce</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-special-sauce/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/mums-special-sauce/</guid><description>Good for serving with chicken and pork. Cooked version is good for steamed fish.
Ingredients 1 tbsp light soy sauce 1 tbsp dark soy sauce 1 tbsp oyster sauce 1 tsp sugar 1 tsp sesame oil Fried red onions (optional) Chopped spring onions Method (raw version) Mix everything together and serve.</description></item><item><title>Fettuccine Carbonara</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fettuccine_carbonara/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/fettuccine_carbonara/</guid><description>The Italian name, carbonara, comes from the word for coal. This dish is believed to have been created by coal miners, or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the black pepper on the pasta which resembles coal dust.</description></item><item><title>Tau yu bak</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/tau-yu-bak/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/tau-yu-bak/</guid><description>Ingredients 2 kg pork collar butt, cut into large pieces 1 head garlic, separated into cloves with skin on 1 tbsp sugar 1 tbsp cooking caramel 2 tbsp light soy sauce 2 tbsp dark soy sauce Pepper 1 tsp five-spice powder (optional) Hard-boiled eggs Method Add garlic, sugar, cooking caramel, light soy sauce, dark soy sauce, five-spice powder and pepper to a large pot.</description></item><item><title>Crispy Skin Chicken with Spiced Salt</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crispy_skin_chicken_with_spiced_salt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/crispy_skin_chicken_with_spiced_salt/</guid><description>Ingredients Size 13 chicken 2 teaspoons dark soy sauce Oil, for deep frying Spiced salt 1 tablespoon coarse kitchen salt 1/4 teaspoon five spice powder Method Step 1 Remove any fat from inside of chicken.</description></item><item><title>Curry puffs</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/curry-puffs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2005 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/curry-puffs/</guid><description>This recipe makes 72 curry puffs. Can halve or quarter the quantity to make less.
Ingredients 1.4 kg pork mince 1 kg potato, cut into 1cm cube 1 medium onion, finely chopped 2 tbsp coriander powder 2 tbsp curry powder, substitute with coriander powder for non-spicy version 2 tsp tumeric powder Salt and pepper Soy sauce (optional) 12 sheets puff pastry 2 eggs, for glazing Method Partially cook cubed potato in microwave oven for 10min on High with a little bit of water.</description></item><item><title>Lo bak go</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/lo-bak-go/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/lo-bak-go/</guid><description>This is a tested recipe with Ah Tai. This recipe makes a large radish cake. Try half the quantity for a smaller cake.
Ingredients A 4 Chinese sausages, sliced into thin strips Dried shrimps, soaked and finely chopped 200 g pork mince, lightly seasoned with salt, pepper and light soy B 1 kg radish, grated C 4 cup (1 packet/500 g) rice flour 2 tbsp corn starch 6.</description></item><item><title>Chinese New Year cake</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/chinese-new-year-cake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 1994 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/chinese-new-year-cake/</guid><description>Makes 2 cakes of a reasonable size.
Ingredients 3 x 500 g packets of glutinous rice flour 900 g sugar 6 cups warm water Method Fry sugar until dissolved.</description></item><item><title>Laksa</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/laksa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 1993 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/laksa/</guid><description>Ingredients Pre-prepared rempah Chopped dried shrimp Coconut milk Coconut cream Bean sprouts White noodles Prawns, meat and shells separated Stuffed fried bean curd with fish meat Fish cake Fish balls Vegetables (cabbage, beans, tomato, cauliflower, etc.</description></item><item><title>Beef rendang</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/beef-rendang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 1993 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/beef-rendang/</guid><description>Ingredients Beef, cut into chunks 2-3 red onions Chilli Galangal Turmeric Belacan Cumin Coriander powder Coconut milk Salt Dessicated coconut Method Grind red onions, lemongrass, chilli, galangal, turmeric and belacan.</description></item><item><title>Assam chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/assam-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/assam-chicken/</guid><description>The rempah ingredients are from Ah Tai&amp;rsquo;s notes. Can also use this recipe.
Ingredients ~150 g rempah Belacan Chilli Onions Lemongrass Galangal Turmeric 1kg chicken thigh, cut in large pieces Tomatoes, cut in wedges 1 onion, coarsely chopped Tamarind paste, diluted with water Sugar Mint leaves/laksa leaves (optional) Method Use pre-made rempah, or grind rempah ingredients and fry in lots of oil until fragrant.</description></item><item><title>Assam fish</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/assam-fish/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/assam-fish/</guid><description>This dish is a bit soury.
Ingredients Rempah Belacan Chilli Onions Lemongrass Galangal Turmeric Tamarind paste Fish fillet Pineapple pieces Method Grind rempah ingredients and fry in lots of oil until fragrant.</description></item><item><title>Ah Tai's tau yu bak</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/ah-tais-tau-yu-bak/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/ah-tais-tau-yu-bak/</guid><description>Ingredients Pork (fatty cut like pork belly), cut in large chunks with fat and skin Onion, finely chopped Dark soy sauce Cinnamon stick Cloves 1 star anise 2-3 cloves garlic A bit of sugar Pinch of salt Method Fry onion.</description></item><item><title>Ayam kapitan</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/ayam-kapitan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/ayam-kapitan/</guid><description>Ingredients Chicken pieces Pre-prepared rempah Coconut milk Method Marinate chicken pieces with ground rempah. Fry marinated chicken in a pot on low heat until chicken is cooked. Add in some coconut milk then serve.</description></item><item><title>Curry prawns</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/curry-prawns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/curry-prawns/</guid><description>Ingredients Pre-prepared rempah Pineapple cubes Coconut milk Coconut cream Prawns Method Fry rempah in lots of oil. Add pinapple cubes and coconut milk. Simmer. Add prawns and coconut cream.</description></item><item><title>Sambal ikan bilis</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/sambal-ikan-bilis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/sambal-ikan-bilis/</guid><description>Ingredients Rempah Red onions Lemongrass Galangal Turmeric Belacan Chilli powder Tamarind paste Sugar Ikan bilis, washed and rinsed to remove salt Method Fry ikan bilis in oil on low heat until crisp.</description></item><item><title>Tomato chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/tomato-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/tomato-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients Chicken fillets, cut into pieces Onion, finely chopped/ground Chilli, ground Tomato Vinegar Tomato sauce Sugar Method Marinate chicken pieces with salt. Fry the pieces until slightly browned.</description></item><item><title>Vegetable curry</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/vegetable-curry/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 1992 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/vegetable-curry/</guid><description>Ingredients Rempah Onion Chilli Lemongrass Galangal Turmeric Belacan Dried shrimp Coconut milk Coconut cream Vegetables Small tofu Fish balls Bean curd sheet Cabbage Long bean Carrot Eggplant Method Grind rempah ingredients together.</description></item><item><title>Chicken rendang</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/chicken-rendang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/chicken-rendang/</guid><description>Adapted from the recipe here: https://rasamalaysia.com/chicken-rendang/
Ingredients 1.5 kg chicken pieces 150 g rempah 1 onion, diagonally sliced 1 cinnamon stick 6 cloves 4 star anise 5 cardamom pods 2 lemongrass (white part only), smashed 1 cup coconut milk 8 kaffir lime leaves, bruised 7 tbsp toasted grated coconut (kerisik), or desiccated coconut 1 tbsp sugar or to taste Salt to taste Method Heat oil in a frying pan/pot.</description></item><item><title>Coriander chicken</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/coriander-chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/coriander-chicken/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 kg chicken thigh fillets 2 cloves crushed garlic Salt and pepper to taste 1 tbsp soy sauce 2 tbsp coriander powder 1 tsp turmeric powder Method Marinate chicken in rest of the ingredients for at least 2 hours.</description></item><item><title>Nanna's steamed eggs</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/nannas-steamed-eggs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/nannas-steamed-eggs/</guid><description>Ingredients 5 eggs 1 cup mince 2½ cup warm water Chives Seasoning (light soy) Method Mix everything together in a dish. Microwave on high for 10 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Thai Fish Cake</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thai_fish_cake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thai_fish_cake/</guid><description>Ingredients 225g salmon fillet 3 tbls Grand Palace red curry paste 2 tbls fish sauce 1 egg 3 tbls cornstarch 1/4 tsp baking soda 6 kaffir lime leaves, sliced very thin (or use basil leaves) 3 cup oil for deep frying Garnishes: Green leaf lettuce, cucumber, sliced tomatoes Method Remove all bones from fish and slice the meat.</description></item><item><title>Thai Spareribs</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thai_spareribs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/archive/thai_spareribs/</guid><description>Original image filename: Thai_spareribs.jpg Original image caption: From website. Ingredients 6 lbs spareribs, cut into 2 rib portions boiling water 2 large lemongrass, stalks 1/2 cup soy sauce 6 tablespoons soy sauce 1/2 cup brown sugar (packed) 1/2 cup dry sherry or 1/2 cup sake 2 tablespoons peanut sauce (Thai) 2 tablespoons sesame oil 4 large garlic cloves, peeled 1 1/2 inches piece fresh ginger, peeled, chopped 3/4 cup unsweetened coconut milk Method Preheat oven to 350°F Arrange ribs in single layer in large roasting pan.</description></item><item><title>Turmeric rice</title><link>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/turmeric-rice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jarodl.am/cookbook/recipes/turmeric-rice/</guid><description>Ingredients 3 cups rice (rice measuring cup, not metric cup) 3 tablespoons coconut cream powder 1 teaspoon turmeric powder Pinch salt Method Wash rice. Add enough water for the quantity of rice.</description></item></channel></rss>